<text xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 UNTtite%20(1.3).xsd" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="TEI">
<body>
<pb n="407" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="1" />
<div1 type="article">
<head type="main">SPECIAL LAWS <lb/>PASSED BY <lb/>THE EXTRA SESSION <lb/>OF <lb/>THE EIGHTH LEGISLATURE <lb/>CONVENED JAN. 21, 1861</head>
<byline>BY AUTHORITY</byline>
<byline>AUSTIN 1861</byline>
<pb n="408" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="2" />
<pb n="409" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="3" />
<head type="sub">SPECIAL LAWS <lb/>PASSED BY <lb/>THE EIGHTH LEGISLATURE <lb/>EXTRA SESSION</head>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER I.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act supplementary to an &#8220;Act to incorporate the Houston, Trinity and Tyler Railroad Company,&#8221; and to the acts amenda<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tory of, and supplemental thereto.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted, by the Legislature of the State of Texas. That the Houston, Trinity and Tyler Railroad Company, having selected a point on the Galveston, Houston and Henderson Railroad, between Harrisburg and Houston, in Harris county, as the point of connecting the Houston, Trinity and Tyler Railroad with the Galveston, Houston and Henderson Rail<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />road, and the said Company having commenced the survey of the route, and the construction of its railroad from said point of connection, and run its survey twenty-five miles in the direction of Huntsville, in Walker county, the said connection and route are hereby fully approved, ratified and confirmed as warranted by the act incorporating said Company, and the said Company is authorized to construct its railroad from said point of connection, and on said route, as if the same had been expressly designated in the act incorporating said company: pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vided, that nothing in this act, shall be so construed as to prevent said Company from running said road through the city <pb n="410" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="4" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw> of Houston, or commencing in said city, if the said Company deem it proper to do so.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That the establishment by said Company of its principal office in the city of Galveston, is hereby recognized as valid, and the said Company is authorized to keep its principal office in said city.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>February 1, 1861</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER II.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act supplemental to an act and amendatory of an act entitled an act to incorporate the San Antonio and Mexican Gulf Rail<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />road Company, and supplemental to and amendatory of the sev<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />eral acts supplemental to and amendatory of the above recited act.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the time for the completion of the second section of twenty-five miles of the San Antonio and Mexican Gulf Railroad Company, be, and the same is hereby extended to the first day of January, 1863, anything in the original act of incorporation, or in the several acts supplemental to, and amendatory thereof, to the contrary notwithstanding: provided, that the past failure of said company to have completed any section or any given extent of road, within the time prescribed in said original act of incorporation, or in any of the several acts supplemental to, and amendatory thereof, shall not be so construed as to deprive said company of any of the benefits arising under said original act of incorporation, and the several acts supplemental to and amendatory thereof, or arising un<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />der any general or special law of the State, in the same manner as if said company had made no such failure.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>February 1, 1861</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
<pb n="411" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="5" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER III.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to amend an &#8220;Act to incorporate the the Air Line Railroad Company,&#8221; approved 30th January, 1861.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That section eleven of the above recited act shall hereafter read as follows:</p>
<p>&#8220;Sec. 11. That if said railway is not commenced within six months, and at least twenty-five miles thereof completed and in running order, on or before the thirtieth day of December, 1863, then this charter shall be null and void.&#8221;</p>
<p>Sec. 2. This act shall take effect from its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>February 5, 1861</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER IV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to amend an act entitled an act to amend an act entitled an act to incorporate the Columbus, San Antonio and Rio Grande Railroad Company, passed February 8th, 1860.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the second section of the above recited act, be and the same is hereby so amended as to read as follows: That the eight section of the above recited act be so amended as to hereafter read as follows:</p>
<p>&#8220;That said company shall commence work within two years after the passage of this act, and shall complete twenty-five miles of said road every two years thereafter, or at that rate, until the same reaches San Antonio. And should the said company fail to commence and prosecute the road as herein prescribed, they shall forfeit all their rights and privileges to construct said road further under this charter; and should the said company prosecute their road beyond San Antonio to the Rio Grande, they shall commence within one year after reaching San Antonio, and shall complete ten miles annually thereafter, under the conditions and penalties as set forth in the preceding part of this section.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this act take effect and be in force, from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>February 5, 1861</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
<pb n="412" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="6" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER V.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act for the relief of the Houston Tap and Brazoria Railway Company.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Houston Tap and Brazoria Railway Company, shall have further time, until the first of January, 1863, to complete the section of their road from the Brazos river to the Colorado river, and that this act shall take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>February 5, 1861</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER VI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to incorporate the Lavaca Wharf Company.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That W. P. Baughn, Z. K. Fulton, S. J. Lee, Jno. H. Cross, A. T. Hensley, John S. W. Hubbard and A. J. Walker and others who may become purchasers or subscribers for stock in said com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pany, and their successors and assigns, be, and they are hereby con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />stituted a body corporate and politic, by the name of &#8220;The Lavaca Wharf Company,&#8221; and by that name and style they and their suc<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cessors shall in law be capable of suing and being sued in all courts and places whatsoever.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That said corporation is hereby authorized and empowered to hold, possess and acquire, and the same to sell and convey all such real and personal estate as shall be neces<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sary for the convenient transaction of its business, or which may be conveyed to said company for the security of any debt which may become due and owing, or in satisfaction of any judgment or decree rendered in favor of said company: provided, the property so owned by said company, shall not exceed in value at any one time, two hundred thousand dollars, and may have and use a common seal and the same alter and change at pleasure, and may make all such other regulations and by-laws as shall be necessary and proper for the proper regulation, management, prosecution and preservation of the property and business of said <pb n="413" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="7" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw> company, and which is not in conflict with the constitution and laws of the State.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. The business of said company shall be that of Wharfin<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />gers, and the said company is hereby given full power and authority to erect one or more wharves as their business may require, said wharf or wharves to be erected in the city of Lavaca, in the county of Calhoun, and may be extended out in Lavaca bay, sufficiently far to reach the deepest water, in front of said city: provided, that in the erection of said wharf or wharves, they shall not be so erected as to be in front of private property, owned on the bank of said bay, (and east of Commerce Street) unless the consent of the owner or owners of the bank be first obtained by said company.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. The said company shall have the right to demand and receive a compensation or wharfage from all persons who may use said wharf or wharves, either by the deposit of goods thereon, the transportation of property over the same, or the mooring of ves<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sels alongside of the same: provided, the wharfage charged shall at no time exceed six and one quarter cents per barrel of five and one-half cubic feet, and the moorage charged shall at no time exceed two cents per ton, custom-house measurement, for each day a berth is occupied.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. The capital stock of said company shall be one hundred and thirty thousand dollars, to be divided into shares of one hun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dred dollars each.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. It shall not be lawful for said company, under any pre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tence whatever, to discount notes or hills, or to loan money on in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />terest, or to exercise any banking power, but shall have authority through the agency of its Board of Directors, to borrow any amount of money to carry into complete effect the objects of this incorpo<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ration.</p>
<p>Sec. 7. The business of said company shall be conducted by a Board of five Directors, to be chosen by the stockholders from among themselves, which said Directors, shall serve until the first Tuesday in December in the next succeeding year after their elec<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion, or until others are elected to fill their places, an election for which is provided for, on the first Tuesday in December in each year. In the election of said Board, each share of stock shall be entitled to one vote, and the Directors chosen, must each hold at least one share of the capital stock in his own proper right.</p>
<p>Sec. 8. Said Board of Directors, shall when elected, ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />point one of their number President. They shall also appoint a Secretary, a Treasurer, a Wharfinger and such other officers or <pb n="414" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="8" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw> agents as the business of said company shall require. The Secre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tary, Treasurer, Wharfinger and such other officers or agents as the Board may deem advisable; shall give bonds in such sums as said Board shall direct, for the faithful discharge of their respective duties.</p>
<p>Sec. 9. The Wharfinger or Secretary, (as the Board may direct) shall keep proper books of accounts, in which Shall be registered all the transactions of the company, and the same shall at all times be subject to the inspection of the members of the corporation and stockholders.</p>
<p>Sec. 10. The Board of Directors shall prescribe the duties and fix the compensation of each and every agent and officer by them appointed.</p>
<p>Sec. 11. That this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage, and continue in force thirty years, and no longer.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>February 7, 1861</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER VII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act for the relief of the Texas and New Orleans Railroad Com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pany.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Texas and New Orleans Railroad Company shall have until the first day of January, 1863, to locate its land certifi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cates, and return the field-notes of the same to the General Land Office.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That said Railroad Company, shall have the power, and is hereby authorized to issue a first mortgage upon its railroad from the west bank of the Trinity river to the city of Houston: provided, that this company shall relinquish all claims to the State loan on said section of its road.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>February 7, 1861</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
<pb n="415" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="9" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER VIII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act granting an extension of time for the completion of the Washington County Railroad.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That in the event of the failure of the Washington County Bailroad Company to complete said road to the town of Brenham, in compliance with the provisions of its charter or contract for completion, said company shall have six months extension of time, and shall be entitled to all the provisions of its charter, or the Gen<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />eral Railroad law of this State, or any act supplementary or amenda<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tory thereof. And that this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>February 7, 1861</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER IX.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to amend the eighth section of an act entitled &#8220;An Act to incorporate the Eastern Texas Railroad Company,&#8221; passed by the Eighth Legislature of the State of Texas.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the eighth section of said act shall hereafter read as follows:</p>
<p>&#8220;Section 8. That said corporation shall have power to call for such portions of stock subscribed for, not exceeding twenty-five per cent., every six months, as they may think proper, to be paid at such time and place on the line of said railroad as they may designate, by giving sixty days notice thereof, in some newspaper near said road, or by giving to the stockholders written notices, in which notices shall be specified the amount called for and demanded on each share, and the time and place of payment; and if any stockholder shall fail, neglect, or refuse to pay the amount so called for on his, her, or their stock, within sixty days after the time named for such payment in said notice, no such stockholder shall be entitled to vote in virtue of said shares, or draw any dividend on account thereof, so long as the instalments called for remain unpaid; and the directors of Said company, after giving sixty days notice in some newspaper <pb n="416" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="10" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw> published nearest the place where the office of said company is kept, may sell, at public auction, the shares subscribed for by such de<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />linquent, and may transfer such shares to the purchasers of the same, and if the proceeds of such sales shall not be sufficient to pay the amount due, with interest and charges, such delinquent shall be held liable to said company for the deficit, and if the proceeds shall exceed the amount so due, with interest and charges, he shall be entitled to the surplus.&#8221;</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>February 7, 1861</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER X.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to change the name of the county seat of Hidalgo County.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the name of the town of Edinburgh, the county seat of the county of Hidalgo be changed to Hidalgo.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this act take effect, and be in force, from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>February 7, 1861</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act supplemental to an act for the relief of Myrum Mudget, Daniel Kitchings, A. L. Spencer, and E. G. Cantwell, approved February 8, 1860.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the certificates provided for to be isued to &#8220;A. L. Spencer and E. G. Cantwell&#8221; in said act shall be issued to E. G. Spencer and to A. L. Cantwell, and the Commissioner of the <pb n="417" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="11" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw> General Land Office is required to issue to the parties mentioned in this act.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this act be in force from its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>February 8, 1861</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act for the relief of the Trinity Valley Railroad Company.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the time specified in the charter of the Trinity Valley Railroad Company within which said railroad was to be commenced, and the first section of twenty-five miles completed, be extended one year.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this act take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>February 8, 1861</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XIII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act for the relief of the Houston and Texas Central Railway Company.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the failure of the Houston and Texas Central Railway Company to complete the fourth and fifth sections of twenty-five miles each, of its road by the thirtieth day of July, 1861, shall not work a discontinuance, as to the said company, of the benefits of the act entitled an act to encourage the con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />struction of railroads in Texas, by the donation of land, or any other laws in reference to railroads, if said company shall com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />plete said fourth and fifth sections by the thirtieth day of Jan<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />uary, 1863, and shall thereafter complete twenty-five miles of its road, annually, or fifty miles every two years thereafter: provided, said railroad shall run on the nearest and most practicable route from its line at or near Horn Hill to Dresden, in Ha<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" /><pb n="418" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="12" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw> varro county, and thence to the town of Dallas, or within one and a half mile of said town, and thence to the terminus on Eed Eiver, within fifteen miles of Preston. And said company shall have said road surveyed, staked, and permanently located, to Dresden, or within one mile of said town, by the first day of April, A. D. 1862.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this act take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>February 8, 1861</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XIV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act for the relief of the Southern Pacific Railroad Company.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the time within which the Southern Pacific Railroad Company is required, by the existing laws, to locate the line of its road-bed west of the Brazos river, and for the survey of its lands and the return of its field-notes to the general land office, shall be extended two years, in addition to the time now allowed said com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pany.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this act shall be in force from its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Passed, <date>February 8, 1861</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to provide payment of expenses incurred by special bearer of dispatches sent by the Governor to Washington City.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That six hundred dollars be allowed the special bearer of dispatches sent by the Governor to Washington City, in January, 1860,&#8212;which sum shall be in full payment of all mile<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />age, expenses, and services, of said bearer of dispatches, &#8212; to be <pb n="419" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="13" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw> paid out of any money in the treasury not otherwise appropriated.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this act take effect, and be in force, from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>February 8, 1861</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XVI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act for the relief of Angel Navarro.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Comptroller of the State of Texas be, and he is hereby authorized to draw his warrant upon the Treasurer of the State, in favor of Angel Navarro, for the sum of fifty dollars, bal<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ance due him for his services as special agent to the Ro Grande.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That the sum of fifty dollars be, and the same is hereby, appropriated out of any funds in the treasury not otherwise ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />propriated, to pay said warrant. And that this act take effect from its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>February 9, 1861</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XVII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act appropriating the sum of two thousand five hundred dollars for the payment of S. G. Haynie, James G. Swisher, and James Doyle, for services rendered as Commissioners and Superintend<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ent of the building of the Capitol.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the sum of one thousand dollars be appropriated for the payment of five hundred dollars, each, to S. G. Haynie and James G. Swisher, being the balance due them for services as Com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />missioners for the erection of the Capitol Building, from June 4, 1854, to December 4, 1855.</p>
<pb n="420" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="14" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<p>Sec. 2. That the sum of one thousand five hundred dollars be appropriated for the payment of balance due James Doyle, as Su<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />perintendent of the Building of the Capitol, from December 6, 1854, to December 6, 1855.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That so much of section one of an act entitled &#8220;An Act making appropriations to supply the deficiency in former appro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />priations, and for other purposes, approved February 14, 1860,&#8221; as conflicts with this act, appropriating money for the payment of the services mentioned in this act be, and the same are hereby, repealed. And that this act take effect, and be in force, from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>February 13, 1861</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XVIII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act granting a pension to William H. Anderson.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Whereas, at the regular session of the Eighth Legislature, an appropriation of one hundred dollars per annum, made to William H. Anderson, as a pension, and whereas, the same cannot be drawn by him under the appropriation without additional legislation: Therefore&#8212;</p>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature ot the State of Texas, That an annual pension be granted to William H. Ander<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />son, and that his name be placed upon the list of pensioners, and that his pension be paid as follows: One hundred dollars on the fifteenth day of May, 1861, and fifty dollars on the first day of July thereafter; and semi-annually, thereafter, the sum of fifty dollars. And that this act take effect, and be in force, from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>March 29, 1861</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
<pb n="421" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="15" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XIX.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act making an appropriation to pay John Marshall for certain services.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the sum of five thousand nine hundred and eighty-six dollars, and sixty-six cents, or so much thereof as may be necessary, be, and the same is hereby, appropriated, out of any money not otherwise appropriated, for the payment of John Marshall for pub<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lishing five hundred copies Abstract of Titled and Patented Land; also, for publishing one thousand copies of Appendix of the Eighth Legislature.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this act take effect from its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>April 1, 1861</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XX.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to provide for the settlement of the claims of the company commanded by Captain John Williams, who served upon the frontier in the years 1858 and 1859; and to make an appropria<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion to pay the same.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Comptroller is required to audit the claims of Captain John Williams, and his men, for their services in the years 1858 and 1859, in the same manner as other military services of like character: provided, he is satisfied that the said Williams was acting under the lawful authority, and by the consent, of the Gov<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ernor of the State, at the time he was in the service.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That the sum of sixteen thousand nine hundred and seventeen dollars, or so much thereof as may be necessary, is hereby appropriated for the payment of the same, and the Comp<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />troller is required to issue treasury warrants in payment of said service, as provided for the frontier debt. And that this act take effect from its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>April 1, 1861</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
<pb n="422" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="16" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to authorize the County Court of Anderson County to levy and collect a special tax for certain purposes.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the County Court in and for the county of Anderson be, and it is, hereby, authorized and empowered to levy and collect a sum sufficient for the purchase of one hundred and twenty-eight Morse rifles, purchased by said county for military purposes.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this act take effect, and be in force, from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>April 5, 1861</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to authorize and require all forced sales of real estate and negroes, and sales of real estate or negroes, made by executors and administrators, in the county of Nueces, to be made at the front door of the La Retama House in the city of Corpus Christi.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That all forced sales, hereafter to be made, of real estate or negroes, under execution or order of court, and all sales made by executors and administrators of real estate, or negroes, under order of court, in the county of Nueces, shall be made at the front door of the La Retama House, in the city of Corpus Christi.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>April 6, 1861</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXIII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to provide for the redemption of the Treasury Warrants issued to William Fitzhugh.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That it is hereby made the duty of the Comptroller, <pb n="423" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="17" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw> upon the delivery of the ten per cent, treasury warrants, numbered from seven hundred and sixty (760) to seven hundred and ninety<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />four (794) both inclusive, amounting to seven thousand five hun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dred and five dollars ($7,505 00,) issued to William Fitzhugh, for the payment of mules purchased by him for the public service, to compute the interest due thereon, and issue drafts in his favor for such sum and interest, on the assessors and collectors, payable out of the taxes of 1860.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this act take effect from its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>April 6, 1861</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXIV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act for the relief of Charles Ganahl.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Comptroller be authorized to issue to Charles Ganahl a duplicate of treasury warrant No. 17302 and draft No. 892 on the Assessor and Collector of Gillespie county, drawn on the twenty-sixth March, 1861, for the sum of two hundred and eighty dollars, in favor of said Ganahl, for his mileage and per diem as a member of the State Convention: provided, that said Ganahl shall file an affidavit of the loss of said warrant, together with a bond for double the amount of said warrant, with said Comptroller, conditioned that he will indemnify the State in case the first war<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />rant or draft is paid.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this act take effect, and be in force, from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>April 6, 1861</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act granting a pension to Cynthia Ann Parker.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That Cynthia Ann Parker, of Tarrant county, Texas, be, <pb n="424" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="18" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw> and she is hereby entitled to receive from the State of Texas, a pen<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sion of one hundred dollars per annum, for five years; commencing 1st day of January, 1861, to be paid quarterly, as hereinafter speci<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fied, and the sum of one hundred dollars is hereby appropriated, out of any money in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated, to pay said pension the first year, ending 1st January, 1862.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That the County Court of Tarrant county, shall, on ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />plication, appoint a guardian for said Cynthia Ann Parker, who shall give a bond to the Chief Justice of Tarrant county, in the sum of five hundred dollars, conditioned for the faithful appli<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cation of said pension to the support of the said Cynthia Ann Parker, and for the support and education of her child, and upon the production of the certificate of the Clerk of the County of Tar<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />rant to the Treasurer of the State, certifying that said guardian has qualified and his bond approved, the Treasurer shall pay the said pension to the said guardian or his order.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That this act take effect from its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>April 8th, 1861</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXVI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to incorporate the Honston Cotton Press Company.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That William J. Hutchins, Cornelius Ennis, Chas. E. Greg<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ory, Wm. R. Baker and Henry Sampson, together with their asso<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ciates and successors, be, and they are hereby created and consti<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tuted a body politic and corporate, under the name and style of &#8220;The Houston Cotton Press Company,&#8221; and the said corporation are invested with the power to contract and be contracted with to sue and be sued, to plead and be impleaded, to own sufficient amount of real and personal estate for the transaction of its busi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ness, and to appoint such agent or agents and officer or officers, as may be proper for the maintenance of its rights and the transac<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion of its business; to adopt such by-laws for the regulation of its affairs as are in accordance with this act, and the laws of the State.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this charter shall continue in force for the term <pb n="425" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="19" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw> of twenty years, and take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>April 8th, 1861</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXVII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act for the relief of Thomas H. Duggan.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Commissioner of the General Land office, be au<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />thorised and required to issue to Thomas H. Duggan, a certificate for three thousand nine hundred and sixty-five acres of land, being an augmentation of land to which he is entitled by immigration to the country in 1835, for his headlight, (the said Duggan having heretofore received a certificate for only six hundred and forty acres.) This certificate to be taken as a full satisfaction of the order of survey for one league, granted to said Duggan, and one labor by the Commissioner, Nixon, in September, 1835.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this act take effect, and be in force, from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>April 8th, 1861</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXVIII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act for the relief of John A. Cummings.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Commissioner of the General Land Office be, and he is hereby authorized and required to issue to John A. Cum<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mings, a certificate for three hundred and twenty acres of land, which may be located and patented as other genuine land cer<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tificates.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this act take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>April 8, 1861</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<pb n="426" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="20" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXIX.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act donating land to Cynthia Ann Parker.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Commissioner of the General Land Office be, and he is hereby authorized and required to issue to Cynthia Ann Par<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ker, a certificate for one league of land, to be located, surveyed and patented as other land certificates, upon any of the vacant and un<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />appropriated public land of the State of Texas.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That the title to the land granted by the first section of this act, shall vest in Isaac Duke Parker and Benjamin Parker, in trust for the said Cynthia Ann, and in the execution of said trust, they shall be governed by the laws now in force, or which may bereafter be enacted in relation to guardians of property and per<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sons of minors: provided, that said title shall not vest in said trus<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tees or said Cynthia Ann, until said trustees give bond and security as required by said law in relation to guardians of the property and persons of minors.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>April 8, 1861</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXX.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act providing for a change of venue in the cause of the State of Texas, vs. Albert G. Walker, now pending in the District Court of Tarrant county.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the venue for the trial of the cause of the State of Texas vs. Albert G. Walker, charged with the killing of J. Jeff Courtney, and now pending in the District Court of Tarrant coun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ty be, and the same is hereby changed and transferred from said District Court, to the District Court of Johnson county; and it is hereby made the duty of the clerk of said District Court of Tarrant eoiinty, to transmit the proceedings in said cause forthwith to the District Court of said Johnson county as in cases of change of venue as now provided by law.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this act he in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>April 8, 1861</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<pb n="427" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="21" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXXI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to authorize and require public sales in the county of Hays to be made upon the public square in the town of San Marcos.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That all public sales required by law to be made at the court-house door, in the county of Hays, shall be made on the pub<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lic square in the town of San Marcos.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this act take effect and he in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>April 8, 1861</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXXII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to incorporate, the Texas Baptist College.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That F. J. Kelly, R. A. Felton, J. T. Hand, T. W. Jones, George Yarborough, J. M. Carter, W. H. Smith, D. B. Morrill, J. R. Malone, J. W. Dupree, W. C. Kelly, J. H. Roland, M. V. Smith, M. J. Lawrence, A. E. Clemons, E. J. Beall, Wm. Free<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />man, J. R. Clark, J. F. Johnson, F. W. Beasley, R. S. Camp, M. F. Locke, S. P. Rainey, A. R. Green, W. B. Featherston and J. M. Battle, Trustees of Texas Baptist College located in the town of Tyler, Smith county, in the State of Texas, be, and are hereby created a body corporate, under the name and style of the Board of Trustees of the Texas Baptist College, and by that name shall have succession, and be capable in law to sue and be sued, plead and be impleaded, to enact by-laws, rules and regulations; to have, hold and enjoy all property of whatsoever kind, that may be granted by donation, bequest or otherwise, for the benefit of said institution; to convert said property into money and dispose of the same, and it shall have a common seal for the transaction of its business.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That the Texas Baptist College, shall be under the control and superintendence of the Eastern Texas Baptist Con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vention, and the Board of Trustees shall have power to fill all vacancies that shall occur therein subject to the ratification of <pb n="428" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="22" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw> the succeeding Convention, and a less number than thirteen shall not be a quorum to do business, nor shall the number of Trustees consist at any time of more than thirty, a majority of whom must be present in person, or by proxy, to fill a vacancy.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That the Board of Trustees shall annually present to the Convention a written report of the financial condition of said col<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lege, the by-laws and regulations adopted by the Trustees, the number of professors and teachers, and the number of pupils in attendance during the year.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. That the Board of Trustees shall have the power upon the recommendation of the Faculty to confer degrees in the arts and sciences upon the graduates of said College, and upon such other persons as they may deem worthy, and to give diplomas of the same, by the President and Faculty of the College, and by the President of the Board of Trustees.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. That the funds belonging, or in anywise appertaining to said College, shall not be diverted from the object for which the same were given, and all donations and bequests to said Col<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lege shall be good and binding, although the corporate name thereof may not have been properly stated by the person making such be<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />quest or donation.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. The Board of Trustees may elect from their own number, under such rules and regulations as they may adopt, and for such terms and times as they may see proper, a President, Secretary and Treasurer, and any other officer or agent necessary in the Board. They shall also have the power to construct, enlarge alter or remove all necessary buildings for the purpose of said College, etc., and to do all things necessary to the proper conduct and management of said College, not contrary to law or inconsistent with this char<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ter.</p>
<p>Sec. 7. That this act shall take effect and be in force from and after its passage, and continue in force twenty-five years.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>April 8, 1861</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXXIII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to incorporate the Star State Telegraph Company.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the state of Texas, That Henry W. Jones, W. W. Morris, A. M. Gentry, <pb n="429" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="23" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw> Wm, J. Hutchins and E. A. Blanch, their associates and successors be, and they are hereby incorporated and created a body corporate, under the name and style of &#8220;The Star State Telegraph Company,&#8221; with capacity in said corporate name, to make contracts, to have succession and a common seal, to make by-laws for the government and regulation of the Company, to sue and be sued, to plead and be impleaded, to grant and receive, and generally to do and per<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />form all such acts and things as may be necessary for, or incident to, the fulfilment of its obligations, for the maintenance of its rights under this act, and in accordance with the constitution and laws of this State.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That the capital stock of said corporation shall not ex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ceed five hundred thousand dollars; that said corporation shall be and is hereby invested with the right of locating, constructing, owning and maintaining lines of telegraph from the Sabine river, at Orange, via, Beaumont, Liberty, Houston, Hempstead, Brenham, Lagrange, Bastrop, or from Brenham, via, the Air Line Railroad to the city of Austin. From Houston, via, Richmond, Columbus, and Gonzales to San Antonio. From Hempstead, via, the line of the Texas Central Railway, to Red river, with the right to deviate from said line of railway in advance of its construction, so as to run through the various towns lying contiguous to the designated line of said railway. From Sabine Pass, via, Beaumont and the designated line of the Eastern Texas Railroad to Nacogdoches; thence, via, Rusk, Henderson, Tyler, Starrville to Clarksville. From a point on the boundary line of Louisiana, where the Southern Pacific Railroad begins its line, thence west along said line; also, on all lines of railroad in the State, or otherwise, as the business of the country may require, and local capital can be obtained. That this company shall have the right to extend its lines west to the Rio Grande river, with a view to obtain a connection to the Pacific.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That said Company shall be rally organized whenever twenty-five thousand dollars of its capital stock shall have been subscribed, and twenty five per cent, thereof paid in cash, and the parties named as corporators in this act, shall act as Directors until the first annual meeting of the stockholders, when a new Board of Directors shall be elected under the provisions of the by-laws.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. That the company shall have the power to appoint and remove all such officers and agents as may be necessary for the transaction of its business, and to establish a tariff of charges on messages transmitted over its lines, and to alter the same as it may deem proper.</p>
<pb n="430" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="24" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<p>Sec. 5. At all meetings of the stockholders, each share of one hundred dollars shall be entitled to one vote, which may be given by the holder in person, or by written proxy.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. The books of the company shall always be open to the inspection of any stockholder, and no share of stock shall be trans<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ferred, except upon said company&#8217;s books, when a new certificate shall issue to the assignee.</p>
<p>Sec. 7. Said company may determine to what extent the non payment of shares upon stock shall operate as a forfeiture of the same. Should any subscriber fail to pay the first installment called for after the organization of said company, his subscription shall be void, and the share or shares may be re-issued.</p>
<p>Sec. 8. Said company shall be required to transmit all messages and dispatches over their lines, in the order in which the same are delivered to them for transmission.</p>
<p>Sec. 9. All operators, agents and clerks in the employ of the said company, shall be duly sworn before some justice of the peace or notary public, in the county where they are so employed, to keep secret and inviolate any and all messages and dispatches handed to them for transmission, and any violation of said oath shall be deemed a felony, and punishable by a fine or imprison<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment, or both.</p>
<p>Sec. 10. That this company shall have completed and put in full operation, one hundred miles of its lines within eighteen months after the passage of this act, or this act of incorporation shall expire.</p>
<p>Sec. 11. That this act shall expire in twenty-five years, and shall take effect and he in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>April 8, 1861</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXXIV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act concerning the corporation of the town of Crockett.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the limits and boundaries of the corporation of the town of Crockett, shall hereafter be as follows, to-wit:</p>
<p>Beginning at a point 1250 varas due East from the centre of <pb n="431" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="25" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw> the public square in said town; thence North 950 varas, first corner; thence West 1900 varas, second corner; thence South 1900 varas, third corner; thence East 1900 varas, fourth corner; thence North 950 varas, to the beginning.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That it shall hereafter be in the power of the qualified electors of said town, either to contract or extend the boundaries thereof, by a vote of two-thirds of said electors, cast at any general election for corporate officers, or at any special election which the Chief Justice of Houston county may order for that purpose, on petition, in both cases, of any number of said electors: provided, that ten days notice shall be given of any such general or special election, and of its objects; and further, provided, that said bound<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />aries be not so extended as to include more than 1280 acres, and that the same be surveyed and recorded in the office of the clerk of the county court of said county.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>April 8, 1861</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXXV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to amend an act entitled an act to incorporate the Columbus Tap Railway Company, approved Feb. 2, 1860.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the subscription to the capital stock of the Columbus Tap Railway Company, heretofore made by the Buffalo Bayou, Brazos and Colorado Railway Company of the sum of ten thousand dollars, is hereby legalized and declared valid to all intents and purposes, and that the organization of said company, the election of Directors and proceedings had by them are ratified in all re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />spects, as fully as if the subscription made by said Buffalo Bayou, Brazos and Colorado Railway Company had been made in exact conformity with law.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. The company is authorized to establish a ferry across the Colorado river, at or near the present designated line of the road of the company, as may be thought best by the Board of Directors for the location of the same. The said ferry to be under the control and management of the Board of Directors of the company, and used for all purposes in connection with the road and company and its business that may be proper; the said ferry and the use thereof, not to be subject to the control <pb n="432" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="26" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw> or action of the county court or town council of the town of Colum<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />bus, in any respect whatever. And whenever the bridge of the com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pany shall be completed, then this ferry privilege shall cease and ferry be discontinued.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. This act shall take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>April 8, 1861</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXXVI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to prohibit the sale of intoxicating liquors in the neighbor<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />hood of Baylor University.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That it shall not be lawful to sell any intoxicating liquors, whether the same be alcoholic, malt, distilled, or brewed, within the distance of three miles from the Baylor University, situated in Independence, Washington county, (unless sold by apothecaries for medicinal purposes) and any person offending against the provisions of this act, shall forfeit and pay the sum of not more than one hundred dollars, nor less than fifty dollars for each offence, to be recovered by suit, before any Justice of the peace of the precinct in which the Baylor University is situated; which suit may be in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />stituted in the name of the State, at the relation of the President of said University, and the amount so recovered shall be paid, one<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />half to the county of Washington, and the other half to said Uni<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />versity, and the relator shall be responsible for costs of said suit, when the defendant is not convicted. Prosecutions under this act shall be commenced within six months after the commission of the offence.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>April 8, 1861</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXXVII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to legalize the Certificate of Jacob Laux.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of <pb n="433" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="27" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw> Texas, That the certificate issued to Jacob Laux, by W. F. Evans, Commissioner of Fisher &#38; Miller&#8217;s Colony on the 30th day of April, 1849, for six hundred and forty acres of land in said Colony, shall be held valid, and surveyed and patented like other colony certifi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cates, although it was omitted in the Commissioners report to the General Land Office.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>April 8, 1861</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXXVIII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to incorporate the Galveston and Houston Junction Rail<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />road Company.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That E. B. Nichols, G. Ball, J. H. Hutchings, Jno. Sealy, J. Kauffman, Willis Handle, Wm. Hendley, J. J. Hendley, J. L. Slught, L. M. Hitchcock, Joseph Brarms, N. B. Yard, J. L. Briggs, Robert Mills, D. G. Mills, J. W. Jockush, T. H. McMahan, B. R. Gilbert, J. Osterman, Thos. B. Power, S. B. Lewis, A. Lewis, J. M. Brown, James Sorley, J. C. Smith, J. Dean, J. Dyer, S. Southwick, A. P. Lufkin, B. F. Terry, J. P. Davie, W. R. Smith, W. Cooke, E. S. Wood, J. S. Sydnor, T. W. Pierce, J. S. Leclerc, W. J. Hutchins, their associates and successors, be, and they are hereby constituted and declared to be a body politic and corporate, under the name and style of the Galveston and Houston Junction Railroad Company: provided, that the parties named in this act shall only be authorized to act as Commissioners, to organize said company, by receiving subscriptions to its capital stock.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. [That] said company under the name and style afore<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />said, shall be capable in law of suing and being sued, pleading and being impleaded, defending and being defended in all courts what<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />soever in this State, and may have a common seal, and alter the same at pleasure.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That said company is hereby invested with the right to locate, construct, own, maintain and operate a railroad, com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mencing at or near Houston on the line ot the Galveston, Hous<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ton and Henderson Railroad and running through or around the <pb n="434" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="28" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw> city of Houston, and connecting with the Texas Central Railroad, and not to exceed ten miles in length, to he used for the trans<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sportation of passengers, mails and freight, by locomotives pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pelled by steam, and cars attached as used on other railroads, and charge and receive compensation therefor, and to be regulated by, and subject to all the general laws now in force, or hereafter to be passed for the regulation of railroads.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. That the capital stock of said company, shall not exceed one hundred and fifty thousand dollars, divided into shares of one hundred dollars each, and said persons out of their number shall elect a President and Secretary and Board of Directors, which elec<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion shall take place in Galveston, on or before the 10th day of August, 1861, who shall hold their offices until others are appointed under the by-laws of said company, and said company are author<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ized and empowered to make all by-laws and regulations for the government of said company, not in contravention of the constitu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion and laws of the State, and shall establish and keep their office in the city of Galveston.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. That said company shall complete said road and make said connection between the Galveston, Houston and Henderson, and Texas Central Roads, on or before the first of January, 1863: provided, that in case a connection by railroad shall be made through the city of Houston between the Texas Central and the Galveston, Houston and Henderson Railroad of the same gauge as those roads, by the 1st day of July, 1861, then all right under this charter shall cease and determine.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. That this act take effect from its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>April 8, 1861</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXXIX.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to enable J. H. Saunders, the guardian of Webster J. Saun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ders, to remove the property of his ward, from the State of Texas.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That J. H. Saunders may remove the property of his ward, Webster J. Saunders, from the county of Harrison in this State, to the State of Arkansas, one of the United States of America, whenever said J. H. Saunders, shall have produced to the Chief Justice of Harrison county, at some regular term of the county court, a full and complete transcript of the records <pb n="435" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="29" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw> of a court of a competent jurisdiction in the State of Arkansas, properly authenticated, showing that he has been appointed guar<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dian of the estate of said Webster J. Saunders, and given bond and security as may be required by the laws of the State of Arkansas, and is authorized by such court to receive said property.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this act shall be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>April 8, 1861</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XL.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act for the relief of William Eubanks, Assignee of Simeon Clemens.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Commissioner of the General Land Office be, and he is hereby authorized and required to issue patent to Wm. Eubanks, Assignee of Simeon Clemens, on one certain survey in Lamar county, for two hundred and sixty-eight acres of land, sur<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />veyed by virtue of part of certificate No. 169, issued by the Board of Land Commissioners of Lamar county, for 320 acres, on the 30th day of December, 1841, class 4, and which is now on file in the General Land Office: provided, that this act does not interfere with the rights of third parties.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this act take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>April 8, 1861</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XLI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act concerning the Alamo Ditch, in the city of San Antonio, and to regulate irrigation therefrom.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That from and after the first day of January, A. D., <pb n="436" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="30" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw> 1862, the city of San Antonio shall have and exercise no control or authority over the Alamo ditch, and its branches, in the said city, and the former limits thereof, and the right of irrigation from said ditch, and branches, except so far as may be necessary to pre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vent nuisance, and to preserve the health of said city.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That all persons, originally entitled to irrigation from said ditch, shall meet at the office of the Clerk of the County Court of Bexar County, on the 2nd Monday in the month of January, in each year hereafter, at ten o&#8217;clock in the forenoon, and elect, from their number, six Directors, and also a ditch Commissioner, who need not be of their number, whose term of office shall be one year and until the next election, unless said office be made vacant.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. The said Directors may meet at such time and place as they may deem necessary, four of whom shall constitute a quorum for business. They may elect a permanent chairman, and in his absence at any meeting, a temporary chairman. They shall keep a record of their transactions, and shall have power to ordain and establish all needful rules and regulations respecting the preserva<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion, repairing and cleaning of said ditch and its branches, for the maintenance and repair of the dam, and all necessary water-gates, and for the distribution of water from said ditch and its branches, not inconsistent with ancient usage and the laws of this State, hav<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing a due regard to the rights of each person entitled to irrigation therefrom.</p>
<p>They may assess the amount of money to he paid by those entitled to irrigation, for the purpose aforesaid, and for the salary of the ditch Commissioner, and may enforce the collection of the same, either by suit in the name of the chairman before any court of com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />petent jurisdiction, or by withholding the distribution of water from any person failing to pay the amount assessed against him, until payment thereof. They may also pass all necessary by-laws for their own government, and may appoint such officers as may be requisite to carry out the provisions of this act.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. It shall be the duty of the Ditch Commissioner to superintend and direct all work to he done upon said dam, ditch and its branches, and for this purpose, to employ and pay all necessary laborers to attend to and superintend the distribution of water from the said ditch and its branches, and to perform such other duties as may be imposed upon him by said directors, which they are hereby authorized to define. He shall be subject to the orders of said directors, and shall receive such compensa<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" /><pb n="437" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="31" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw> tion as shall be determined by them. He may be removed by said directors, if two-thirds of their body vote therefor, in which case a majority of such directors may appoint a successor to fill the va<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cancy.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. If any person shall take water from the said ditch or its branches, for irrigation, when not entitled to the same, or when withheld from him, as provided in section third of this act, he shall be subject to a fine of not less than ten nor more than twenty-five dollars, to be prosecuted and recovered before any Justice of the Peace of said county, in said city, in the name of the State, and any person who shall not pay any fine assessed upon him for violation of this section, shall be imprisoned, as provided in the case of non<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />payment of fines imposed for the violation of the criminal law of this State; such prosecution and conviction shall not prevent a civil action by every person who may have sustained damages by such unlawful taking of water. This section shall not be construed to prohibit the use of waste water at the termination of said ditch or branches.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. All fines that may be recovered under the provisions of this act, shall be paid to the Chairman of said Directors, to be ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />plied to the salary of said Commissioner, or the payment of any expenses created under this act.</p>
<p>Sec. 7. All persons entitled to distribution of water from said ditch or its branches, shall be entitled to one vote for each hour of water to which they may be entitled. Those owning less than one hour may unite together and for each hour owned by them jointly, cast one vote, through the person deputised by them so to do.</p>
<p>Sec. 9. This act shall take effect and he in force from and after the first day of December next.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>April 8, 1861</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
<pb n="438" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="32" />
<pb n="439" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="33" />
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">INDEX TO SPECIAL LAWS.</head>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">A</head>
<p>Air Line Railroad Company&#8212;To amend act incorporating... <ref>5</ref></p>
<p>Anderson, W. H&#8212;Granting a pension to................. <ref>14</ref></p>
<p>Appropriations&#8212;To pay special bearer of dispatches sent by the Governor to Washington City.......... <ref>12</ref></p>
<p>To pay Angel Navarro for services as special agent to the Rio Grande....................... <ref>13</ref></p>
<p>To pay S. G. Haynie, James G. Swisher and James Doyle for services as Commissioners and Superin<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tendent of the building of the Capitol.................... <ref>13</ref></p>
<p>To pay John Marshall for certain services........ <ref>15</ref></p>
<p>To pay company commanded by Capt. John Wil<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />liams, who served on the frontier in the years 1858 and 1859.......... <ref>15</ref></p>
<p>Anderson County&#8212;Authorizing to levy a special tax.......... <ref>16</ref></p>
<p>Alamo Ditch in San Antonio&#8212;To regulate irrigation there<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />from. ............................ <ref>29</ref></p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">B</head>
<p>Baylor University&#8212;To prohibit sale of intoxicating liquors in neighborhood of...................... <ref>26</ref></p>
</div3>
<pb n="440" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="34" /><fw type="header" place="top">Index.</fw>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">C</head>
<p>Columbus, San Antonio and Rio Grande R. R. Company&#8212;To amend act incorporating.............. <ref>5</ref></p>
<p>Cantwell, E. G.&#8212;For the relief of........................ <ref>10</ref></p>
<p>Commissioners of the building of the Capitol&#8212;Appropriating money to pay for services as.................. <ref>13</ref></p>
<p>Cummings, John A.&#8212;For the relief of...................... <ref>19</ref></p>
<p>Crockett&#8212;Concerning the corporation of the town of........ <ref>24</ref></p>
<p>Columbus Tap Railway Company&#8212;To amend act incorporating................................................ <ref>2</ref></p>
<p>Clemens, Simeon, William Eubanks assignee of&#8212;For relief of <ref>29</ref></p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">D</head>
<p>Dispatches sent by Governor to Washington City&#8212;To pay ex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />penses of bearer of........................... <ref>12</ref></p>
<p>Duggan, Thomas H.&#8212;For relief of............................. <ref>19</ref></p>
<p>Doyle; James&#8212;Appropriating money to pay for services as Superintendent of the Capitol......................... <ref>13</ref></p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">E</head>
<p>Eastern Texas Rail Road Company&#8212;To amend act incorpo<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />rating........................ <ref>9</ref></p>
<p>Eubanks, William, assignee of Simeon Clemens&#8212;For the re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lief of................................ <ref>29</ref></p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">F</head>
<p>Fitzhugh, William&#8212;Providing for the redemption of Treasury warrants issued to................................ <ref>16</ref></p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">G</head>
<p>Ganahl, Charles&#8212;For the relief of..................... <ref>17</ref></p>
<p>Galveston and Houston Junction R. R. Company&#8212;To incor<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />porate.................................... <ref>27</ref></p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">H</head>
<p>Houston, Trinity and Tyler R. R. Company&#8212;Supplementary to act incorporating............................ <ref>3</ref></p>
<p>Houston Tap and Brazoria Bailway Company&#8212;For the relief of.................................... <ref>6</ref></p>
<p>Hidalgo County&#8212;To change name of county seat.............. <ref>10</ref></p>
<p>Houston and Texas Central Railway Company&#8212;For the re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lief of............................. <ref>11</ref></p>
<pb n="441" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="35" /><fw type="header" place="top">Index.</fw>
<p>Haynie, S. G.&#8212;To pay for services as Commissioner, &#38;............ <ref>13</ref></p>
<p>Houston Cotton Press Company&#8212;To incorporate.......... <ref>18</ref></p>
<p>Hays County&#8212;Authorizing and requiring forced sales to be made, where............................. <ref>21</ref></p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">I</head>
<p>Incorporations&#8212;Houston, Trinity and Tyler R. R. company, supplementary............................ <ref>3</ref></p>
<p>San Antonio and Mexican Gulf R. R. Company, sup<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />plemental.................... <ref>4</ref></p>
<p>Air Line R. R. Company, to amend................ <ref>5</ref></p>
<p>Columbus, San Antonio and Rio Grande R. R. Com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pany, to amend........................... <ref>5</ref></p>
<p>Lavaca Wharf Company............................... <ref>6</ref></p>
<p>Eastern Texas R. R. company, to amend............. <ref>9</ref></p>
<p>Houston Cotton Press company............. <ref>18</ref></p>
<p>Texas Baptist College...................... <ref>21</ref></p>
<p>Star State Telegraph Company............... <ref>22</ref></p>
<p>The town of Crockett, concerning................. <ref>24</ref></p>
<p>Columbus Tap Railway company......................... <ref>25</ref></p>
<p>Galveston and Houston Junction R. R. company... <ref>27</ref></p>
<p>Intoxicating Liquors&#8212;Prohibiting sale of in neighborhood of Baylor University........................ <ref>26</ref></p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">K</head>
<p>Kitchings, Daniel&#8212;For relief of.................... <ref>10</ref></p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">L</head>
<p>Lavaca Wharf Company&#8212;To incorporate........................ <ref>6</ref></p>
<p>La Retama House&#8212;Requiring forced sale to be made at............. <ref>16</ref></p>
<p>Laux, Jacob&#8212;To legalize certificate of................................ <ref>26</ref></p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">M</head>
<p>Mudset, Myrum&#8212;For relief of..................................... <ref>10</ref></p>
<p>Marshall, John&#8212;To pay for certain services................... <ref>15</ref></p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">N</head>
<p>Navarro, Angel&#8212;For relief of............................. <ref>13</ref></p>
<p>Nueces County&#8212;Requiring forced sales in, to be made where. <ref>16</ref></p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">P</head>
<p>Pensions&#8212;To W. H. Anderson......................... <ref>14</ref></p>
<p>To Cynthia Ann Parker............................... <ref>17</ref></p>
<p>Parker, Cynthia Ann&#8212;Granting pension to................... <ref>17</ref></p>
<p>Donating land to............................ <ref>20</ref></p>
</div3>
<pb n="442" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="36" /><fw type="header" place="top">Index.</fw>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">R</head>
<p>Rail Road Companies&#8212;Houston, Trinity and Tyler R. R. company................................. <ref>3</ref></p>
<p>San Antonio and Mexican Gulf R ER company...... <ref>4</ref></p>
<p>Air Line R. R. company............................................. <ref>5</ref></p>
<p>Columbus, San Antonio and Rio Grande R. R. com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pany.......... <ref>5</ref></p>
<p>Houston Tap and Brazoria R. R. company........... <ref>6</ref></p>
<p>Texas and New Orleans R. R. company............. <ref>8</ref></p>
<p>Washington county R. R. company.............. <ref>9</ref></p>
<p>Eastern Texas R. R. company........................ <ref>9</ref></p>
<p>Trinity Valley R. R. company........... <ref>11</ref></p>
<p>Houston and Texas Central R. R. company................ <ref>11</ref></p>
<p>Southern Pacific R. R. company.............. <ref>12</ref></p>
<p>Columbus Tap Railway company............ <ref>25</ref></p>
<p>Galveston and Houston Junction R. R. Company... <ref>27</ref></p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">S</head>
<p>San Antonio and Mexican Gulf R. R. company&#8212;Supple<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mental to act incorporating.................. <ref>4</ref></p>
<p>Spencer, A. L.&#8212;For relief of.............................. <ref>10</ref></p>
<p>Southern Pacific R. R. Company&#8212;For relief of............... <ref>12</ref></p>
<p>Special bearer of dispatches to Washington City&#8212;To pay ex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />penses........................................... <ref>12</ref></p>
<p>Swisher, James G.&#8212;To pay for services as Commissioner, &#38;c. <ref>13</ref></p>
<p>Superintendent of the Capitol&#8212;To pay expenses of........ <ref>13</ref></p>
<p>State of Texas vs. Albert G. Walker&#8212;Change of venue........... <ref>20</ref></p>
<p>Star State Telegraph Company&#8212;To incorporate............ <ref>22</ref></p>
<p>Saunders, J. H.&#8212;Enabling him to remove property of ward from Texas............................. <ref>28</ref></p>
<p>Saunders, Webster J.&#8212;To enable his guardian to remove his property from Texas........................ <ref>28</ref></p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">T</head>
<p>Texas and New Orleans R. R. Company&#8212;For relief of........... <ref>8</ref></p>
<p>Trinity Valley R. R. Company&#8212;For the relief of.................. <ref>11</ref></p>
<p>Texas Baptist College&#8212;To incorporate............................ <ref>21</ref></p>
</div3>
<pb n="443" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="37" /><fw type="header" place="top">Index.</fw>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">W</head>
<p>Washington County Railroad&#8212;To extend time for comple<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion ................................ <ref>9</ref></p>
<p>Williams. Capt. John&#8212;For relief of company commanded by, in 1858 and 1859.................................. <ref>15</ref></p>
<p>Walker, Albert G.&#8212;Change of venue.......................... <ref>20</ref></p>
</div3>
</div2>
<pb n="444" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="38" />
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">THE STATE OF TEXAS.</head>
<p>I, Bird Holland, Secretary of State of the State of Texas, do certify that the Extra Session of the Eighth Legislature of said State, convened according to the proclamation of the Governor, at Austin, on Monday the twenty-first day of January, in the year one thousand eight hundred and sixty-one, and adjourned on Tues<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />day, the 9th day of April, the same year.</p>
<p>And I further certify that the acts contained in this volume, are true copies, taken from the original rolls deposited in the Depart<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment of State, with which they have been carefully compared.</p>
<p>Given under my hand and official seal, at the city <floatingText rend="left"><body><p>[L. S.]</p></body></floatingText>of Austin, the sixth day of May, A. D., one thousand eiffht hundred and sixty-one.</p>
<closer>
<signed>BIRD HOLLAND, Secretary of State.</signed>
</closer>
</div2>
</div1>
</body>
</text>