<text xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 UNTtite%20(1.3).xsd" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="TEI">
<body>
<pb n="781" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="23" />
<div1 type="article">
<head type="main">SPECIAL LAWS <lb/>CALLED SESSION <lb/>TENTH LEGISLATURE.</head>
<pb n="782" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="24" />
<pb n="783" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="25" />
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">SPECIAL LAWS.</head>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER I.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to amend the first and second Sections of An Act entitled &#8220;An Act to in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />corporate the Rusk County Iron Company.&#8221; Approved Dec. 15th, 1863.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the first section of the above recited act shall hereafter read as follows: to wit: &#8220;Sec. 1. That Wm. Davenport, W. W. Morris, Taylor Brown, William L. McMurray, R. W. McLane, A. S. Hayter, John Barham, John S. Buckner, W. W. Bell and W. Durham citizens of the State of Texas, their associates and successors be, and are hereby created a body corporate and politic, under the name and style of &#8216;The Rusk County Iron Company,&#8217; with capacity to own property, real, personal and mixed, in such quantities as may be necessary for the legitimate purposes of this corporation, to make contracts, have a common seal, establish by-laws for its government, and in their corporate name to sue and be sued, grant and receive, and generally to do and perform such things and acts as may be essential and incident to the fulfill<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ments of their objects, or the maintenance of their rights under this act, and not inconsistent with the Constitution of this State.&#8221; That the second section of said act shall, hereafter, read as follows: &#8220;Sec. 2. That said company is hereby created with the right to erect, own, maintain, and carry on a manufactory of iron and steel, of every description whatever, and all other articles of which iron or steel form a part, at such place, or places, as said company may select in the county of Rusk, or elsewhere in the State of Texas.&#8221;</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this act take effect from its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>May 23d, 1864</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER II.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act, to Incorporate the Cherokee Furnace Company.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That R. P. Mitchell, G. S. Doty, T. L. Phileo, John B. Sydnor, J. C. Green, W. W. Ford and F. M. Hicks, citizens of the State of Texas, and B. E. Jones and G. W. Weather<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ford, citizens of the State of Louisiana, their associates and successors be, and are hereby created a body corporate and politic, under the name and style of the &#8220;Cherokee Furnace Company,&#8221; with capacity to own property, real and personal, in such quantities as may be necessary for the legitimate object of this corporation, make contracts, have succession and a common seal, to make by-laws for its govern<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment, and in their own corporate name to sue and be sued, to grant and receive, and generally to do and perform such things and acts as may be necessary and proper for or incident to the fulfillment of their objects or maintenance of their rights under this act, not inconsistent with the Constitution of the State.</p>
<pb n="784" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="26" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<p>Sec. 2. That the said company is hereby created with the right to erect, own, maintain and operate a manufactory of iron and steel, of every description what<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ever, and all other articles of which iron and steel may form a part, at such place or places as said company may select within the county of Cherokee.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. The capital stock of said, company shall be divided into shares of five hundred dollars each, and the holders of shares shall constitute said company, and said capital stock shall not exceed one million of dollars.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. The corporators mentioned, in the first section of this act shall, within ninety days from its passage, cause an election to be held for a Board of Directors of not less than three, nor more than seven in number, who shall be elected by the Stockholders, at such time and place as may be appointed, and annually there<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />after; Provided, that in case of failure to elect at the stated time, the Board of Directors incumbent shall continue in office until there be an election, the time of which shall be fixed by said Board, whereof notice shall be given as required by law governing other corporations. The corporators, under this act, shall be considered a Board of Directors until the first election of Directors has taken place.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. No person shall be eligible as a Director unless he is the owner of at least ten shares of stock of the company. The said Board shall elect a President from their number, fill vacancies until the next succeeding Stockholders&#8217; meeting, and appoint such officers as they may deem necessary, and require security for the faithful performance of their respective duties. They shall have power to pre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />scribe the time and place for the payment of installment or assessment on stock; declare the forfeiture of stock for non-payment; and to do or cause to be done all other acts and things which they may deem necessary and proper in conducting the business of said company. They shall have the right to have located and surveyed such of the public land of this State, as may be necessary for the purpose of car<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />rying into successful operation their manufactory, adjoining or contiguous to their place of operation, by paying to the State the price of one dollar per acre, or may, at their option, locate the same with certificates. A majority of the Board of Di<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />rectors shall constitute a quorum for the transaction of business, but in no case shall a Director vote by proxy.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. This act shall take effect from its passage, and be in force tor twenty<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />five years.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>May 23d, 1864</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER III.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to incorporate the Henderson Masonic Female Institute.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That A. J. Smith, Wm. Stedman, Thomas A. Oliver, J. M. Dodson, William H. Estill, Bennett Boggess and John P. Grigsby, be, and they are hereby constituted a body corporate under the name of the trustees of the &#8220;Henderson Masonic Female Institute, &#8220;situated in the town of Henderson, Rusk county, Texas; and by said name may sue and be sued; enact such by-laws and rules as may be necessary for their gov<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ernment; purchase and hold property; receive donations for the use of said Insti<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tute; have a common seal, and authority to confer, though the principle of said Institute, any and all literary honors and degrees upon all the students considered by the Faculty worthy to receive the same.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That the rights and privileges herein granted shall extend to the Trustees herein named, and their successors, who shall be chosen by the members of Clinton Lodge, No. 23, F. &#38; A. Masons, at such time as said Lodge may deter<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mine and the terms of office of the Trustees aforesaid, shall be at the will of said Lodge.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That the election of the Principal, and other members of the <pb n="785" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="27" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw> Faculty of said Institute, shall remain with said Lodge, or with such Committee as said Lodge may appoint for the purpose; and the term of office of any member of the Faculty of said Institute, shall be subject to the will and pleasure of said Lodge, or of the Committee specially entrusted by said Lodge with their selection.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. That the Trustees of said Institution, and their successors, shall have the right to elect such officers, from their own number, as may be deemed necessary for the transaction of their business.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. That diplomas, granted by virtue of the authority of this act, shall be signed by the Principal of said Institute, and attested by the Secretary of the Board of Trustees.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. That this act take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>May 25th, 1864</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER IV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to authorize and require the County Courts of Hunt and Tarrant Counties to examine, and, if necessary, to correct the assessment rolls of said Counties for the year 1864, so as to conform to the several laws of this State, in relation to the assessment and collection of ad valorem taxes.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the County Courts of Hunt and Tarrant Counties be, and are hereby authorized and required to examine, and, if necessary, correct the assessment rolls of said counties for the year 1864, so as to conform to the several laws of this State, in relation to the assessment and collection of an ad valorem tax; and, if deemed necessary by said courts, to order a new assessment for said year.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>May 25th, 1864</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER V.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to incorporate the Beaver Iron Manufacturing Company.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted By the Legislature of the State of Texas, That N. A. Willett, John H. Morrison, George W. Stafford and G. G. Higgenbotham, and their associates and successors be, and they are hereby declared and constituted a body politic, under the name and style of the &#8220;Beaver Iron Manufacturing Company,&#8221; with capacity to own property both real and personal; to make contracts; to have succession and a common seal; to make by-laws for its government; and, in its corporate name, to sue and be sued; to grant and receive, and generally to do and perform such acts and things as are necessary and proper for, and incident to, the fulfillment of its objects, or maintenance of its rights under this act, and con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sistent with the provisions of the constitution of the State of Texas; and to have and exercise all of the lights, privileges and immunities granted to other corpora<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tions of a like character.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That the said, company be, and is hereby established, with the right to erect, own, maintain and operate an Iron Manufactory, including all articles manu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />factured from pig or bar iron, or derivable from the ores of iron, separately or conjointly, at such place as said company has or may elect in the county of An<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />derson.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That the business of said company shall be conducted by said corpor<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ators, and the liability of each member of said company shall be only co-extensive with the amount of stock, held or owned by him in the business.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. That the capital stock of said company shall consist of the amount taken or which may be taken, by said members, their associates and successors.</p>
<pb n="786" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="28" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<p>Sec. 5. That this charter shall expire at the end of ten years from this date.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. That this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>May 25th, 1864</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER VI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to suspend the levy and collection of a Special Tax by the County Court of Comal County, until one year after the close of the War between the Confed<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />erate States and the United States.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the act entitled &#8220;An Act to authorize the County Court of Comal County to levy a Special Tax, approved February 8th, 1860,&#8221; is hereby suspended until one year after the close of the war between the Confederate States and the United States.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>May 25th, 1864</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER VII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to incorporate the &#8220;Dallas Manufacturing Company.&#8221;</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted, by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That A. J. Cornett, Ed. C. Browder, John S. Ballard and T. E. Sherwood and their associates be, and they are hereby incorporated a body corporate under the name and style of The Dallas Manufacturing Company,&#8221; for the manufacturing of woolen and cotton goods, spinning of thread and other fabrics, for home and. public use, and to do and perform all other things necessary for the successful prosecution of the business and objects of said association; to own and hold real and personal prop<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />erty; to sue and be sued; to plead and be impleaded, and to take all other legal ways and means to carry out the objects of said association.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That the Capital Stock shall not exceed two hundred thousand dollars, which may be invested in machinery, fixtures, and in any way best calculated to insure the successful prosecution of the business of said Company. Said manu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />factory shall be located in the town of Dallas, Dallas County, Texas. The parties named and appointed by this act are hereby invested with the rights and powers of Directors until Directors may be chosen or elected by the stockholders hereafter.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That when sixty thousand dollars of the capital stock is subscribed on the books of the Company, the Directors shall proceeed to organize said Company by calling the stockholders together and dividing the capital stock into shares of one hundred dollars each. Each share will entitle the holder to one vote by himself or proxy. Any stockholder may transfer his or her share or shares of stock, in writing, properly attested.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. That the government of the affairs of said Company shall be vested in a Board of four Directors, a majority of whom shall constitute a quorum to do busi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ness. The stockholders shall elect one of their number President of said Company. The Directors shall give at least ten days&#8217; notice to each stockholder of the time and place of election for President and new Directors, who shall hold their office for two years and have the power to fill, by appointment, any vacancy that may occur in said Board, until the next regular election. They shall also have power to appoint such other officers, for said Company, as they may find to be necessary, and may re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />quire bonds and security for the faithful performance of their several duties. The books of said Company shall be open to the inspection of the stockholders at all times.</p>
<pb n="787" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="29" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<p>Sec. 5. That any stockholder failing or refusing to pay in his stock or any in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />stalment, after ninety days&#8217; notice from the Directors, without good cause shown, said stock shall be forfeited to the Company, together with all instalments pre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />viously paid. No stockholder shall be liable for any debt or liability of said Com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pany for more than the amount of stock subscribed by him.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. That the rights, powers, privileges and immunities hereby granted and conferred under this act, shall remain in force for the term of twenty-five years.</p>
<p>Sec. 7. That this act shall take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>May 26th, 1864</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER VIII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act for the relief of Robert Pulsford.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That Robert Pulsford, of the Kingdom of Great Britain, be and he is hereby relieved from the disability of alienage, so far as to permit him to hold by conveyance a certain in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />terest in the John R. Harris and John Brown leagues of land, in Harris county, and for the purpose of receiving and securing the same, and of disposing and con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />veying said land, he is hereby vested with all the rights and privileges of a citizen of this State.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this act take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>May 26th, 1864</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER IX.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to Incorporate the &#8220;Trinity Mills Manufacturing Company.&#8221;</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted, by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That Frank M. Wigginton, Ward H. Witt and Richard B. Murphy, and their associates, be and they are hereby incorporated a body corporate and politic, under the name and style of the &#8220;Trinity Mills Manufacturing Company,&#8221; for the manufacture of woolen and cotton goods, spinning of thread and other fabrics for home and public use, and to do and perform all other things necessary for the successful prosecution of the objects of said association, to own and hold personal property, and such real property as may be necessary for the use of the Company in the erection of buildings and carrying on the business of the Company, and such lands as said Company may receive from the State, under the provisions of &#8220;An Act to encourage the erection of certain machinery by donation of land and otherwise, approved December 15th, 1863;&#8221; and in all suits and legal process against this Cor<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />poration, it shall be sufficient to make service as in other cases upon the Presi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dent, or to leave a copy of the citation and petition at the usual place of the Cor<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />poration for doing business.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That the capital stock shall not exceed two hundred thousand dollars, which may be invested in machinery, fixtures, and in any other way best calcu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lated to insure the successful prosecution of the business of said Company. Said manufactory to be located at the Trinity Mills, in Dallas County, Texas. The parties named and appointed in this act are hereby invested with the rights and powers of directors until directors may be elected or chosen by the stockholders.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That when one hundred thousand dollars of the capital stock is sub<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />scribed on the books of the Company, the Directors shall proceed to organize said Company by calling the stockholders together and dividing the capital stock into shares of one hundred dollars each, and each share will entitle the holder to one vote by himself or proxy. Any stockholder may transfer his or her stock, in writing, properly attested.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. That the government of the affairs of said Company shall be vested <pb n="788" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="30" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw> in a Board of three Directors, a majority of whom shall constitute a quorum to do business. The stockholders shall elect one of their number President of said Com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pany. The Directors shall give at least ten days&#8217; notice to each stockholder of the time and place of election for President and Directors, who shall hold their office for two years, and have the power to fill, by appointment, any vacancy that may occur in said Board, until the next regular election. They shall also have the power to appoint such other officers for said Company as they may find to be necessary, and may require bonds and security for the faithful performance of their several duties. The books of said Company shall be open to the inspection of the stock<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />holders at all times.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. That any stockholder failing or refusing to pay in his stock or any instalment after ninety days&#8217; notice from the Directors, without good cause shown, said stock shall be forfeited to the Company, together with all instalments pre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />viously paid. No stockholder shall be liable for any debt or liability of said Com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pany for more than the amount of stock subscribed by him.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. That the rights, powers, privileges and immunities hereby granted and conferred under this act shall remain in force for the term of twenty years.</p>
<p>Sec. 7. That this act take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>May 26th, 1864</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER X.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to incorporate &#8220;The Star State Machine and Manufacturing Company.&#8221;</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That A. M. Gentry, Ralph Hooker, Samuel G. Powell, Geo. H. Bringhurst and Sam&#39;l Myers and their associates and successors be, and the same are hereby declared and constituted a body corporate and politic, under the name and style of &#8220;The Star State Machine and Manufacturing Company,&#8221; with capacity to contract, own and maintain such real and personal estate as may be necessary for the prosecution of its business and carrying into effect the object of its organization, at such place or places in the State of Texas as it may determine, to make con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tracts, to have succession and a common seal, to make by-laws for the govern<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment and regulation of its affairs, to sue and be sued, to sell, alienate and transfer its property and products, and generally to do and perform all such acts and things as it may be necessary and proper for the fulfillment of its objects, or the maintenance of its rights under this act, and consistent with the Constitution of this State.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That said company is hereby created with the right to erect, own, main<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tain and operate manufactories and spinning jennies, looms, knitting machines, cotton and wool cards, and all such manufacturing and other machinery and im<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />plements as the necessities of the country may require, together with the right to manufacture all articles of cotton, wool, wood or metals or other substances, the materials of which are the products of the State of Texas, that may be required by the Confederate, or State Governments, or the people at large.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. The capital stock of said company shall be divided into shares of one hundred dollars each, and the holders of said shares shall constitute the company, and the capital stock shall be limited to five millions of dollars.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. The business of said company shall be conducted by a Board of Directors of not less than three nor more than five, to be chosen by the stockholders annually. After the first election the said Directors shall elect a President from among their own number, who shall be the chief executive officer of the company, and upon whom all legal service may be made at the principal office of the company, which shall be considered its domicil.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. The Board shall elect or appoint other such officers and agents as it may deem necessary, and exact security for the faithful performance of their duties; fix the time for payment of all instalments upon subscription to <pb n="789" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="31" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw> the stock, to declare forfeitures of stock for non-payment, and a majority of the Board shall constitute a quorum for the transaction of business.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. That the parties (or a majority of them) named, in the first section of this act, are hereby invested with the right and authority to organize said com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pany, whenever one hundred thousand dollars of the capital stock shall have been subscribed and twenty-five per cent, thereof paid in cash, and that this act shall expire at the expiration of twenty years from its passage.</p>
<p>Sec. 7. That no person shall be eligibl e to the office of Director, who shall not be the holder of at least ten shares of the capital stock; each share shall en<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />title the owner thereof to one vote in person or by proxy, and the shares shall only be transferable in such manner as may be prescribed by the by-laws, and shall be deemed personal property.</p>
<p>Sec. 8. This company shall be entitled to the benefits of any laws which have heretofore been, or may bereafter be, passed by the Legislature of this State, to encourage the erection of machinery or manufactories by donations of land or otherwise.</p>
<p>Sec. 9. This company shall have put in operation some of its machinery for the manufacture of gowns or socks, drawers and shirts, or have manufactured and offered for sale to the Government or people on or before the first day of January, 1865, or this charter shall be null and void, otherwise to be in full force and effect.</p>
<p>Sec. 10. That this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>May 28th, 1864</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to incorporate &#8220;The Falls of Brazos Manufacturing Company.&#8221;</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That Churchill Jones and his associates are hereby created a body corporate and politic under the name and style of &#8220;The Falls of Brazos Manufacturing Com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pany,&#8221; with capacity in said corporate name to make contracts, to have suc<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cession and a common seal, to make by-laws for the government and regulation of its affairs, to sue and be sued, to plead and be impleaded, to grant and re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ceive, and do and perform all such acts and things as may be necessary and proper for or incident to the fulfillment of its obligations or the maintenance of its rights under this act and consistent with the Constitution.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Said company is hereby invested with the right, power and authority to erect, own, establish, maintain and operate a cotton and woolen manufactory, grist, saw and flouring mill or mills in the County of Falls, at or near the falls of the Brazos river, or at such place as they may designate, with a capital stock of one hundred thousand dollars, to be invested in the purchase of lands, build<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ings, machinery, mills, looms, spindles, &#38;c., with the right to erect such buildings and establish such mills and shops as may be necessary to the success of said company, and to invest so much of the capital stock in negroes, cotton, wool, and other goods, as said company may deem expedient in the prosecution of said enterprise.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That the said Churchill Jones and his associates; so soon as thirty thousand dollars is subscribed and paid in, may proceed to organize said company, calling the stockholders together for that purpose; the capital of said company to consist of all its property, real and personal, franchises and rights to property, and shall be divided into shares of one hundred dollars each, each share entitling the owner thereof to one vote, by himself or proxy, at all the meetings of said company; said shares shall be deemed personal estate and shall be transferable by any conveyance in writing, recorded by the Treasurer or Secretary in a book kept for that purpose, or in such other manner as the by-laws of the company shall provide.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. The government of the affairs of the company shall be vested in a <pb n="790" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="32" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw> Board of Directors, to consist of three persons, who shall elect one of their number President of said company: Provided, no person shall be eligible to the office of Director unless he is the owner of three or more shares of the stock of said company. The directors shall be elected for one year, and shall have power to fill all vacancies of any and every kind, and may appoint or elect a Secretary, Treasurer, Superintendent, and such other officers and agents as they may think necessary, and require bond for the faithful performance of their duties. They shall also have the right to pass and adopt all needful by-laws and regulations for the conduct of their business, and shall cause to be kept accurate records of all meetings of the Board of Directors of said company, which records shall at all times be open to the inspection of the stockholders of said company, together with such other books as may be necessary to show at all times the amount of expenditures, receipts and disbursements of said company.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. The Board of Directors shall be convened by the President, who shall preside at all meetings of the Board, and in his absence a President pro tem. shall be appointed by the directors, and all conveyances, contracts, sales or pur<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />chases, together with other business operations of the company, shall be signed by the President, countersigned by the Secretary or Treasurer, as the company may direct, and under seal of the company.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. Any agreement in writing, by which any person or persons shall be<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />come a subscriber to the stock of said company, may be enforced against him ac<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cording to its terms, and if any subscriber shall fail to pay his stock or any instalment thereon within ten days from the date said instalment is required to be paid, the directors may sell at auction and transfer to the purchaser the share or shares of such delinquent, and if the proceeds of sale shall not be sufficient to pay the amount due on said subscription, with interest and charges thereon ac<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cruing, such delinquent shall be held responsible and liable for the remainder due the company, and if the proceeds shall exceed the amount due the company, said delinquent shall be enttitled to the surplus.</p>
<p>Sec. 7. Said company may acquire real estate by purchase or donation, which real estate may form a part of the capital stock of said company, which may be disposed of to aid in the construction of said manufacturing mills, &#38;c.: Provided, nothing in this act shall be so construed as to confer banking powers or privileges.</p>
<p>Sec. 8. The rights, powers, privileges and immunities hereby granted, shall be and remain in force for twenty years from and after the passage of this act.</p>
<p>Sec. 9. Each subscriber who may invest capital in the stock of the Fails of Brazos Manufacturing Company, and be a holder of the same, shall at all times receive the dividend due him when declared, if any: Provided, the directors may, if they deem it proper, invest said dividends in extending and enlarging their manufacturing operations.</p>
<p>Sec. 10. No stock or shareholder shall be responsible or liable for any debts or contracts made or entered into by the President or any agent of said company, not within the legitimate and bona fide business of said company, but shall be liable in proportion to the amount of his or her stock only for the bona fide debts of said company, in prosecuting the works, and carrying into effect the true in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />terest and intentions of the company, in accordance with the provisions of this act, and said liabilities shall be assessed, adjudged and collected in the event of failure, dissolution or loss pro rata upon each stockholder, in proportion to the amount of stock subscribed and paid, and the stock book of said company shall be the criterion by which the liability of each stockholder shall be arrived at.</p>
<p>Sec. 11. This act shall take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>May 28th, 1864</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<pb n="791" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="33" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act for the Relief of Indigent Families of Calhoun, Refugio, San Patricio and Nueces Counties.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, that the provisions of an act entitled &#8220;An Act to donate a part of the State and County Taxes of Galveston County, for the year 1863, and during the continuance of the present war, to that county for the relief of the indigent families of the County of Galveston,&#8221; shall be, and the same is extended to Calhoun, Refugio, San Patricio and Nueces Counties.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>May 28th., 1864</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XIII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act for the relief of Lieut. W. H. Cochran, A. A. C. S., of the Mounted Regi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment, T. S. T.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Adjutant and Inspector General of the State of Texas, be and he is hereby au<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />thorized and required to pass and approve, if found correct, the accounts of Lieut. W. H. Cochran, A. A. C. S., Mounted Regiment T. S. T., for subsistence stores issued by order of Capt. H. T. Edgar, to the indigent families of soldiers of said regiment, in the County of Uvalde, between the first day of November, 1863, and the twenty-ninth day of February, 1864, amounting in value to the sum of three hundred and ninety-three dollars and forty-three cents.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. The amount so allowed shall be certified to the Comptroller&#8217;s office, and deducted from the appropriation for the support of soldiers&#8217; families due said county, and this act shall be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>May 28th, 1864</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XIV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to Incorporate the &#8220;Independence Manufacturing Company.&#8221;</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That John McKnight, Albert G. Haynes and Willett Holmes, and their associates and suc<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cessors be and they are hereby incorporated a body politic and corporate under the name and style of the &#8220;Independence Manufacturing Company,&#8221; and by that name may sue and be sued, plead and be impleaded in any of the courts of this State, to hold real and personal estate, to sell and convey the same or any part thereof, to contract and be contracted with, and to perform all other acts and things necessary for the successful prosecution of the objects of the association; provided, however, the said corporation shall not acquire or hold more real estate than is necessary for the purposes of said corporation in carrying on their cor<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />porate business.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Said Company may manufacture cotton and woolen goods, woolen rolls and any other fabrics and articles, for home and public use, said Company may at any time choose to manufacture.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. The capital stock of said Company shall not exceed the sum of two hundred thousand dollars, to be divided into shares of one hundred dollars each, and may be invested in any manner best calculated to insure the success<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ful prosecution of the business of the company.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. When fifty thousand dollars shall be subscribed, the stockholders may elect not less than three nor more than five Directors who shall hold their office for one year, and until their successors are elected and qualified. Said Directors may proceed to elect a President from among their number, who shall <pb n="792" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="34" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw> hold his office for the term of one year. They shall also have power to appoint such other officers as they may find necessary, and require bonds for the faithful performance of their respective duties.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. The Board of Directors shall be convened by the President, who shall preside at all meetings of the Board and stockholders, and in his absence a President pro tem. may be elected.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. That this act shall continue in force for and during the term of twenty years from its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>May 28th, 1864</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to incorporate &#8220;The Texas Copper Manufacturing Company.&#8221;</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That D. B. Culberson, M. D. K. Taylor, Wm. R. Shannon, H. C. Lyon, Wm. De Ryee, and E. Pendleton, and their associates and successors, be and the same are hereby declared and constituted a body politic under the name and style of &#8220;The Texas Copper Manufacturing Company, &#8220;with capacity to own property, both real and personal; to make contracts; to have succession and a common seal; to make by-laws for its government, and in its corporate name to sue and be sued; to grant and receive, and generally to do and perform such acts and things necessary and proper for, and incident to, the fulfillment of its objects, or maintenance of its rights under this act, and consistent with the provisions of the Constitution of the State of Texas.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That the said Company be and is hereby established with the right to erect, own and operate a Copper, Iron, Sulphur and Saltpetre Manufactory at such place or places as said Company may elect.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That the Capital Stock of said Company shall be divided into shares of one hundred dollars each, and the holders of said shares shall constitute said Company; and said Capital Stack shall not exceed one hundred thousand dollars.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. That the affairs and business of said Company shall be conducted by a Board of Directors, not less than three nor more than five, who shall be elected by the stockholders at their organization, under this act, and annually thereafter; Provided, that in ease of failure to elect at the stated time or times that the Board of Directors incumbent shall continue in office until there be an election, the time for which may be fixed by said Board; of which reason<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />able notice shall be given.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. No person shall be eligible as a Director unless he be a member of the Company. The said Board shall elect a President from their number, fill vacancies and appoint such officers as they may deem necessary, and require security for the faithful performance of their respective duties, and to do gen<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />erally, or cause to be done, all other acts and things which they shall deem proper in conducting the affairs of said Company. A majority of the Board of Directors shall constitute a quorum to do business.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. That the parties named in this act are hereby appointed Commis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sioners and invested with the right of organizing said Company, and that this charter shall expire at the end of twenty-five years from the passage of this act, and for that period the Commissioners, or their associates and successors, shall have the right to work and operate any mine or mines, ore or ores, re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />served to the State, free from charge, let or hindrance on the part of the State of Texas, and may, for the purpose of operating such manufactory, use, free from charge, such timber or coal, from public lands of the State, as may be necessary for said purpose.</p>
<p>Sec. 7. That this act take effect from its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>May 23th, 1864</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<pb n="793" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="35" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XVI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to Incorporate the &#8220;San Marcos Cotton and Woolen Manufacturing Com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pany.&#8221;</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That Wm. K. Little, L. M. Spencer and L. J. Timnes, and their associates and successors, are hereby created a body corporate and politic by the name of the &#8220;San Marcos Cotton and Woolen Manufacturing Company,&#8221; with power to sue and be sued, pled and be impleaded; to acquire, hold and convey personal prop<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />erty and such real estate as may be necessary to carry out the purposes of the corporation; to have succession and a common seal and to do such other things as are necessary to carry out the purposes of this act.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That the said company be and is hereby established with the right to erect, own and operate machinery and buildings on the San Marcos river, for the manufacture of cotton and woolen goods and such other articles as said company may at any time choose to manufacture.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That the capital stock of said, company shall be divided into shares of one thousand dollars each, and the holders of said shares shall constitute said company, and said capital stock shall not exceed two hundred thousand dollars.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. That the affairs and business of said company shall be conducted by a Board of Directors, not less than three nor more than five, composed of the stockholders; a majority of said Board of Directors shall constitute a quorum to do business, and shall continue in office until there be an election, the time for which may be fixed by said Board.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. That the parties named in this act are hereby invested with the right to export cotton for the purchase of cotton and woolen machinery necessary for said manufactory, according to law.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. That the members of said, company shall be entitled to the benefits of any bonus, loan or other benefits, that may be granted to companies or indi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />viduals, who engage in the manufacture of similar goods, by any law passed by the Legislature.</p>
<p>Sec. 7. That the parties named in the first section of this act are hereby invested with the right to organize said company and may enact such by-laws for their government as they may, from time to time, deem necessary and proper, and shall have all such rights and privileges as are by law incident to or necessary for corporations of this character.</p>
<p>Sec. 8. That this act take effect from and after its passage and continue in effect for a period of twenty years.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>May 28th, 1864</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XVII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to Incorporate &#8220;The Comal Springs Manufacturing Company.&#8221;</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That Joseph Landa and his associates and successors, be and they are hereby consti<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tuted and declared to be a body corporate and politic, under the name and style of &#8220;The Comal Springs Manufacturing Company,&#8221; with power to sue and be sued, plead and be impleaded, to acquire, hold and convey personal pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />perty, and such real property as may be necessary for the erection of buildings and carrying on the manufacturing business, as herein provided, and such land as they may become entitled to under an act granting bounties to manufactur<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing companies, to have succession and a common seal, and to do and perform all such acts and things as may be necessary to carry out the purposes of this act consistent with the Constitution of the State of Texas.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That the said company be and is hereby established, with the right to erect, own, maintain and operate establishments for the manufacture of cot<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" /><pb n="794" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="36" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw> ton and woolen goods, or such other articles for home or public use, separately or conjointly, as said company may at any time choose to manufacture, at or near the city of New Braunfels, in Comal county.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. The capital stock of said company shall consist of shares of five hun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dred dollars ($500) each, or any less amount, not exceeding the sum of eight hundred thousand dollars, and the shareholders shall make by-laws for the gov<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ernment of the affairs of the company, and create such board of management as they think proper.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. That this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage, and remain in force for twenty years.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>May 28th, 1864</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XVIII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to Incorporate &#8220;The Cairo Manufacturing Company.&#8221;</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That William Keigwin, Marshal T. Patrick, George Patrick and William B. Middleton, their associates and successors, be and are hereby constituted a body politic and cor<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />porate, under the name and style of &#8220;The Cairo Manufacturing Company,&#8221; with capacity to hold personal property and such real property as may be nec<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />essary to carry out the objects of the Corporation and also the land granted as a bonus, and the capital stock of said company shall not exceed three hundred thousand dollars; to make contracts, to have succession, a common seal, to make by-laws for its government, and in its corporate name to sue and be sued, to grant and receive, and generally to do and perform such acts and things as may be necessary and proper for, or incident to, the fulfillment of its object or the maintenance of its rights under this act, and not inconsistent with the constitu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion and laws of this State.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this company be and is hereby established, with the right to erect, own, maintain and carry on an establishment for the manufacturing of flour, wool rolls, cotton thread and cloth, on Boggy Creek, near the town of Cairo, on the Trinity river, in Leon county.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That this compare shall conduct the operations of said manufactory in such manner and form as shall be consistent with the general laws of the State, and shall be entitled to all privileges and benefits in any wise belonging to such corporations as resulting from such laws.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. This charter shall continue for twenty years, and shall be subject to future amendments upon application of a majority of the company to the Leg<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />islature.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. That this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>May 28th, 1864</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XIX.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to Incorporate the &#8220;Comal County Mutual Aid Association.&#8221;</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the officers and members of the Comal County Mutual Aid Association, as now or<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ganized, be and they are hereby constituted a body corporate and politic, under the name and style of the &#8220;Comal County Mutual Aid Association,&#8221; and be that name they and their successors and associates shall have all the ordinary privileges of a corporation, not contrary to the constitution and laws of the State of Texas, for the carrying on and conducting of a general mercantile establishment and for the purposes herein stated.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. The said Association shall furnish necessaries for its members, for fam<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ilies, and other dependents of officers and soldiers who are or may be hereafter in the service of the Government of the Confederate States of America, or who <pb n="795" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="37" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw> may have died or been disabled in said service, at prices which shall not exceed the aggregate of cost and twenty-five per centum thereon, and for accomplish<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing said objects the association may trade in any suitable manner.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. The capital stock of said company may be one hundred thousand dollars, or any less amount, in shares of thirty dollars, or any less amount, as the association may determine, and no stockholder shall be liable for any debt or liability of said association for more than the amount of his share or shares.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. That this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>May 26th, 1864</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XX.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act for the Relief of Robert Robsen.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Whereas, On the 7th day of February, 1861, an annuity contract was entered into between Robert Robsen and, Robert H. Tobin, by the terms of which the said Robsen sold and conveyed to the said Tobin all the property, real, per<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sonal and mixed, amounting in value to about the sum of $80,000, and there<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />upon delivered up to said Tobin the possession and control of said property, with a small reservation of some favorite property.</p>
<p>The consideration to be paid, by Tobin to Robsen was the annual and prompt payment of the sum of $9000, on the 1st day of January of each year, during the life time of the said Robsen, who was then an old and infirm man.</p>
<p>And Whereas, The said Tobin has retained the possession of said property, but has totally failed, up to the present time, to make any payment, as stipu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lated in said contract, and has thus left the said Rbsen without any means of support. Now, therefore,</p>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the above recited contract shall not be embraced within the class of contracts for the payment of money specified in the act known as the Stay Law, suspending all laws for the collection of debts, approved Dec. 2d, 1863, or the supplement<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ary act, approved Dec. 16th, 1863, and nothing therein contained shall restrain any court of competent jurisdiction from hearing and proceeding to trial and judgment in any action that has been or may be brought to enforce the annual payments under said contract.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. This act shall take effect and be in force from its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>May 28th, 1864</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to Incorporate the &#8220;Tyler County Card and Machine Factory.&#8221;</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas. That J. H. McKinney, T. L. Clark, and L. G. Clark, of Tyler County, and their associates and successors, be and are hereby declared and constituted a body politic and corporate, under the name and style of the &#8220;Tyler County Card and Machine Factory, with capacity to own property, both real and personal, to make con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tracts, to have succession and a common seal, to make by-laws for its govern<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment, and in its corporate name to sue and be sued, and generally to do and perform such acts as are necessary and proper to carry out the objects of this act, which are not inconsistent with the constitution and laws of the State of Texas.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That said corporation shall have the right to erect all such buildings and machinery as may be necessary to manufacture the machinery for the manu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />facture of cotton and woolen cards, and also to manufacture cotton and woolen cards.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. The capital stock of said corporation shall not exceed three hundred <pb n="796" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="38" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw> thousand dollars, and the value of real estate which may be held or owned by said corporation shall not, at any time, exceed fifty thousand dollars in value.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. The affairs and business of said corporation shall be managed by a board of directors, who shall be elected by the stockholders at their organiza<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion, under this act, and annually thereafter, and in case of failure to elect at the stated time, the incumbents shall hold on until their successors are elected. The said board shall consist of not less than three stockholders, who shall elect a President from their own number, and a majority of said board shall consti<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tute a quorum to do business.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. The parties named in this act are hereby appointed commissioners to organize said corporation under this act. The privileges herein granted shall not be extended beyond twenty-five years from the passage of this act.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. This act shall take effect from its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>May 28th, 1864</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to Incorporate the &#8220;Guadalupe Manufacturing Company.&#8221;</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That M. T. Johnson, John S. Slaughter, William Misseiger, of the county of DeWitt, State of Texas, their associates and successors, be and they are hereby created a body corporate and politic, under the name and Style of the &#8220;Guadalupe Man<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ufacturing Company,&#8221; with capacity to hold personal property, and such real property as may be necessary for the erection of buildings and carrying on the business of the corporation as herein indicated, and that all land that may be do<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />nated by the State to this corporation, to make contracts, have a common seal, establish by-laws for its government, and in their corporate name to sue and be sued, to grant and receive, and generally to do and perform such acts as may be necessary for the fulfillment of the objects of this corporation and the main<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tenance of their rights under this act, and not inconsistent with the constitution of this State.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That the said company are hereby created with the right to own, erect, maintain and carry on, a factory for the manufacture of cotton and wool rolls, and cloth of any and all kinds. That said company shall also have the privilege of running in connection with said factory a grist flouring mill, when it does not conflict with the successful operation of the manufacturing depart<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. The capital stock of said company shall not exceed five hundred thousand dollars, to be divided into such shares as the company may decide necessary.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. When one hundred thousand dollars are subscribed, the stockholders may proceed to elect two or more directors, who shall hold their offices for the term of two years; said directors shall proceed to elect one of their number President, who shall hold his office for and during the term of two years.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. That when suit shall be brought against the company, it shall be sufficient to execute process against the President, either in person or by leav<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing a copy at the office of the company, with some white person, attached to the company, over the age of eighteen years.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. Be it further enacted, That this act shall continue in force from and during the term of twenty years from its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>May 28th, 1864</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXIII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to authorize the issuance of Rations to certain employees in the Cap Factory.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the State Quartermaster be and he is hereby authorized to procure supplies and to <pb n="797" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="39" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw> issue rations to all females and males, under 16 years of age, that are now or may bereafter be employed in making percussion caps at the city of Austin: Pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vided, that he shall issue only in such quantity to each as is allowed a soldier in the Confederate States army, and that the rations so issued shall comprise such part of wages as may be agreed to between the State Quartermaster and Superintendent of the Cap Factory, with the sanction of the Military Board.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>May 28th, 1864</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXIV.</head>
<p>An Act to authorize the County Court of Caldwell County to levy and collect an ad valorem tax in specie to support the families and other dependents of soldiers.</p>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the County Court of Caldwell County, is authorized and empowered to levy and collect an ad valorem tax in specie to raise funds to support the families and other dependents of soldiers who are a charge upon said county, not to exceed one-half of one per cent, upon the value of the property taxed.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That said Court may appoint an Assessor and Collector to make the necessary assessment, and to collect the taxes to be raised under the provisions of this act, under such regulations as may be adopted by said Court.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That this act be in force and effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>May 28th, 1864</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act for the relief of the minor heirs of the late John D. Stell.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the legal representatives of the late John D. Stell, be and the same are hereby au<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />thorized to sue for and collect so much of the interests due upon notes and bonds due them, as may be by the proper authorities declared necessary for the maintenance and education of the said minor heirs of the said John D. Stell.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. All laws and parts of laws forbidding the same are hereby repealed, only so far as it relates to this act, and this act to take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>May 28th 1864</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXVI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to prohibit the sale of Ardent or Spirituous Liquors within five miles of the Court House within the Town of Waxahachie, Ellis County, except for me<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dicinal purposes.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That if any person shall, within five miles of the Court House within the town of Wax<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ahachie, Ellis county, in this State, sell any ardent or spirituous liquors, except for medicinal purposes, in any quantities whatever, such person shall, upon con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />viction thereof, be deemed guilty of a misdemeanor and fined in any sum not less than two hundred dollars and not more than one thousand dollars, and the jury trying the same may add imprisonment in the County Jail, not exceeding three months.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That if any person shall, within the District prescribed in the first section of this act, give, barter or exchange any ardent or spirituous liquors to any one with intent to evade the provisions of this law, such person shall be <pb n="798" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="40" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw> deemed guilty of a like misdemeanor, and, on conviction thereof, subject to the penalties prescribed in the first section of this act, and proof by the State of the delivery of liquors, the sale of which is herein prohibited within said District, shall be deemed prima facie evidence of intent to avoid or evade the provisions of this act; and it shall not be necessary for the State, in any indict<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment under this act, to allege or prove that liquor sold, given, bartered or ex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />changed, was not for medicinal purposes.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That all laws and parts of laws in conflict with the provisions of this act be, and the same are hereby repealed.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>May 28th, 1864</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
</div2>
<pb n="799" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="41" />
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">JOINT RESOLUTIONS.</head>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER I. JOINT RESOLUTION.</head>
<p>Resolved by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That, recognizing in Gen. E. Kirby Smith, Commander in the Trans-Mississippi Department, ability, effi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ciency and devotion to the cause of our country, we, the Representatives of the people of the State, tender to him, his officers and soldiers, our grateful thanks for the recent brilliant victories so gallantly achieved on the bloody fields of Louisiana and Arkansas, with full assurances to them that every instrumental<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ity will be employed by the State, in proper co-operation with the Department, for the consummation of our independence and the establishment of a firm and permanent government.</p>
<p>2. That the Governor of the State cause a copy of these resolutions to be forwarded to Gen. Smith, with the request that they be read to his troops on dress parade.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>May 24th, 1864</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER II.</head>
<opener>
<salute>Joint Resolution of thanks to Col. Santos Benavedes and the Officers and Men under his command.</salute>
</opener>
<p>1. Be it resolved, by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That when, in the Autumn of the past year, our enemy was invading this State from many direc<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tions, and was exultant in the prospect of success, by overpowering armies, by insiduous policy, by the aid of traitors in our midst, by desertions from our army and by the fears of the weak of faith, at a time which tried men&#8217;s souls, when unwavering patriotism and true courage were more than ever to be ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />preciated, the people of this State witnessed with admiration the attitude of Col. Santos Benavedes and his handful of men, who dared to dispute, and did successfully maintain, the possession of an extensive tract of our frontier.</p>
<p>2. That the thanks of the people of the State are due and are hereby ten<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dered to Col. Santos Benavedes, and the officers and men under his command, for their steadfact opposition to the enemy in the field and the zeal they have shown in the service of their country.</p>
<p>3. That the Governor be requested to transmit a copy of these resolutions to Col. Benavedes, and that they be read to his regiment on dress parade.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>May 24th, 1864</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<pb n="800" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="42" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER III.</head>
<opener>
<salute>Joint Resolution in relation to the Tonkaway Indians.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Whereas, From the earliest settlement of Texas, and during the war of Texan Independence and border wars with other Indian tribes, the Tonkaway Tribe of Indians have remained true and faithful, and been the close and constant allies of our people; and</p>
<p>Whereas, At the earliest dawn of the present war, said tribe declared their destiny to he our destiny, and in consequence of their fidelity to the cause of Southern Independence they were attacked by our enemies and more than one<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />half of the tribe perished, including the brave old veteran Chief Placadore, who, with his warriors, women and children, proudly perished rather than betray or desert the cause which they had espoused; and</p>
<p>Whereas, The remnant of this faithful people are now wanderers on our soil, in the most wretched and dependent condition; Therefore</p>
<p>1. Be it resolved, That the Governor take such steps to settle them on the public domain of the State, and at such place as he may deem proper.</p>
<p>2. That the sum of thirty-five thousand dollars annually, for the years 1864 and 1865, be and the same is hereby appropriated out of any money in the Treasury, not otherwise set apart, for the support and maintenance of said tribe of Indians; the same to be expended under the direction of the Governor.</p>
<p>3. That these resolutions be in force from their passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>May 28th, 1864</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER IV. JOINT RESOLUTION.</head>
<p>Whereas, Information has been received that the remains of the late Brig. Gen. Wm. R. Scurry are on the way to this place, for interment in the State Cemetery, therefore</p>
<p>1. Hesolved, That a committee of five be appointed to act in conjunction with any like committee that may be appointed on the part of the Senate, to make all suitable preparation for the proper reception of the remains of the distinguished dead, in the event they arrive here before the adjournment of the Legislature. If not, then the Governor is respectfully requested, in behalf of the State, to take such action in the premises as in his opinion may be meet and proper; and we hereby tender to him the use of this hall for the foregoing purpose.</p>
<p>2. Resolved, That the expenses of the burial be paid from the fund appro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />priated to defray the contingent expenses of the present session of the Legis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lature.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>May 28th, 1864</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
</div2>
<pb n="801" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="43" />
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">INDEX TO SPECIAL LAWS.</head>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">A</head>
<p>Page.</p>
<p>Adjutant General,</p>
<p>Authorized to issue Rations to certain employes of the Cap Factory.. <ref>38</ref></p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">B</head>
<p>Beaver Iron Manufacturing Company, Act Incorporating................................... <ref>27</ref></p>
<p>Benavedes, Col. Santos, Joint Resolution of thanks to................................... <ref>41</ref></p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">C</head>
<p>Cairo Manufacturing Company, Act of Incorporation................................... <ref>36</ref></p>
<p>Calhoun County, For the relief of indigent families of................................... <ref>33</ref></p>
<p>Caldwell County, See &#8220;County Courts&#8221;.</p>
<p>Cap Factory, Authorizing the issuance of Rations to certain employes of................................... <ref>38</ref></p>
<p>Cherokee Furnace Company, Act of Incorporation..................................................... <ref>25</ref></p>
<p>Cochran, Lieut. W. H., For the relief of............................................... <ref>33</ref></p>
<p>Comal County, See &#8220;County Courts.&#8220;</p>
<p>Comal County Mutual Aid Association, Act of Incorporation................................... <ref>36</ref></p>
<p>Comal Springs Manufacturing Company, Act of Incorporation................................... <ref>35</ref></p>
<p>Counties, For the relief of indigent of Calhoun, Refugio, San Patricio and Nueces....................................................... <ref>33</ref></p>
<p>County Courts, To examine, and if necessary, correct the Assessment Rolls for 1864 of Hunt and Tarrant Counties................................... <ref>27</ref></p>
<p>To suspend the levy and collection of a Special Tax, Comal County................................... <ref>28</ref></p>
<p>To levy and collect a Special Tax for the support of indigent families, Caldwell County................................... <ref>39</ref></p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">D</head>
<p>Dallas Manufacturing Company, Act of Incorporation................................... <ref>28</ref></p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">F</head>
<p>Falls of Brazos Manufacturing Company, Act of Incorporation................................... <ref>31</ref></p>
<pb n="802" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="44" /><fw type="header" place="top">Index.</fw>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">G</head>
<p>Guadalupe Manufacturing Company, Act of Incorporation................................... <ref>38</ref></p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">H</head>
<p>Heirs of John D. Stell, For the relief of................................... <ref>39</ref></p>
<p>Henderson Masonic Female Institute, Act of Incorporation................................... <ref>26</ref></p>
<p>Hunt County, See &#8220;County Courts.&#8221;</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">I</head>
<p>Incorporations,</p>
<p>Beaver Iron Manufacturing Company................................... <ref>27</ref></p>
<p>Cairo Manufacturing Company................................... <ref>36</ref></p>
<p>Cherokee Furnace Manufacturing Company................................... <ref>25</ref></p>
<p>Comal County Mutual Aid Association................................... <ref>30</ref></p>
<p>Comal Springs Manufacturing Company................................... <ref>35</ref></p>
<p>Dallas Manufacturing Company................................... <ref>28</ref></p>
<p>Henderson Masonic Institute................................... <ref>26</ref></p>
<p>Independence Manufacturing Company................................... <ref>33</ref></p>
<p>Falls of Frazos Manufacturing Company................................... <ref>31</ref></p>
<p>Guadalupe Manufacturing Company................................... <ref>38</ref></p>
<p>Rusk County Iron Company&#8212;Amended................................... <ref>25</ref></p>
<p>San Marcos Cotton and Woolen Manufacturing Company................................... <ref>35</ref></p>
<p>Star State Machine and Manufacturing Company................................... <ref>30</ref></p>
<p>Texas Copper Manufacturing Company................................... <ref>34</ref></p>
<p>Tyler County Card and Machine Factory................................... <ref>37</ref></p>
<p>Trinity Mills Manufacturing Company................................... <ref>29</ref></p>
<p>Independence Manufacturing Company, Act of Incorporation................................... <ref>33</ref></p>
<p>Indians, Tonkaway, Joint Resolution in relation to................................... <ref>42</ref></p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">N</head>
<p>Nueces County, For the relief of indigent families of................................... <ref>33</ref></p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">O</head>
<p>Officers and Soldiers, Joint Resolution of thanks to................................... <ref>41</ref></p>
<p>Officers and Men. Joint Resolution of thanks to................................... <ref>41</ref></p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">P</head>
<p>Pulsford, Robert, For the relief of................................... <ref>29</ref></p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">R</head>
<p>Refugio County, For the relief of indigent families of................................... <ref>33</ref></p>
<p>Robsen, Robert, For the relief of................................... <ref>37</ref></p>
<p>Rusk County Iron Company, Act of Incorporation-Amended................................... <ref>25</ref></p>
</div3>
<pb n="803" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="45" /><fw type="header" place="top">Index.</fw>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">S</head>
<p>San Marcos Cotton and Woolen Manufacturing Company, Act of Incorporation................................... <ref>35</ref></p>
<p>San Patricio County, For the relief of indigent families of................................... <ref>33</ref></p>
<p>Star State Machine and Manufacturing Company, Act of incorporation................................... <ref>30</ref></p>
<p>Stell, John D., heirs of, For the relief of................................... <ref>39</ref></p>
<p>Scurry, Brig. Gen. Win. R., Joint Resolution in relation to remains of................................... <ref>42</ref></p>
<p>Smith, Gen. E. Kirby, Joint Resolution of thanks to................................... <ref>41</ref></p>
<p>Spirituous Liquors, Sale of, prohibited within five miles of the Court House in the town of Waxahachie, Ellis County................................... <ref>39</ref></p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">T</head>
<p>Tarrant County, See &#8220;County Courts.&#8220;</p>
<p>Texas Copper Manufacturing Company, Act of Incorporation................................... <ref>34</ref></p>
<p>Tyler County Card and Machine Factory, Act of Incorporation................................... <ref>37</ref></p>
<p>Trinity Mills Manufacturing Company, Act of Incorporation................................... <ref>29</ref></p>
<p>Tonkaway Indians, Joint Resolution in relation to................................... <ref>42</ref></p>
</div3>
</div2>
<pb n="804" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="46" />
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">ERRATUM.</head>
<p>On page 18, in General Joint Resolution, Chapter VIII, second paragraph, ninth line, the word &#8220;improvements&#8221; should be &#8220;impressments.&#8221;</p>
</div2>
<pb n="805" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="47" />
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">THE STATE OE TEXAS, Department of State.</head>
<p>I, Robert J. Towne, Secretary of State of the State of Texas, do certify that I have compared the foregoing Laws and Joint Resolutions of the Extra Session of the Tenth Legislature with the originals now on file in this Department, and that they are true copies of such originals.</p>
<p>I further certify, that the Extra Session of the Tenth Legislature of the State of Texas, in compliance with the Proclamation of the Governor, assem<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />bled on Monday, the ninth day of May, A. D. 1864, and adjourned on the twen<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ty-eighth day of May, in the same year.</p>
<p>In testimony whereof, I have hereunto signed my name, and <floatingText rend="left"><body><p>| Seal. |</p></body></floatingText>caused the Seal of the Department of State to be affixed, at Austin, this 20th of Julv, A. D. 1864.</p>
<closer>
<signed>E. J. TOWNES, Secretary of State.</signed>
</closer>
<pb n="806" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="48" />
</div2>
</div1>
</body>
</text>
