<text xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 UNTtite%20(1.3).xsd" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="TEI">
<body>
<pb n="655" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="1" />
<div1 type="article">
<head type="main">GENERAL LAWS <lb/>OF <lb/>THE TENTH LEGISLATURE <lb/>OF <lb/>THE STATE OF TEXAS</head>
<byline>PUBLISHED BY AUTHORITY</byline>
<byline>HOUSTON 1864</byline>
<pb n="656" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="2" />
<pb n="657" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="3" />
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">GENERAL LAWS.</head>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER I.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act making an appropriation to defray the contingent expenses of the Tenth Legislature.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the sum of ten thousand dollars in Confederate Treasury notes, or so much thereof as may be necessary, be and the same is hereby appropriated to pay the contingent, expenses of the Tenth Legislature.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>November 16th, 1863</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER II.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to amend the first section of an Act entitled &#8220;An Act to prevent Specula<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion in Certain Cases, &#8220;Approved January 13th, 1862.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the first section of the above recited Act shall hereafter read as follows: That if any person shall falsely represent himself as a Commissary, or Quartermaster, or Purchasing Agent, of the Confederate States, or of the State of Texas, or as the sub-agent of any Commissary, Quartermaster or Purchasing Agent, as aforesaid, or as the agent of any County Court, for purchasing supplies; or of any &#8220;Mutual Aid Association;&#8221; or other association, whose object is to procure supplies for the poor and needy families of this State; or for the family or families of any Texan or Confederate&#39; States soldier, or soldiers, and shall, under such false representation, purchase any article of clothing&#8212;shoes, leather, hides, cloth, cotton or wool; or any other article of cothing, or from which clothing can be manufactured; or any provisions&#8212;wheat, flour, corn, corn-meal, meat, hogs, cattle or any other article of subsistence of any description; or any horses, mules, work oxen, wagons, ambu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lances, or any Government supplies whatever that are needed in the armies; or shall hire any negroes or other labor; or rent any houses, representing that the article or articles so purchased axe on account of, or for the use and benefit of, such State or Confederate States: or Association, or County, or families; or that the negroes or labor, or houses so hired, are for the use of the Confederate States or State of Texas, in any manner; such person shall be deemed guilty of a felony: and upon conviction thereof, in a court of competent jurisdiction, shall be punished by con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />finement in the State Penitentiary, at hard labor, not less than two, nor more than ten years, for each offence.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>November 24, 1863</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
<pb n="658" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="4" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER III.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to authorize the Supreme Court of the State, for the Galveston District, to hold its Spring Term at the City of Austin, or elsewhere.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Supreme Court of the State for the Galveston District, is hereby authorized to hold its Spring Term for the year 1864, and annually thereafter, at the City of Austin, or at such other place as the Supreme Court may determine, until the City of Galveston is permanently relieved of the presence of the public enemy</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That the Judges of said Court are hereby authorized to have the records and papers appertaining to the Supreme Court of said Galveston District, removed to the City of Austin, to be kept separate and apart from the records and papers of the Austin District, and to be returned to the Galveston District, as soon as the same may be safely done.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That this Act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>November 27th, 1863</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER IV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act for the Relief of Pre-emption Settlers and to extend the time for the re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />turn of the field notes, and to extend the time for the payment of all dues by settlers, under Acts authorizing the Sale of the Public Domain.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That all settlers under the various Pre-emption Laws, shall have until the 1st day of January, 1866, to return their field notes and pay the dues thereon.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. All laws conflicting with the first section of this Act, are hereby re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pealed.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That this act shall take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>November 27th, 1863</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER V.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to authorize the use of the Jails of the several Counties for the Custody of Deserters and other offenders against Military Law.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That it shall be the duty of the Sheriffs of the several counties of the State of Texas, to receive into custody, and safely keep, all persons committed to their charge by an order of a commissioned officer in the military service of the Confederate States, or of the State of Texas; That the order of the officer committing the offender shall be a sufficient warrant to the Sheriff receiving into his custody the person or per<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sons charged with desertion, or any other offence against the military law; and it shall be the duty of the Sheriff to safely keep said prisoner or prisoners until other<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />wise ordered by the military authorities, or until discharged by due course of the law of the land; Provided, however, that the military officers committing said of<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fenders, shall provide for their subsistence, and shall furnish a sufficient guard if the jail be insecure.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this Act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>November 27th, 1863</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER VI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to amend the finst section of an Act to cede Jurisdiction in certain cases, passed Dec. 19th, 1849.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the first section of the above recited Act shall hereafter read as follows: The Confederate States of America shall be, and are hereby authorized and empow<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ered, to purchase, acquire, hold, own, occupy and possess, such land or lands <pb n="659" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="5" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw> within the limits of this State, as they shall judge it expedient, and shall seek to occupy and hold, as sites on which to erect and maintain light houses, forts, garri<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sons, military stations, magazines, arsenals, dock-yards, armories or manufactories for arms or munitions, and all other needful buildings or any of them, as contem<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />plated and provided in the Constitution of the Confederate States of America; said purchases to be effected either by contract with the owner or owners of said land or lands, or in the manner hereinafter provided.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this act be in force from its passage</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>November 27th, 1863</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER VII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to amend all laws for the Collection of Debts and Liabilities on Bonds, Promissory Notes, Bills of Exchange, and Contracts for the Payment of Money, until twelve months after the Ratification of a Treaty of Peace between the Con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />federate States of America and the United States of America, or until otherwise provided by law.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That until twelve months after the ratification of a treaty of peace between the Confed<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />erate States of America and the United States of America, or until otherwise pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vided by law, all laws for the collection of debts and liabilities on bonds, promissory notes, bills of exchange,, and contracts for the payment of money, except in cases of official liabilities on the part of public officers, liabilities and indebtedness to the State, and also where money has been received on deposit, or in trust for those who may be entitled to the same, and for the collection of the interest on the money loaned at interest by guardians, belonging to their wards, are hereby suspended: Provided, That this act shall not be construed to forbid the issuance of writs of at<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tachment, sequestration, or injunction, nor the institution of necessary preliminary proceedings for that purpose, in accordance with existing laws; and, provided, fur<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ther, that this act shall not apply to any claim or demand against alien enemies; and, provided further, that this act shall not be so construed as to interfere with the action of the Supreme Court in deciding all cases as now directed by law.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this act shall not apply to parties who have cases now pending in the Courts, who agree, in open Court, to proceed to trial.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That until the expiration of the time named in the first section of this act, or until otherwise provided by law, no execution or venditioni exponas, founded upon any judgment or decree, obtained previous to the passage of this act, shall be issued for the sale of property, nor shall there be any sales under execution or writs of venditioni exponas, now issued or levied, unless the judgment creditor, or his agent or attorney, shall make an affidavit in writing, before the Justice of the Peace, or the Clerk of the Court, to whom he shall apply for said execution or venditioni exponas, that the defendant is about to remove his property beyond the State, or the County where the judgment or decree was rendered, or that he is about to transfer or secrete, or has transferred or secreted his property, for the purpose of defrauding bis creditors, and that, thereby, the plaintiff will probably lose his debt; and he shall also swear that the writ is not sued out for the purpose of injuring the defendant: Provided, That any debtor or defendant, who may have property in the hands of the Sheriff or other officer, under levy of execution or ven<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ditioni exponas, shall, within sixty days after the passage of this act, replevy the same, by giving bond in double the value of the property, or the amount of the debt, if it be less, with good and sufficient security, payable to the plaintiff in the writ, for the forthcoming of the property when the remedies for the collection of debts, hereby suspended, shall be revived.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. That this act shall not be construed to discharge the lien which has already been acquired by due process of law, nor shall the time, during which this law is in force, be computed in any case where the statute of limitation comes in question.</p>
<pb n="660" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="6" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<p>Sec. 5. That during the time named in this act, or until otherwise provided by law, it shall not be necessary to issue execution or writs of venditioni exponas to prevent judgments from becoming dormant, nor shall it be necessary for the holder of any bill of exchange or promissory note to bring suit against the acceptor of such bill of exchange, or against the maker of such promissory note, in order to secure and fix the liability of any drawer, or endorser, of such bill of exchange, or any endorser of such promissory note.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. That until the time named in the first section of this act, or until other<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />wise provided by law, there shall be no sales of property under deeds of trust, or mortgages, or hypothecations in writing; but the beneficiaries under the same shall be entitled to the benefits of the writ of sequestration, in accordance with the ex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />isting laws: Provided, That in all cases where the property conveyed by deeds of trust, or mortgages with power of sale in the mortgagee, may be of a perishable na<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ture and liable to depreciation in value by lapse of time, the beneficiaries in such deeds of trust or mortgages shall, after the maturity of the same, be entitled to the benefits of the writ of sequestration, upon making affidavit in writing before the officer to whom he shall apply for said writ as follows, to wit: First, that he holds an unsatisfied deed of trust, or mortgage, upon the property sought to be sequestered, and which shall be described in the affidavit, and shall also state that the debt secured by said deed of trust, or mortgage, is due and unpaid, and the amount thereof; second, that the said property is of a perishable nature and is depreciating in value, or that it is being wasted by the person in possession of the same, and that, by reason of such depreciation or waste, the security provided by such deed of trust, or mortgage, will become insufficient before the lapse of time provided for in this act, for the payment of the amount due on such deed of trust or mortgage, and thereupon said writ of sequestration shall be issued, and the property seques<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tered may be replevied by the debtor, or grantor in said deed of trust or mortgage, or in default thereof, by the beneficiary therein, as now provided by law, under the act regulating sequestration.</p>
<p>Sec. 7. That until the time named in this act, or until otherwise provided by law, no property of any soldier, seaman, or marine, now or hereafter engaged in the military or naval service of the Confederate States of America or the State of Texas, shall, during such service, be levied On under execution, or sold by virtue of any levy heretofore made; nor shall the property of any such soldier or marine be subject to attachment, or writs of venditioni exponas, or sequestration, during his continuance in said service.</p>
<p>Sec. 8. That this act shall take effect and be in force from and after the first day of January, A. D., 1864.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>December 2d, 1863</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER VIII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to provide for the employment of additional labor in the State Penitentiary.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That it shall be the duty of the Financial Agent of the State Penitentiary, under the ad<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vice of the Directors thereof, to hire an additional amount of labor for said Peni<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tentiary.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That said Financial Agent shall employ either white persons or slaves, or both, to labor in said Penitentiary, as may be found most advantageous to said in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />stitution; and as much labor shall be so employed as can be advantageously used in working the whole of the machinery of said institution.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That in all receipts and disbursements of money, under the provisions of this act, the said Financial Agent shall be governed by the laws in force in other eases; and he shall also include in his annual reports to the Directors an account of such action as he may take, under the provisions of this act.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. That in order to carry out the provisions of this act, said, financial Agent is authorized to use such an amount of money as may be necessary, out <pb n="661" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="7" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw> of the appropriation made for the purposes of the Penitentiary, or out of the pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ceeds of sales of articles manufactured therein</p>
<p>Sec. 5. That this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>December 2d. 1863</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER IX.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act making an appropriation for the mileage and per diem pay of the Members, and the per diem pay of the Officers of the Tenth Legislature of the State of Texas.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the sum of seventy-five thousand dollars in Confederate Treasury notes, or so much thereof as may be necessary, be and the same is hereby appropriated, out of any money in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated, for the mileage and per diem pay of the members and the per diem pay of the officers of the Tenth Legislature of the State of Texas.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That the certificate of the Secretary of the Senate and the Certificate of the Chief Clerk of the House, shall be sufficient evidence to the Comptroller, upon which he shall audit the claims and draw his warrants upon the Treasurer for the respective amounts.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That this act be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>December 4th. 1863</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER X.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to require District Attorneys to report to the Comptroller&#8217;s Office in certain Cases.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Comptroller shall furnish to the several District Attorneys respective statements of defalcations to the State in their districts, specifying names of defaulters and amounts due, which claims shall have been placed in charge of said Attorneys for collection; and thereupon said Attorneys, respectively, shall make complete returns to the Comptroller twice a year at the expiration of the regular circuits of the courts of the Districts, showing the exact condition of any suits that shall have been instituted for such collections, and the precise situation of the collections, that shall have been made, either with or without suits; and in any case where such At<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />torney shall have failed to make such return, the salary of such delinquent shall not be paid until the proper return shall have been received at the Comptroller&#39;s Office.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. This Act shall be in force from its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>December 4th, 1863</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to amend &#8220;An Act concerning Common Carriers, and defining their liabilities in certain cases,&#8221; approved February 4th, 1860.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the first section of an &#8220;Act concerning Common Carriers and defining their liabilities in certain cases.&#8221; approved February 4th, 1860, be so amended as hereafter to read as follows, to-wit: Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That railroad companies and other common carriers of goods, wares, and merchandize for hire, within this State, on land, or in boats, or vessels, on the skaters entirely within the body of this State, shall not limit, or restrict their liability, as it exists at common law, by any general or special notice, nor by inserting exceptions in the bill of Lading, nor memorandum given upon the receipt of the goods for transportation, nor in any other manner whatever, and <pb n="662" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="8" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw> no special agreement, made in contravention of the foregoing provisions of this sec<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion, shall be valid.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this Act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>December 4th, 1863</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to amend the 1st section of an Act approved January 14th, 1862, to fix the salaries of the officers and Clerks therein named.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the first section of the above recited Act shall hereafter read as follows, viz: That the salary of the Governor&#8217;s Private Secretary shall be twelve hundred dollars per annum.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this Act shall take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>December 4th, 1863</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XIII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to provide for the Manufacture of Spinning Jennies.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That it shall be the duty of the Military Board to cause to be constructed, with as much dispatch as practicable, at the State Foundery in the city of Austin or elsewhere, machines for spinning cotton thread, commonly called spinning jennies, to be sold to the people and the proceeds of the sales paid into the State Treasury; and in the sales of said machines, regard shall be had, as far as practicable, to the wants of the people in different parts of the State.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That for the purpose of carrying into effect the foregoing section, the sum of two hundred thousand dollars, or so much thereof as may be necessary, is hereby appropriated.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That this Act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>December 7th, 1863</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XIV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to amend &#8220;An Act to suspend the operations of the Estray Laws, for and during the existence of the present War, and for six months after its termination, except in certain cases,&#8221; approved February 25th, 1863, shall hereafter read as follows, to-wit:</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That from and after the passage of this Act, all laws and parts of laws, providing for the estraying of stock, and prescribing the course of proceedings in the same, and of selling stock heretofore estrayed, shall be in all things suspended for and during the existence of the present war, and until six months after peace shall be concluded, with the exceptions hereinafter mentioned.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That any person may have the right, under the regulations now in force for estraving stock, to estray any vicious animal, or breachy stock, that is likely to injure the stock in the ranged or the property of any person, and any person desiring to estray any such stock shall, in addition to the regulations heretofore prescribed, prove by two credible witnesses, by an affidavit in writing, to be filed with the papers in the County Clerk&#8217;s office, that the property estrayed is vicious, breachy, or so unruly as to be dangerous, and unfit to run at large.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That any person or persons, having estrayed, any property which was un<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sold at the time of approving of the above Act, he, she, or they, shall proceed to sell such stock, as heretofore prescribed for selling estray stock.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. Provided, that in all cases of sales under this Act of stock hereafter estrayed under the provisions of this Act, the person estraying said stock shall <pb n="663" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="9" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw> not be permitted, either directly or indirectly, to bid for such stock, and shall, after deducting the amount of fees for estraying, pay the whole amount of the sale into the County Treasury for the use of the county, if not claimed by the legal owner of said stock.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. That this Act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>December 7th, 1863</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to raise Two Millions of Dollars, or so much thereof as may be necessary, by the Sale of Cotton Bonds, to provide for the Defense of the State and to Repel Invasion, and for the Purchase of Machinery for manufacturing purposes.</salute>
</opener>
<p>In view of the existing war, waged by the people and Government of the United States, against the people and Government of the Confederate States, and for the purpose of repelling the invasion of this State by the enemy, therefore, Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas.</p>
<p>Section 1. That the Governor of the State of Texas be, and he is hereby author<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ized to sell, or have sold, the bonds of the State to the amount of Two Millions of Dollars, or so much of said sum as he may deem necessary, to meet the purposes contemplated in this Act.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That said bonds shall be issued in such sums as the Governor of the State shall deem most suitable; and, if he should deem it advisable, he may author<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ize said bonds to bear interest, not exceeding six per cent. per annum; said interest to be paid at the same time, and in the same manner hereinafter prescribed for the payment of the principal.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That the payment of the bonds issued in pursuance of the provisions of this Act, shall be made in predicated upon, and secured by the cotton now be<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />longing, or which may bereafter belong, to the State of Texas. The quality of said cotton and the price thereof, shall be fixed by the Governor and specified on the face of said bonds; that the cotton so pledged for the payment of said bonds, shall be delivered, in good merchantable order, free of carriage, at any port in the State of Texas not in possession of the enemy, at which the holder or holders of the bonds may demand, with the exception of such ports as lie South of Pass Cavallo; that the State shall pay all export duties on said cotton, and shall issue a certificate of ownership, and procure an export permit to accompany the delivery of said cotton; Provided, however, that if the owner or owners of said bond or bonds, shall fail to demand the delivery of said cotton before the expiration of six calendar months after a treaty of peace between the belligerents mentioned in the beginning of this Act, then said bond or bonds may be discharged, by the State paying in money the face value of said bond or bonds, with interest thereon at the rate at which said bond or bonds may have been negotiated, from the date of the sale of said bond or bonds, which date shall be endorsed thereon by the agent author<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ized to negotiate the sale of said bonds.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. That said bonds shall be signed by the Governor, countersigned by the Comptroller, and bear the Seal of the State.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. That the Governor of the State be and is hereby authorized to appoint, at a reasonable compensation, some suitable person or firm, to act as agent in Europe, or elsewhere, to verify, issue, endorse and dispose of said bonds, with power to substitute other agents in his or their stead; and no bond shall confer any right until verified, issued and endorsed by said agent or substituted agent, who shall be commissioned by the Governor under the Seal of the State.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. That the money raised by the sale of the bonds issued in pursuance of the provisions of this Act, shall constitute a special fund, to be used only in pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />viding for the defense of the State, and repelling any invasion of the same, and for the purchase of the machinery for manufacturing purposes.</p>
<p>Sec. 7. That this Act shall take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>December 10th, 1863</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
<pb n="664" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="10" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XVI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to amend the caption and first section of &#8220;an Act relating to Forfeitures in certain cases of Bail Bonds and Recognizances, in cases of Misdemeanor, &#8220;ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />proved Dec. 9th, 1861.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the cap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion of the above named Act be and the same is hereby amended so as hereafter to read as follows, to-wit: &#8220;An Act relating to forfeitures in certain cases of bail bonds and recognizances in cases of felonies and misdemeanors.&#8221;</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That the first section of the above entitled Act shall hereafter read as follows: That during the continuance of the existing war between the Confed<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />erate States of America and the United States, no forfeitures of any bail bond or recognizance, executed or entered into, by any defendant or surety for a defendant, witness or surety for a witness, in any case of misdemeanor or felony, shall be taken or entered by any court in this State, against such defendant or surety for defendant, witness or surety for witness, while such defendant or witness shall be in the military or naval service of the Confederate States of America or of this State; nor shall any such forfeiture be taken or entered against any such surety of a defendant or witness, while such surety shall be in such service.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. This Act shall take effect and be in force from and after its passage, and shall cease to be of force or effect from and after the establishment of peace be<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tween the Confederate States and the United States.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>December 10th, 1863</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XVII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to amend the first section of &#8220;An Act to regulate proceedings in the Dis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />trict Courts, &#8220;approved May 13th, 1846.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the first section of an Act entitled &#8220;An Act to regulate procedings in the District Courts,&#8221; approved May 13th, 1846, be so amended as to read as follows: No person who is an inhabitant of this State shall be sued out of the County where he has his domicil, except in the following cases, viz: First, in case of married women, who must be sued in the county where her husband has his domicil; Second, in case the defendant is a transient person, in which case he may be sued in what<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ever county he may be found: Third, in cases where there may be two or more defendants residing in different counties, in which cases the plaintiff may institute suit in any county where any of such defendants may reside: Fourth, in cases where a person has contracted to perform an obligation in any particular county, in which case suit may be instituted in that county, or where the defen<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dant has his domicil; Fifth, in cases of executors, administrators or guardians of an estate, or, trustees, who must be sued in the county in which the estate is administered; Sixth, in cases of fraud and also in cases of defalcation of public officers, in which cases suit may be instituted in the county where the fraud was committed, or where the defalcation occurred, or whore the defendant has his domicil; Seventh, where the defendant has committed some crime, or offence, or trespass, for which a civil action in damages may be commenced, in which cases, suit may be instituted in the county where the Crime or offence or trespass was committed, or in the county where the defendant has his domicil; Eighth, in cases where the suit is for a slave, animal, or other movable property, in which cases suit may be instituted in whatever county such property may be found, or where the defendant resides; Ninth, in cases where the defendant has inherited an estate, concerning which suit is commenced, in which case suit may be instituted in the county where the estate principally lies; Tenth, in cases for the foreclosure of mortgages or lien, in which cases suit may be instituted in the county where the mortgaged property or property subject to lien, or any <pb n="665" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="11" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw> part thereof, may be; Eleventh, in cases where the recovery of land, or damages thereto, is the object of a suit, in which cases suit must be instituted where the land or a part thereof is situated.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this Act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>December 10th, 1863</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XVIII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act authorizing the County Courts to regulate the Pay of Sheriffs in certain cases.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the County Courts of the several counties composing the State of Texas, be and the same are herdby authorized to allow the Sheriffs thereof, for summoning jurors, in the District Courts, serving election notices, notices on overseeers of roads, and at<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tending on District and County Courts, and doing all other business not pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vided for, such sum or sums of money as such courts may deem sufficient for said service, not to exceed two hundred dollars per annum, to be paid out of the Treas<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ury of said County, any law to the contrary notwithstanding.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it enacted that all laws and parts of laws securing or attempting to secure to certain counties, the object embraced in section one, of this Act, be and the same are hereby repealed.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. Be it enacted, that this act take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>December 10th, 1863</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XIX.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to aid Enrolling Officers in the discharge of their official duties.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That whenever any Enrolling Officer of this State, or of the Confederate States of Amer<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ica, within this State, may be authorized or required to execute any order directed to him by proper authority, or in the lawful discharge of the duties of his office, to arrest any person having been drafted, or any person subject to conscription, or any deserter from the military service of this State or of the Confederate States, it shall be lawful for such officer, if he deem it necessary, to call on the Sheriff of the county in which such order is to be executed, or such person arrested, to aid him in the execution of such order, or in making such arrest, and should the Sheriff not be at the command of such Enrolling Officer, in consequence either of other pressing official business, or of absence, then it shall be lawful for such officer to call on any number of persons he may deem necessary to aid him in executing such order or making such arrest.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That whenever any Sheriff is called upon to render the aid contemplated in the first section of this Act, it shall be his duty to do so, and if required by such officer, shall call to his aid the power of the county; and any Sheriff failing or re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fusing to render such aid, or to call out the power of the county when so required, shall for any such failure or refusal, be fined not less than one hundred dollars, nor more than five hundred dollars, to be recovered on motion before the District Court of his county, by the District Attorney or Enrolling Officer, of which motion he shall have three days notice.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. Every person failing or refusing to render the assistance to the Sheriff or Enrolling Officer, required by the provisions of this Act, shall be deemed guilty of an offence, and on conviction thereof before any court of competent jurisdiction, be fined in a sum of not less than twenty-five dollars, nor more than two hundred and fifty dollars.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. That this Act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>December 11th, 1863</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
<pb n="666" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="12" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XX.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to amend the seventy-first section of &#8220;An Act to regulate proceedings in the County Courts, pertaining to Estates of deceased persons,&#8221; approved March 20th, 1848.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That from and after the passage of this act, the seventy-first section of &#8220;An Act to regu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />late proceedings in the County Courts, pertaining to estates of deceased persons,&#8221; ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />nroved March 20th, 1848, be amended so as hereafter to reau as follows, to wit:</p>
<p>Sec. 71. That whenever any property is rented or hired by an executor or ad<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ministrator, under the provisions of this act, such renting or hiring shall be made at public auction to the highest bidder, after having given at least ten days notice thereof, by posting a copy of such notice at the Court-house and at two other public places in the county where the same is to take place, or by private agreement, as the Chief Justice, either in vacation or term time, by order shall direct, which order shall be entered on the minutes of the Court.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That the provisions of the above section of this act shall apply as well to the renting or hiring of property by a guardian as by an executor or adminis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />trator: Provided, That an account in writing and under oath, of such renting or hiring, shall, in all cases, be returned to the Court and subject to the approval of the Chief Justice.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>December 14th, 1863</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to punish persons who may remove or destroy any Timber, Rails, or Lumber, belonging to the several Asylums of this State.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That from and after the passage of this act, it shall not be lawful for any person, or per<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sons, to take or remove any timber, rails, or lumber, from the grounds or premises of the Lunatic, Blind, or Deaf and Dumb Asylums of this State, or destroy the same; and if any person shall be guilty of a violation of the foregoing provisions of this act, he shall be punished by a fine not less than twenty-five, nor more than one hundred dollars, for each and every such violation, recoverable before a Justice of the Peace by summary proceeding, upon complaint of the Superintendent of such Asylum, or any other person; and said fines shall, when collected, be appropriated to the use of the Asylum upon which the depredation was committed.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>December 14th, 1863</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act supplementary to, and amendatory of, &#8220;An act to adopt and establish a Penal Code.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the following articles, in the chapters and titles named of the act above recited, commonly known as the &#8220;Penal Code,&#8221; be and they are hereby so amended that they shall hereafter read as follows, viz:</p>
<div4 type="section">
<head type="main">Part II.&#8212;Title VI.&#8212;Chapter 1.</head>
<p>Article 231. Treason against this State shall consist only in levying war against it, or adhering to its enemies, giving them aid and comfort.&#8212; [Constitution, Art. 7, Sec. 2.</p>
<p>Article 231. A. Whenever war is pending between the State of Texas and any other belligerent, or between the Confederate States and any other bel<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ligerent, while Texas is a member of the Confederacy, it is not necessary to prove any actual communication between the public enemy and any person <pb n="667" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="13" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw> charged with treason, to establish the offense of treason. Any act, the tendency of which is to give aid and comfort to the public enemy, committed with intent to aid his operations or defeat or interrupt those of this State, or the Confederate States, is an overt act within the meaning of the Constitution. The intent is to be determined by the declarations or other conduct of the party, taken in connection with the act.</p>
</div4>
<div4 type="section">
<head type="main">Chapter II.</head>
<p>Article 233. Whoever shall know that another person has committed treason against this State, or against the Confederate States, while this State is a member of the Confederacy, and shall not, within five days from the time of his having come to such knowledge, give information of the same to the Governor, or to some Judge of a Court of Record of this State:</p>
<p>Whoever shall intend, to commit treason against this State, or against the Con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />federate States, while this State is a member of the Confederacy; and</p>
<p>Whoever shall know that another person is intending to commit treason against this State, or against the Confederate States, while this State is a member of the Confederacy, and shall not, within five days from the time of his having come to such knowledge, give information of the same to the Governor, or to some Judge of a Court of Record of this State, shall be deemed guilty of misprision and treason: Provided, the husband or wife shall not be compelled to give information against each other, nor a mother against her child.</p>
<p>Article 233. A. The intention to commit treason, specified in the foregoing, is evidenced by any declaration made by the party of a purpose to do any act which would constitute treason, whether made orally or in writing, taken in connection with any conduct showing the purpose to be real.</p>
<p>Article 234. A. Any person who shall, while war is pending between the State of Texas and any other belligerent, or between the Confederate States and any other belligerent, Texas then being a member of the Confederacy, in any way advise another person to join the public enemy, or in any way aid or assist another person to join the public enemy;</p>
<p>Any person who shall publicly maintain, pending any war as aforesaid, that either himself or any other person, a citizen or inhabitant of this State, does not owe obedience or duty to this State, or that he does owe obedience or duty to the government of the public enemy.</p>
<p>Any prson who shall privately, or otherwise than publicly, maintain, pending any war as aforesaid, that any citizen or inhabitant of this State does not owe obedience or duty to this State, or that he does owe obedience or duty to the gov<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ernment of the public enemy, with the purpose to induce such citizen or inhabitant to avoid the performance of his duties as such; and</p>
<p>Any person, who shall, pending any war as aforesaid, write, print, or publish or cause to be written, printed, or published, or counsel, aid, advise, or assist, in writing, printing, or publishing, any letter, book, address, or other writing, main<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />taining the right or duty of any citizen or inhabitant of this State to give aid or comfort to the public enemy, or that any citizen or inhabitant owes obedience or duty to the government of the public enemy, shall be deemed guilty of encouraging treason, and shall suffer the same punishment as is herein provided for misprision</p>
</div4>
<div4 type="section">
<head type="main">Title XXI.&#8212;Chapter I.</head>
<p>Article 780. The agreement to come within the definition of conspiracy, must be to commit one or more of the following offenses: Treason, murder, robbery, arson, burglary, rape, or theft.</p>
<p>Article 781. Conspiracy to commit treason or murder shall be punished by confinement in the Penitentiary, not less than two nor more than ten years. Conspiracy to commit any of the other offenses named in the preceding article, shall be punished by one-half of the punishment affixed by law to the commission of the offense so intended by the parties; Provided, That in no case the punishment by confinement in the Penitentiary be less than two years.</p>
</div4>
<div4 type="section">
<head type="main">Chapter II.</head>
<p>Article 784. If any person shall threaten to commit treason, or to take the <pb n="668" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="14" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw> life of a human being, or to inflict upon any human being any serious bodily injury, he shall be punished by imprisonment in the Penitentiary, not less than two nor more than five years, or by fine not exceeding two thousand dollars.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>December 14th, 1863</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div4>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXIII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to authorize the Quartermaster of the State to dispose of a certain amount of the Percussion Caps manufactured at the State Works.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section I. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Quartermaster of the State be authorized to dispose of one-tenth of the percussion caps manufactured at the State Works, to private parties, at such prices and in such manner as he may deem proper.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That in disposing of the caps, he shall endeavor to distribute them to the citizens of the different sections of the State, as much as possible.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. The proceeds arising from the sale of the caps, shall be applied to the payment of expenses incurred in keeping up and sustaining the Cap Manufactory; and this act to take effect from its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>December 14th, 1863</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXIV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act supplementary to an act, entitled &#8220;An Act to Define the Duties of Secre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tary of State,&#8221; passed May the 9th, 1846.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Secretary of State, in addition to the Chief Clerk, shall be authorized to appoint an Assistant Clerk, with a salary of one thousand dollars per annum, who shall exercise the powers of Chief Clerk during his absence or vacancy in that office, and shall discharge such other duties as may be required of him by the Secretary of State.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. The Secretary of State shall be the custodian of the records of the Senate and House of Representatives, after the adjournment of the Legislature, and it shall be his duty to arrange and file, and preserve in his office all papers of any value, and furnish certified copies of them when demanded: Provided, That papers, not the evidence of private relief Granted, may be delivered to their owners.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. The Secretary shall have charge and supervision of the State Library, shall keep it accessible for the inspection and use of the public, and, when the Legislature is in session, one of the Clerks shall remain in the Library during all the time either House may be in session; but no person shall be permitted to take the books from the Library, except under such rules and regulations as the proper Board may make and establish.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. The Secretary shall procure for the two Houses, before the commence<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment of each session, the necessary stationery, fuel and lighting materials, and have the Capitol fitted up when the Legislature meets.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. This act shall be in force from and after its, passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>December 14, 1863</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to amend the fifty-eighth section of &#8220;An Act to regulate proceedings in the County Courts, pertaining to Estates of deceased persons.&#8221; approved March 20th, 1848.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the fifty-eighth section, of the above recited act, be so amended as to read as fol<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" /><pb n="669" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="15" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw> lows, to wit: All sales for the payment of the debts, owing by the estate, shall be ordered to be made of such property as may be deemed most advantageous to such estate to be sold.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this act take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>December 14th, 1863</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXVI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to amend &#8220;An Act to organize County Courts,&#8221; approved March 16th, 1848.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted, by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the twenty-first section of &#8220;An act to organize County Courts,&#8221; approved March 16th, 1848, be amended so as hereafter to read as follows: Sec. 21. That a regular term of the County Court shall commence and be held at the Court-house of each county in this State on the first Monday in January, April, July, and October, in every year, for the transaction of all business growing out of, or connected with the powers and jurisdiction of the County Court over all matters other than those named in the second and twentieth sections of this act; such terms shall be held by the Chief Justice, with the assistance of any two or more of the County Commis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sioners, and may continue for one week but not longer; and special terms of said Court may be held in like manner, and for like purposes as provided for in this sec<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion, at such other times as the Chief Justice may appoint: Provided, however. That no County Tax shall be levied, unless at some one of the regular terms, and with the assent of the Chief Justice and three of the County Commissioners, or the assent of the four Commissioners. Should a quorum of said County Court not ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pear at the time appointed for holding the same, the Sheriff of the County, or in his absence or in case of vacancy in that office, the Coroner shall adjourn the Court from day to day for three days, and should a quorum not appear on the morning of the fourth day, then he shall adjourn the Court until the next term in course.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>December 14th, 1863</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXVII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to suspend the Location, Survey and Sale of the Public Lands, except in certain cases.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That until six months after the close of the present war, all laws authorizing the location survey or sale of any of the public lands or land scrip, except in cases herein pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vided for, are hereby suspended.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. The suspension provided for in the preceding section, shall not be con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />strued to prevent the location, survey and sale of the public lands to actual set<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tlers, as now provided by law, nor to prevent the location, survey and patent of the University Lands, or the lands to which the several counties are entitled for the use of schools, nor shall it prevent the return of field notes and perfection of title to lands already surveyed.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. All holders of land scrip issued to railroad companies shall have the same time to locate, survey, return the field notes to and alienate the same, after the termination of the period of suspension, herein provided for, that they would have been entitled to from this time, had this law not have been enacted, and during the period of suspension, herein provided for, no location or survey shall be forfeited by reason of not returning the field notes to the same: Provided, that any one engaged in the manufacture of Tar, Pitch or Turpentine, shall not he precluded from locating upon any such pine lands as may be necessary for such manufacture: Provided, that the field notes be returned to the General hand Office within ninety days after the location is made; nor shall persons or cor<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" /><pb n="670" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="16" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw> porations entitled to land under the law granting lands to encourage manufactures be prevented from filing and locating upon any vacant land needed for such factories, upon making oath, that the lands so filed upon are needed. If filed on by a corporation, said oath shall be made by its manager.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. That during the time named in this Act, the Commissioner of the General Land Office shall keep such clerks and draughtsmen only as are or may be necessary to carry on the business of the office; and that this Act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>December 14th, 1863</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXVIII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act making an appropriation to pay deficits in appropriations heretofore made, and making appropriations for the payment and support of the Frontier Regi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the sum of eight hundred thousand dollars, in Confederate States Treasury Notes, or so much thereof as may be necessary, be and the same is hereby appropriated to pay deficits in appropriations heretofore made for the pay and support of the &#8220;Mounted Regiment of Texas State Troops, &#8220;commanded by Col. James E. McCord: and for the pay and support of said Regiment until otherwise provided for.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>December 14th, 1863</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXIX.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act providing for the auditing and settling of the claims of the State of Texas for Frontier Defense against the Confederate States.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Governor of the State is hereby authorized to take such proceedings as he may deem most advisable, to have audited and settled the claims of the State of Texas against the Confederate States, for money expended by the State of Texas in de<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fense of the Frontier of Texas, and that the sum of three thousand dollars, or so much thereof as may be necessary, is hereby appropriated, to enable the Governor to carry into effect the intention of this Act.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>December 14th, 1863</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXX.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to provide for the assessment and collection of Income Taxes on Sales of distilled Spirits, Fermented Liquors and Wines, and for such purpose to define and regulate such sales.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, as follows:&#8212; Any person, firm or Association, having in this State any distilled spirit, fermented liquor or wine, and therein selling the same, by wholesale, for money, or so barter<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing the same for any other article, shall pay an income tax as follows:</p>
<p>For the aggregate amount so sold or bartered within each calendar month, for any value not exceeding two dollars per gallon, the tax on such value shall be at the rate of five cents per gallon.</p>
<p>For the aggregate amount so sold or bartered within each calendar month, for more than the preceding rate of value and not for more than three dollars per gallon, the tax on such value shall be at the rate of fifteen cents per gallon.</p>
<p>For the aggregate amount so sold or bartered within each calendar month, for more than the last rate of value and not for more than four dollars per gallon, the tax on such value shall be at the rate of one dollar per gallon.</p>
<pb n="671" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="17" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<p>For the aggregate amount so sold or bartered within each calendar month, for more than the last rate of value and not for more than five dollars per gallon, the tax on such value shall be at the rate of one dollar and fifty cents per gallon.</p>
<p>For the aggregate amount so sold or bartered within each calendar month, for more than the last rate of value and not for more than six dollars per gallon, the tax on such value shall be at the rate of two dollars and seventy cents per gallon.</p>
<p>For the aggregate amount so sold or bartered within each calendar month, for more than the last rate of value and not for more than seven dollars per gallon, the tax on such value shall be at the rate of three dollars and fifty-five cents per gallon.</p>
<p>For the aggregate amount so sold or bartered within each calendar month, for more than the last rate of value and not for more than eight dollars per gallon, the tax on such value shall be at the rate of four dollars and forty cents per gallon.</p>
<p>For the aggregate amount so sold or bartered within each calendar month, for more than the last rate of value and not for more than nine dollars per gallon, the tax on such value shall be at the rate of five dollars and twenty-five cents per gallon.</p>
<p>For the aggregate amount so sold or bartered within each calendar month, for more than the last rate of value and not for more than ten dollars per gallon, the tax on such value shall be at the rate of six dollars and ten cents per gallon.</p>
<p>For the aggregate amount so sold or bartered within each calendar month, for more than the last rate of value and not more than eleven dollars per gallon, the tax on such value shall be at the rate of six dollars and ninety-five cents per gallon.</p>
<p>For the aggregate amount so sold or bartered within each calendar month, for more than the last rate of value and for not more than twelve dollars per gallon, the tax on such value shall be at the rate of seven dollars and eighty cents per gallon.</p>
<p>For the aggregate amount so sold or bartered within each calendar month, for more than the last rate of value and not for more than thirteen dollars per gallon, the tax on such value shall be at the rate of eight dollars and sixty-five cents per gallon.</p>
<p>For the aggregate amount so sold or bartered within each calendar month, for more than the last rate of value and not for more than fourteen dollars per gallon, the tax on such value shall be at the rate of nine dollars and fifty cents per gallon.</p>
<p>For the aggregate amount so sold or bartered within each calendar month, for more than the last rate of value, and not for more than fifteen dollars per gallon, the tax on such value shall be at the rate of ten dollars and thirty-five cents per gallon.</p>
<p>For the aggregate amount so sold or bartered within each calendar month, for more than the last rate Of mine and not for more than sixteen dollars per gallon, the tax on such value shall be at the rate of eleven dollars and twenty cents per gallon.</p>
<p>For the aggregate amount so sold or bartered within each calendar month, for more than the last rate of value and not for more than seventeen dollars per gal<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lon, the tax on such value shall be at the rate of twelve dollars and five cents per gallon.</p>
<p>For the aggregate amount so sold or bartered within each calendar month, for more than the last rate of value and not for more than eighteen dollars per gallon, the tax on such value shall be at the rate of twelve dollars&#8217; and ninety cents per gallon.</p>
<p>For the aggregate amount so sold or bartered within each calendar month, for more than the last rate of value and not for more than nineteen dollars per gallon, the tax on such value shall be at the rate of thirteen dollars and seventy-five cents per gallon.</p>
<p>For the aggregate amount so sold or bartered within each calendar month, for more than the last rate of value and not for more than twenty dollars per gal<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" /><pb n="672" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="18" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw> Ion, the tax on such value shall be at the rate of fourteen dollars and sixty cents per gallon.</p>
<p>For the aggregate amount so sold or bartered within each calendar month, for more than the last rate of value and not for more than twenty-one dollars per gal<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lon, the tax on such value shall be at the rate of fifteen dollars and forty-five cents per gallon.</p>
<p>For the aggregate amount so sold or bartered within each calendar month, for more than the last rate of value and not for more than twenty-two dollars per gal<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lon, the tax on such value shall be at the rate of sixteen dollars and thirty cents per gallon.</p>
<p>For the aggregate amount so sold or bartered within each calendar month, for more than the last rate of value and not for more than twenty-three dollars per gal<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lon, the tax on such value shall be at the rate of seventeen dollars and fifteen cents per gallon.</p>
<p>For the aggregate amount so sold or bartered within each calendar month, for more than the last rate of value and not for more than twenty-four dollars per gal<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lon, the tax on such value shall be at the rate of eighteen dollars per gallon.</p>
<p>For the aggregate amount so sold or bartered within each calendar month, for more than the last rate of value and not for more than twenty-five dollars per gal<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lon, the tax on such value shall be at the rate of eighteen dollars and eighty-five cents per gallon.</p>
<p>For the aggregate amount so sold or bartered within each calendar month, at any rate higher than the value of twenty-five dollars per gallon, the tax shall be at the rate of seventy-six per centum on the amount of such sale.</p>
<p>But, sales of wine, made within this State, are exceptions and shall not be subject to such taxes.</p>
<p>Such selling or bartering, in the sense of this law, is, by wholesale, when done without special license for retailing.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Any person, firm or association, having in this State any distilled spirit, fermented liquor, or wine, and therein selling the same, by retail, for money, or so bartering the same for any other article, shall pay an income tax as follows:</p>
<p>On the value of the aggregate amount so sold or bartered within each calendar month, at any rate not exceeding the rate of five dollars per gallon, the tax shall be at the rate of five per centum.</p>
<p>On the value of the aggregate amount so sold or bartered within each calendar month, at any rate higher than the preceding and not higher than the rate of ten dollars per gallon, the tax shall be at the rate of ten per centum.</p>
<p>On the value of the aggregate amount so sold or bartered within each calendar month, at any rate higher than the rate of ten dollars per gallon, the tax shall be at the rate of fifty per centum.</p>
<p>But, sales of wines made within this State are exceptions and shall not be subject to such taxes.</p>
<p>Such selling or gartering, in the sense of this law, is by retail when done with special license for retailing.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. When any person, firm, or association, having any article, subject to such taxes, as owner at the present time by any means, or as first owner at any subse<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />quent time, either from importation into the State or from production within it, shall furnish such article for retailing, such disposal thereof shall be a sale, by wholesale, under this law. This shall be the construction: If the person, firm, or association be partly or entirely enterested in the retailing, as if it were done by any disconnected person; and a trust or donation for the purpose of retailing shall receive the same kind of construing. Neither kind of tax shall be evaded by any blending of wholesale and retail interests, nor by any arrangement of trust or gift; and every person making such respective disposal of any such article, shall dis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tinctly and separately account therefor, as in case of an ordinary sale; and tax shall be paid, in every case, on fair market value.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. The Treasury Notes of the Confederate States of America being in <pb n="673" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="19" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw> general use as the circulating medium of exchanges, and as the common current standard of values, and the taxes imposed by this Act being receivable in such cur<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />rency, it shall be the standard of values of the articles sold or bartered, as afore<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />said, including the articles received in exchange, without regard for any different estimate, that may be made for the purpose of evading the provisions of this law or for any other reason.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. The sale of any distilled spirit, fermented liquor, or wine of bad quality is absolutely prohibited; and any such article shall be so regarded when adulterated or tinctured with any poisonous or unhealthful substance, or when its strength shall be under second proof as known in market, or as may be otherwise ascertained. In each county the County Court shall establish proper tests for ascertaining the quality of such articles, and shall have authority to apply the test in any reason<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />able manner. Also, the Assessor and Collector shall have authority, in any proper manner, to ascertain the qualities of such articles, either by applying the tests, that may be established by the Court, if any, or by the use of other appropriate means. But sales of wine made within this State and not adulterated nor tinctured with any poisonous or unhealthful substance, although in strength below second proof, shall not be within the foregoing prohibition.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. The taxes imposed by this law shall apply to sales to be made out of this State, of such articles taken from it for market, as well as to sales made within this State; and the person, firm, or association, who shall make any preparation or movement of such an article in commencing so to take it from this State for market, or who shall make any committal of such an article to any person, that he may take it from the State for market, shall pay this tax, which shall be assessed and collected promptly, on the value of the subject of such preparation, movement, or committal, on an estimate of such value, to be made by the Assessor and Collector according to the current market value of the article in his county, as if sale had been therein completed at such value.</p>
<p>Sec. 7. Within the first ten days of every month, each person, firm, or association, liable for such taxes, shall render to the Assessor and Collector of the county, where sales shall have been made, or from which articles have been taken for market, or in which preparation, movement, or committal shall have been made, as aforesaid, a true account of the articles so sold, or taken from this State for market, or pre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pared, moved, or committed therefor, during the next preceding month. Such ac<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />count, as to wholesale tarnsactions, shall show, respectively, dates of sale, to whom sold, kinds and quantities sold, and prices per gallon, or like particulars, as far as practicable, in relation to articles taken from this State for market, or prepared, moved, or committed therefor. Such account, as to retail transactions, shall show like particulars, except to whom sold. And, at any other time, on demand of the Assessor and Collector, any person, firm, or association, so liable to render an ac<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />count, shall do so within two days from such demand. Also, any person, firm, or association, so liable, shall show to the Assessor and Collector, on his demand, to be made in a reasonable manner, an account book or other memorandum, respectively of each foregoing particular. Every account, account-book, or memorandum, to be rendered or shown, as aforesaid, in order to meet the requisition therefor, must be verified by some person liable therefor; and such verification must show, that the account, account-book, or memorandum, respectively, contain a fully just, and true exhibition of the facts, required to be shown by such means. Such verification must be made by written affidavit, stating particulars according to the nature of the case, subscribed by the person making it, sworn to before some officer authorized to administer oaths, including the Assessor and Collector, and delivered to him. Every such affidavit shall be filed in the office of the Clerk of the County Court.</p>
<p>Sec. 8. If any such affidavit shall be wilfully false, the person making it shall be guilty of perjury, and shall be subject to punishment as in other cases of perjury. Moreover, if any person shall violate any of the other provisions of this law, he shall be guilty of a misdemeanor, indictable in the District Court; <pb n="674" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="20" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw> and, on conviction, he shall be punished by fine not exceeding five thousand dollars, or by imprisonment, not exceeding six months, or in both modes, in the discretion of the jury trying the case; and each person included in a firm or association, so violating these other provisions, shall be liable to these penalties.</p>
<p>Sec. 9. Any person, firm, or association, at the end of each month, shall be liable for payment of the taxes, which shall have accrued against him or them in that month, and shall pay the same to the Assessor and Collector within the first ten days after the end of the month; and, in case the Assessor and Collector at any time shall demand an account, as before provided, he shall then demand pay<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment of the taxes, that shall have previously accrued, without reference to monthly time, and they shall be paid within two days allowed, for rendering the account so demanded. Any person, who shall have become liable for any of such taxes, shall so continue until payment, notwithstanding any punishment that may be inflicted under this law. The Assessor and Collector of the county wherein the taxes shall have accrued, shall collect the, same, and may sue therefor in the name of the State, if necessary; and, in any such case of suit the defendant or defendants, shall be liable to judgment and execution for the taxes, and for the amount of fifty per cen<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tum thereon. Whenever such suit shall be necessary, it shall be prosecuted to judg<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment and execution without delay, notwithstanding any law for suspending the col<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lection of ordinary debts.</p>
<p>Sec. 10. The subjects of taxation under this law shall not be liable to taxation by any other county, city or town.</p>
<p>Sec. 11. All laws contrary to the provisions of this act are suspended during its continuance in force; and this act shall be in force from its passage until the close of the present war and the ratification of a treaty of peace between the Confederate States of America and the United States of America.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>December 15th, 1863</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXXI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to amend &#8220;An Act to define and punish Sedition and to prevent the dangers which may arise from persons disaffected to the State.&#8221;</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State Texas, That the caption of the above recited act shall hereafter read as follows: &#8220;An Act to punish persons who are disaffected to the State:&#8221; that the act itself shall be so amended as to hereafter to read as follows: That if any person shall willfully advise or persuade any person, liable to perform military duty, to refuse or evade the per<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />formance of legal military service of this State, or of the Confederate States, or shall attempt in any manner to influence the decision, or bias the opinion, of any person in favor of the enemies of the Confederate States or of this State, he shall be pun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ished by imprisonment in the Penitentiary, not less than three nor more than five years.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. This act shall take effect and be in force from its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>December 15th, 1863</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXXII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to define and punish the crime of Disloyalty to the State of Texas.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That if any person within this State shall, by any means, wilfully attempt to dissuade or discourage the people from performing their duty in the military or naval service of the Confederate States or of this State, or shall aid, advise or induce any soldier, seaman or marine, in said service, to desert therefrom, or shall <pb n="675" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="21" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw> harbor any such deserter, or shall by means of any verbal, written, or printed statement, attempt to create disaffection among the people towards this State or the Confederate States, or influence them to aid, assist or adhere to the public enemy, in any manner whatever, shall be punished by confinement in the Peni<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tentiary, for not less than two nor more than five years.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That if any person within this State shall wilfully communicate to the public enemy any information in regard to the disposition, strength or movements of the army, or the designs of the military authorities, or shall aid or abet any one so doing, he shall be deemed guilty of disloyalty, and, on conviction thereof,&#8221; shall be punished by confinement in the Penitentiary, for not less than three nor more than five years.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That this act be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>December 15th, 1863</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXXIII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act appropriating two hundred thousand dollars as a Hospital Fund for the Soldiers of Texas in the armies of the Confederate States of America, and to re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />peal other laws, as named in this Act on the same subject.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted, by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the sum of two hundred thousand dollars is appropriated as a Hospital Fund, to be administered as the Governor may deem necessary, according to the provisions of an act approved January 8th, 1862, entitled &#8220;An act to create a Hospital Fund, to be expended for the comfort of the sick and wounded soldiers of the State of Texas in the Confederate army.&#8221;</p>
<p>Sec. 2, So much of said act, approved January 8th, 1862, as made an appropria<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion, is repealed, and likewise &#8220;An act appropriating two hundred thousand dollars, to be expended for the relief of the sick and wounded soldiers of the State of Texas in the army of the Confederate States.&#8221; approved March 5th, 1863, is repealed.</p>
<p>Sec: 3. This act shall be in force from its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>December 15th, 1863</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXXIV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to provide for the Support of the Families and Dependents of Texas Soldiers.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That for the years 1864 and 1865, or during the continuance of the present war, should the same end before the first day of January, 1865, the sum of one million of dol<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lars per annum, be and the same is hereby appropriated for the support and main<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tenance of the families, widows and dependents of such officers and soldiers of Texas as have been, may now, or hereafter may be, in the military service of the Confed<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />erate States, or in the active militia or volunteer service of the State of Texas, and which families, widows or dependents may need the assistance and support of the State.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. The money hereby appropriated shall be distributed by the Comptroller of the State, under such regulations as he shall adopt, consistent with this act, to the several counties of this State, according to the number of the indigent in each, as ascertained in the manner herein required.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. It shall be the duty of the Comptroller of the State, immediately after the passage of this act, to forward to the Chief Justice of each county in the State a copy of this act, with such instructions and forms as may be necessary to carry its provisions into effect; and said Chief Justices shall, immediately upon the receipt of the same, ascertain or cause to be ascertained, in such manner as they may deem best, the number of indigent persons in their re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />spective counties entitled to relief under this act, and shall make an accurate return <pb n="676" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="22" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw> of the same to the Comptrollers office, on or before the first day of March, 1864, and a like return shall be made by them on or before the first day of March, 1865.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. Upon the first day of March, 1864, the Comptroller shall distribute to the several counties in this State one-half of the first annual appropriation herein made, according to the returns herein required, and on the first of September fol<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lowing shall, in like manner, distribute the remaining half of said appropriation; and the distribution shall be made on the first of March and September, in the same manner, for the year 1865, on the basis of the returns required by this act: Pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vided, That in cases where the returns have not been received by the Comptroller, the distribution shall be made upon such equitable basis as the Comptroller may determine; and the Comptroller is hereby authorized to draw his draft on the Assessors and Collectors of the respective counties entitled to such relief, in favor of the Chief Justices of said counties for the amount due said county; and the money so received shall be expended by the County Court as directed by this act.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. The County Courts of the respective counties shall administer the funds, hereby appropriated, in the manner deemed by them best suited to accomplish the objects of this act: Provided, no portion of said funds shall be used for any purpose except in the purchase of necessary supplies or in liquidation of proper demands for such supplies, or other appropriate relief, furnished or contracted to be furnished at a stipulated and reasonable price; and, provided further, that no per centage shall be allowed to any officer or agent employed in the administration of said fund.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. Any Chief Justice who shall negligently or corruptly make a false return of the number of indigent persons in his county, as contemplated by the third sec<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion of this act, shall be deemed guilty of a misdemeanor, and, on conviction before any Court having jurisdiction, shall be fined in any sum not less than five hundred dollars, and shall be dismissed from office.</p>
<p>Sec. 7. That this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>December 15th, 1863</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXXV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to encourage the Erection of certain Machinery by donations of Land and otherwise.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That any per<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />son, company, or corporation, desiring to avail themselves of the benefits of this act, shall erect and put into successful operation by the first day of March, A. D. 1865, new and efficient machinery for the manufacture of iron from ore, or for the manufacture of cotton or wool into thread or cloth, or for the manufacture of fire arms, nitre, sulphur, powder, salt, cotton or woolen cards and spinning jennies, or paper and oil.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That upon being notified of the erection and completion of any machinery of the kind described in the foregoing section, and upon being satisfied that said machinery was erected and put into operation within the time prescribed in the first section of this act, it shall be the duty of the Governor and owner or owners of said machinery, to appoint, each, one disinterested person to act as commission<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ers, who shall appoint a third commissioner to act with them in the valuation of said machinery; said commissioners shall, before making said valuation, take and subscribe the following oath. &#8220;I, A. B., do solemnly swear that I am not interested in the machinery erected by &#8212; &#8212; and situated in &#8212;. nor am I related to any person who is so interested, either by affinity or consanguinity, and that I will make a correct and impartial valuation of the same, to the best of my ability: so help me God:&#8221; which, together with their valuation, shall be returned to the Gen<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />eral Land Office.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. That it shall be the duty of the said commissioners, after making a minute personal examination of said machinery and after procuring such other evidence of its value as may be accessible to them, to value the same at its <pb n="677" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="23" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw> true value in specie. In said valuation, the necessary buildings and structures erected for the efficient operation of said machinery, shall be included, but the land upon which they are situated shall not be valued.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. Any person, company, or corporation, hereafter erecting and putting into efficient operation by the first day of March, A. D. 1865, any machinery of the char<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />acter described in the preceding sections of this act, shall be entitled to receive from the State a grant at the rates of one section of three hundred and twenty acres of land for every one thousand dollars worth of machinery so erected and put into efficient operation.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. That any person, company, or corporation, erecting and putting into efficient operation machinery of the character described in the first section of this act, and filing with the Commissioner of the General Land Office the affidavit and valuation provided for in the second section of this act, may file an application with any District Surveyor of any Land District in the State, a copy of which application shall in all cases be forwarded to the Commissioner of the General Land Office by the District Surveyor, to survey a quantity of land equal to double the amount which they may be entitled to receive under this act, lying and being in such dis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />trict and subject to location and entry; and said application shall specifically de<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />scribe the lands applied for and intended to be surveyed, and if said person, com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pany, or corporation, shall file with the District Surveyor a certificate of the Com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />missioner of the General Land Office that the affidavit and valuation, provided for in the fourth section of this act, have been filed in his office; said application shall exempt the land so designated from any future location, entry, or pre-emption privi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lege.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. It stall be the duty of said person, company, or corporation, to cause to be surveyed the land so designated in sections of three hundred and twenty acres each, unless prevented by previous surveys or a navigable stream, which surveys shall be delineated upon a map or maps, the even and odd sections being differently colored and regularly numbered, from one upwards to the full number surveyed for any person, company, or corporation; and the field notes of said surveys, and map or maps, shall be by said company deposited with the Commissioner of the Gen<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />eral Land Office.</p>
<p>Sec. 7. Fractional sections containing more than three hundred and twenty acres of land, shall be regarded as whole sections, and two fractional sections, each con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />taining less than three hundred and twenty acres, shall be taken as a whole sec<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion, and all the alternate or even sections shall be reserved to the use of the State until appropriated by law; and surveys, under the provisions of this act, shall be made by the Deputies and District Surveyors of the district in which the land is situated, and the field notes shall be recorded in such district and returned to the General Land Office as other surveys; that the provisions of this bill shall apply to all works, for the purpose indicated in this bill, commenced since the second day of March, 1861.</p>
<p>Sec. 8. That this act be in force and effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>December 15th, 1863</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXXVI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to Provide for the Protection of the Frontier, and turning over the Fron<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tier Regiment to Confederate States Service.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That all per<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sons liable to do military duty, who are at the passage of this act bona fide citizens of the following line of counties, and all counties lying north and west of said line, to-wit: Cook, Wise, Barker, that part of Johnson west of the Belknap and Fort Graham road, Bosque, Coryell, Lampasas, Burnett, Blanco, Bandera, Medina, Ken<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dall, Atascosa, Live Oak, McMullen, La Salle, Dimmit, and Maverick, shall be en<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />rolled and organized into companies, not less than twenty-five nor more than sixty<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />five men, rank and file.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That it shall be the duty of the Governor, immediately after the <pb n="678" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="24" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw> passage of this act, to cause the counties designated in the preceding section to be divided into three districts, as nearly equal in territory and population as may be; in each of which districts he shall appoint a suitable person, with the rank and pay of Major of Cavalry, who shall be the ranking officer of the district to which he is appointed, and which officer shall be charged with the organization of the men subject to duty in his district, and with the control of the companies when organ<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ized, and the defense of the same, as provided herein, and under such other regu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lations as the Governor may prescribe.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That the commissioned officers of each company, of fifty men or more, shall consist of one Captain and two Lieutenants; if less than fifty men, two Lieu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tenants. The non-commissioned officers shall consist of one Sergeant and one Cor<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />poral for every ten men.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. That each member of a company shall be required to keep himself fur<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />nished with a suitable horse, gun, and ten days provisions, and all necessary equip<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ments, [including ammunition.]</p>
<p>Sec. 5. That no person who is not an actual resident, in good faith, of the fron<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tier district herein specified at the passage of this act, shall be a member of the or<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ganization provided for by this act; and it shall be the duty of captains of com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />panies, and of the commanding officers of the several districts, to exclude non<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />residents of the frontier district from membership in said organization, and, in case of doubt, strict and full proof under oath shall be required, to the satisfaction of the officer.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. That the companies organized under the provisions of this act, shall be required to keep at least one-fourth of their number in the field in actual service, making equal divisions of time; and the officers commanding districts shall have the power and authority to order out the whole force under such restrictions, regu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lations and requirements as the Governor may devise for the control and manage<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment of the organization herein provided for.</p>
<p>Sec. 7. That every officer and private of each of said companies shall, before en<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tering upon duty, be required to take an oath before some one authorized by law to administer oaths, that he will use his best endeavors to arrest, and deliver to the nearest Confederate State authorities, every person reported or known to him to be a deserter, either from the State or Confederate States army, and also all per<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sons from the interior counties who are avoiding conscription or draft service.</p>
<p>Sec. 8. That the pay of officers and privates, while engaged in actual service as provided in the sixth section of this act, shall be as follows, to-wit: Captains, three dollars per day; lieutenants, two dollars and seventy-five cents per day; sergeants, two dollars and fifty cents per day; corporals, two dollars and twenty-five cents per day, and privates, two dollars per day; and no other pay or allowances shall be made to officers or privates than the per diem as above provided</p>
<p>Sec. 9. That any officer or private wilfully failing or refusing to perform his duty, or guilty of any other offense, shall be reported by one of the commissioned officers of his company to the district officer, whose duty it shall be to order the sitting of a Court Martial, to consist of not less than three nor more than five com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />missioned officers, who shall proceed to hear the evidence, and shall acquit or con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vict, as the merits of the case may demand; and, in case of conviction, the Court may assess such punishment as is prescribed by the rules, regulations, and articles of war, for the army of the Confederate States: Provided, if any person convicted of a minor offense be of conscript age, he may, at the discretion of the Court, be de<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />livered to the nearest officer of the Confederate States for service on the army of the Confederate States.</p>
<p>Sec. 10. That it shall be the duty of the Governor to appoint such person or per<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sons, as he may choose, to draw from the proper authorities of the State the fund appropriated for the pay of the men organized under this act. Such person or per<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sons, so appointed, to give bond or security for the faithful performance of the duties required of them. The payments to be made to the men as often as once in every four months.</p>
<pb n="679" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="25" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<p>Sec. 11. That it shall be the duty of the Adjutant General to furnish the com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />panies organized under this act, with the necessary amount of ammunition, upon proper requisitions made by the commanders of the several districts.</p>
<p>Sec. 12. That the Governor shall, upon the completion of the foregoing organi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />zation, turn over the Frontier Regiment, with all its equipments, to the Confederate States service: Provided, the Confederate Commander will account to the State for all property so turned over at its proper value; otherwise the the Governor shall make such disposition of said property as shall best subserve the interest of the State; any law conflicting with this provision be and the same is hereby repealed.</p>
<p>Sec. 13. That the Governor shall cause to be made such other regulations, for the government and control of the organizations herein provided for, as he may deem necessary, to the end that the force so provided shall be made as effectual as possible to defend the frontier; and should Confederate troops be kept on the fron<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tier, and, in the event that the enemy should invade any portion of the State near the frontier, the Governor shall have the power to order the commanders of such districts, as may be contiguous to the scene of danger, to take the whole or part of their respective forces and participate in repelling the enemy; but in no event are such forces to be kept away from their own proper field of operations for a longer time than one month, unless such forces are used against an Indian enemy.</p>
<p>Sec. 14. That this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>December 15th, 1863</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXXVII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act supplemental to and to amend the first and fourth sections of an act en<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />titled &#8220;An Act appropriating sixteen thousand dollars, or so much thereof as may be necessary, for the recovering, or repairing the roofs on the Capitol, the Gen<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />eral Land Office, the Old Land Office, and the Treasury buildings,&#8221; approved March 6th, 1863.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the first and fourth sections of the act before recited, be so amended as to read as follows:</p>
<p>&#8220;Section 1. That the sum of $16,000, in addition to the amount heretofore ex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pended, or so much thereof as may be necessary, be and the same is hereby appro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />priated, to pay for recovering, or repairing the roofs of the Capitol, the General &#8220;Land Office, the Old Land Office, and the Treasury buildings.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;Section 4. The work may be let out in one or more contracts; and the said &#8220;commissioners may advance upon said contract or contracts as the work pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />presses, money to the amount of three-fourths of the price agreed upon to be paid &#8220;for said work, and no more, until the work, or each separate job of work, be com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pleted, and if after an examination the said commissioners shall find such work &#8220;well done, then the remaining one-fourth of the price agreed upon shall be paid.&#8221;</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That the Military Board be authorized, and required, to procure and de<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />liver to the said Board of Commissioners, the necessary tin or copper for gutters, and the nails to complete said work, and for the procuring of said tin or copper, and nails, said Board may use any funds under their control, not otherwise appro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />priated.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That this act be in force from its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>December 15th, 1863</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXXVIII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act for the relief of owners of lands sold for Taxes and bought by the State.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas. That the time for the redemption of lands heretofore sold for taxes and bought by the <pb n="680" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="26" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw> State, be further extended to the first day of January, 1866: Provided, that the owners of land so sold, shall pay, before that date, to the Assessor and Collector of the county wherein the sale was made, or to the Comptroller of the State, double the amount of the taxes for which the sale was made, and also all the taxes since due to the State and county on said lands, and the cost attending such sale.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted that this act take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>December 15th, 1863</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">XXXIX.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to Reorganize the Military Board of the State of Texas.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That there is hereby created a Military Board of the State of Texas, to be composed of three members: the Governor of the State, who shall be ex officio President of the Board, and two other members, who shall be appointed by the Governor. The members appointed by the Governor shall be liable to be removed by him, whenever, in his judgment, the public interest may require it; they shall reside at the seat of Government, and shall receive an annual salary of twenty-two hundred and fifty dollars each; and before they enter upon the duties of their office, they shall take and subscribe the oath of office prescribed by the Constitution, and shall each give bond, with good and sufficient sureties, in the sum of twenty-five thousand dollars, payable to the State of Texas, conditioned that they will well and faithfully perform the duties of their office; which bond shall be approved by the Governor, and, together with their oaths of office, shall be filed in the office of the Secretary of State.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. As soon as the Military Board, created by this act, shall be organized it shall succeed to the duties of the existing Military Board, and shall take charge of all its unfinished business; and the powers of this Board shall be as those hereto<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fore conferred on the Military Board, and shall be extended to the control of all public works and supplies, and to the aid of producing, within the State, by the importation of articles necessary and proper for such aid.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. The Board shall procure regular books to be kept, showing all their transactions, and shall open an account with the Comptroller and Treasurer, which shall show the general progress of their business, and at the expiration of every six months, shall file an account of their transactions, accompanied with vouchers for money paid out; the money received for articles sold by the Board, or for work done, shall be placed in the Treasury, subject to the orders of the Board for future operations, unless the Board shall order the same to be placed to the account of the general revenue.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. In carrying out the purposes of this act, the Board shall have power to employ two clerks, whose salaries shall not exceed fourteen hundred dollars each, and such other agents and employees as they may find necessary, allowing them reasonable compensation for their services.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. That this act take effect, and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>December 16th, 1863</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XL.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act supplementary to and amendatory of &#8220;An Act to suspend all laws for the collection of debts and liabilities on bonds, promissory notes, bills of exchange and contracts for the payment of money, until twelve months after the ratifica<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion of a treaty of peace, between the Confederate States of America and the United States of America, or until otherwise provided by law,&#8221; approved Dec. 2d, 1863.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the first section of the above recited act shall be so amended as hereafter to read as follows: That until twelve months after the ratification of a treaty of peace between the Confederate States of America and the United States of <pb n="681" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="27" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw> America, or until otherwise provided by law, all laws for the collection of debts and liabilities on bonds, promissory notes, bills of exchange and contracts for the payment of money, except in cases of persons who abandon the country; liabilities on the part of public officers; liabilities and indebtedness to the State, and also when money has been received on deposit or in trust for those who may be entitled to the same, and for the collection of the interest on the money loaned at interest, by guardians, belonging to their wards, are hereby suspended. Provided, That this act shall not be construed to forbid the issuance of writs of attachment, seques<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tration, or injunction, nor the institution of necessary preliminary proceedings for that purpose, in accordance with existing laws, and provided further, that this act shall not apply to any claim or demand against alien enemies; and provided fur<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ther, that this act shall not be so construed as to interfere with the action of the Su<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />preme Court in deciding all cases, as now directed by law.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>December 16th, 1863</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XLI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to provide for special terms of District Courts, and to extend the powers of the Judges thereof, in certain cases.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That when any person shall be legally charged with the commission of a high crime, the Judge of the District Court having jurisdiction of the case, may call a special term of the proper court, at any time, for the trial of the case; and he may cause grand and petit jurors to be summoned in the usual mode, to attend the court, except that the drawing for the jurors may be only fifteen days before the commencement of the term; and he may cause the accused person to be brought before the court at such term, whether imprisoned or bound for appearance at a regular term; and such obligation shall be discharged by appearance and trial of the accused at the special term; and the Judge may, in all other respects, proceed in such special busi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ness, at such special term, as he might do at a regular term of the court. The order for the special term and for the jurors therefor, shall be entered as part of the min<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />utes of proceedings of the term at the commencement thereof; and the rights of the State and of any person, interested in the proceedings of the court at such term, shall be the same that they would be in the like case at a regular term.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. The several Judges of the District Courts, are hereby authorized and em<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />powered, in all oases of injunction, to hear and determine motions to dissolve the same, without determining the merits, in vacation as well as at a regular term, after answer filed, upon ten days notice of the time and place of hearing said mo<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion, being given to the opposite party or his attorney; and by proper order have the proceedings placed upon the minutes of the appropriate court, and the said Judges shall have power to punish any and all persons for disobeying a writ of in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />junction, or other legal process, by fine, or imprisonment, or by both punishments, to such an extent as will enforce obedience thereto, by order made within the term time or vacation.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. This Act shall be in force from its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>December 16th, 1863</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XLII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to provide for ascertaining conflicts in Surveys and County Boundaries, to prevent such, conflicts from being hereafter created, and to provide for patenting surveys in such cases.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That for the purpose of ascertaining conflicts in, and making proper connections of surveys and county boundaries, in cases where from discrepancies and imperfections of <pb n="682" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="28" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw> field notes, it becomes necessary, for the proper compilation of maps and issuing of patents, the Commissioner of the General Land Office shall be authorized to order such surveys to be made as he may deem necessary, and to employ a competent surveyor for said purpose. All such surveys shall be made under the directions, and according to the instructions, of the Commissioner of the General Land Of<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fice, and proper field notes of the same shall be recorded in the counties or districts affected thereby, and returned to the General Land Office, with the accounts of the surveyor for making the same, which accounts shall be audited by the Commis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sioner of the General Land Office, and be paid by the Treasurer of the State upon his certificate.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Before any county in this State, not already regularly organized as a land district, under existing law, shall be recognized as such, the county court shall cause the boundary lines of the county to be run out, plainly marked, and duly connected according to law, and the field notes of the same, duly recorded, to be forwarded to the General Land Office, and shall also file in said office, in such man<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ner and form as the Commissioner thereof shall require, satisfactory evidence that all the requisitions of the law have been complied with, and no surveyor of any such county shall be authorized to survey any public land therein, until a certifi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cate from the Commissioner of the General Land Office, has been recorded in his office, certifying that said county is authorized, under the law, to have a separate survevor&#8217;s office.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. If from mutilation or deficiency of records, or other causes, it be found impracticable to procure the requisite maps and transcripts of records, in the man<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ner heretofore required by law, it shall be competent to procure the same from the General Land Office, and when so procured and certified, they shall be held and deemed to have the same force and effect, as the original records. Every such transcript shall be made in a well bound book, and shall be paid for by the county as now required by law, and for the purpose of making the same, the Commis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sioner shall be authorized to employ such additional clerks as may be necessary at any time, provided that no charge shall thereby be made to the State.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. Whenever, upon making proper connections of surveys, and establishing proper connections of counties, it shall appear that any survey which has been, or may bereafter be made, is entirely without the limits of the county or district in which the same purports to have been made, it shall be the duty of the Commis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sioner of the General Land Office, to cause the field notes or a certified copy of the same, to be recorded in the county or district in which the same is situated; pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vided the survey does not conflict with any previous location or survey made in the proper county, and every such survey shall be patented, and shall be as valid as though made originally in the proper county.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. The provisions of the first section of this act shall be deemed to extend to all necessary resurveys of University Lands, and all lands in which the State has an interest; and that the sum of twenty thousand dollars, or so much thereof as may be necessary, be and the same is hereby appropriated for the purpose of enabling the Commissioner of the General Land Office to make necessary surveys under the provisions of this act, and that this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>December 16th, 1863</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XLIII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to amend the third and fourth sections of &#8220;An Act to provide necessary as<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sistance for families, and other dependents of officers and soldiers.&#8221; approved March 6th, 1863.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas. That the third and fourth sections of &#8220;An Act to provide necessary assistance for families and other dependents of officers and soldiers,&#8221; approved March 6th, 1863, are amended so as to be as follows:</p>
<p>Sec. 2. In such business the court may obtain money, or other means, either <pb n="683" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="29" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw> by public appropriation or by private donation; and the court may so use any funds, which it may now have, or may bereafter acquire, derived from taxation or other ordinary source; and the court shall raise funds therefor, by extraor<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dinary taxation, as may be proper, to supply necessary assistance for the families or individuals to be provided for, so that these persons shall have suitable subsist<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ence and comfort, and property in their charge shall have prudent management, to prevent loss or waste, and to promote appropriate income; Provided, such extraordinary taxes shall be collected, as needed, according to the State assess<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment, as it may be from time to time; and the aggregate of taxes so collected in each year, shall not exceed the rate of one dollar on each hundred dollars of the assessment, and in the collection of such taxes, the county courts may make any practicable arrangements for receiving payments in other articles than money, so as to promote the assistance herein provided for.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. In such business the court may administer the means under its control, not only in any mode which may be prescribed by law, but, consistently therewith, by any suitable instrumentalities; Provided, the court shall not distribute money to the beneficiaries for them to use at their pleasure; but, the court shall cause the means under its control to be specially applied to relieve the actual wants of the beneficiaries, in giving the assistance herein provided for.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. This act shall be in force from its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>December 16th, 1863</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XLIV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act providing for the purchase of cotton by the State, to meet the payment of the cotton bonds to be issued in pursuance of the provisions of &#8220;An Act to raise two millions of dollars, or so much thereof as may be necessary, by the sale of cotton bonds, to provide for the defense of the State, and to repel invasion, and for the purchase of machinery for manufacturing purposes, &#8220;approved December 10th, 1863.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Governor of the State be, and he is hereby authorized, to have purchased, in such manner as he may consider to the best interest of the State, the cotton necessary to meet the payment of the bonds issued in pursuance of the provisions of &#8220;An Act to raise two millions of dollars, or so much thereof as may be neces<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sary, by the sale of cotton-bonds, to provide for the defense of the State, and to expel invasion, and for the purchase of machinery for manufacturing purposes, approved December 10th 1863;&#8221; and that the sum of two millions of dollars of such funds in the Treasury of the State, not otherwise appropriated, be and is hereby appropriated to be used under the direction of the Governor, in the pur<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />chase of cotton for the purposes aforesaid.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Should there not be sufficient funds in the treasury of the State, to meet the appropriation made in the first section of this act, or should the Governor of the State, in his discretion, deem it advisable to use the lands of the State, to carry into effect the object of this act, in either case, the Governor is hereby au<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />thorized to execute the bonds of this State, payable from six to twelve years after the present war between the Confederate States of America and the United States of America, redeemable at the pleasure of the State, for the sum of two millions of dollars, or so much thereof as he may deem necessary, and in such sums as he may consider most suitable, bearing interest at the rate of seven per cent. per annum, from the date of their negotiation, payable in specie twelve months after the close of said war, and semi-annually thereafter, until the payment of the principal. That said bonds may, at any time, be cancelled at the pleasure of the holder or holders, by presenting said bonds to the Treasurer of the State, who shall pay the face value of said bonds in the land script of the State, at the rate of fifty cents per acre. That said bonds shall be signed by the Governor and Treasurer, and registered by the Comptroller, who shall certify the fact of said registration on the back of said bonds.</p>
<pb n="684" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="30" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<p>Sec. 3. The Governor shall authorize the negotiation and sale of said bonds from time to time, and the proceeds thereof shall be applied, under his direction, in carrying into effect the object of this act.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. This act to take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>December 16th, 1863</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XLV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to amend the first and second sections of &#8220;An Act to regulate the sale of Beef Cattle, and to require Butchers to keep and return lists of cattle slaughtered by them, and to prevent the sale of Calves for slaughter without branding,&#8221; ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />proved March 4th, 1863.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the first section of the above recited act be amended, so as to read as follows, to wit: Every purchaser of beeves for the purpose of slaughter for the Confederate armies within the county where purchased or elsewhere, or for the purpose of exportation or driving to market out of the county where purchased, shall, before slaughtering as aforesaid, or exporting, or driving the same out of the county where purchased, take from each and every person from whom he purchases any such beef, or beeves, a bill of sale of the same, in writing, fully describing the number and kind of ani<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mals purchased, with the age, value, and marks and brands of each, which shall be signed by the party selling the same; and, after having had the same proven or acknowledged as required by law, shall cause the same to be filed for record in the office of the Clerk of the County Court of the county where such beeves were purchased. Such bills of sale shall be recorded by the Clerk of the County Court, in a book to be kept for that purpose, which shall be open for inspection by the public: Provided, That when there shall be no clerk of the county where such record shall be required to be made, the same shall be filed and recorded, in the manner herein required, in some adjoining county; and such record, in an adjoin<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing county, shall not dispense with the necessity of filing and recording in the proper county, so soon as there is a clerk therein authorized to make such record.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Section second of the above recited act is hereby amended, so as to read as follows, to wit: Sec. 2. Any purchaser of beef, or beeves, who shall fail to comply with, or shall violate the provisions of, the first section of this act, shall be deemed guilty of an offense against the laws of this State, and shall be liable to indictment therefor, and, upon conviction, shall be fined in a sum not less than twice nor more than five times the value of the beef, or beeves, slaughtered or driven off, contrary to the true intent and meaning of this act, one-half of which shall go to the informer and the other half shall be paid into the county treasury, to the use of the county as a jury fund: Provided, That, such conviction and fine shall not be plead in bar of any civil suit for damages, brought by the owner of such beef, or beeves; nor of any criminal action to which such person might become liable for forging any bill of sale required under this act.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. This act shall be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>December 16th, 1863</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XLVI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to prescribe the punishment for encouraging Desertion from the Army or Navy of the Confederate States, or the State of Texas.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That if any person within this State shall conceal, harbor, aid, assist, or in any manner give protection to any person who is a deserter from the army or navy of the Confederate States or the State of Texas, knowing such person to be a deserter, <pb n="685" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="31" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw> or, if any person shall, in any manner, aid or assist any one who has been legally drafted for the militia service of this State, in evading or escaping from such mil<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />itia service, such person or persons, so offending, shall be deemed guilty of an of<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fense, and, upon conviction thereof by the District Court of the county where such offense was committed, shall be punished by confinement to hard labor in the State Penitentiary not more than five years, or any less punishment may be assessed by the jury, in their discretion.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Any person who shall advise, or in any manner assist or encourage, any officer, soldier, seaman, or marine, to desert from the army or navy of the Confed<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />erate States or of this State, or shall advise, aid, or encourage, any person who has been legally drafted for the militia service of the State of Texas, to evade or es<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cape from the same, shall be deemed guilty of an offense, and, upon conviction thereof in the District Court of the county where such offender resides, or in the county where such offense was committed, shall be punished by confinement in the State Penitentiary, at hard labor, not less than two nor more than five years: Pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vided, That the penalties of this act shall not attach to the wife, or mother, of any officer, soldier, seaman, or marine, or persons held to militia service in this State, as heretofore designated, who may render aid to her husband or son.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. The Judges of the several District Courts shall give this law especially in charge to the grand juries.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. That this act shall be in force from and after the first day of February, 1864.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>December 16th, 1863</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XLVII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to regulate the Estraying of Stock, in certain Counties therein named.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That hereafter when any stray horse, mare, colt, mule, jack, or jinnet, shall be found on the plan<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tation or land of any citizen of this State, such citizen shall forthwith advertise the same, describing the animal&#39;s color, and specifying the marks and brands, if any, at three public places in the county in which such citizen resides, one of which notices shall be on the Court-house door, for at least twenty days; after the expira<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion of which time, if no owner apply, it shall be lawful for such citizen to appear before some Justice of the Peace, in and for said county, and estray the same.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Any citizen entitled to estray any animal, as provided in the first sec<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion of this act, shall make oath that the animal to be estrayed was taken up at his or her residence, or on his or her plantation, or on his or her land, adjoining the same; that the marks and brands have not been altered, or disfigured, since the same was taken up; that notice has been given according to law, and that no owner has been found, which affidavit shall be sworn to and subscribed by the citizen estraying, and filed; whereupon the Justice shall cause to appear before him, by summons or otherwise, two disinterested householders of his county, commanding them, after being sworn, to value and appraise the same, and certify the valuation, together with a particular description of the animal, including stature, marks, brands, color, and age, under oath, which shall be attested by the Justice, who shall thereupon require of the taker up a bond, with two or more solvent securities, for double the appraised value of such animal, payable to the Chief Justice of the County, or his successors in office, conditioned that the taker up shall comply with the provisions of this act; which affidavit, appraisement, end bond, shall be trans<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mitted by such Justice to the Clerk of the County Court within twenty days there<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />after; for which the said Justice shall receive the same fees that are allowed for similar services by law.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. At any time within twelve months, it shall be lawful for the owner <pb n="686" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="32" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw> of any stray horse, mare, colt, mule, jack, or jinnet, to prove his or her property by the oath or affidavit of any respectable witness, in a certificate, containing a par<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ticular description of the animal, or animals, claimed, including the kind, marks, brands, stature, color, and age, of the same, which certificate shall be sworn to and subscribed before any Justice of the county wherein such animal, or animals, may have been estrayed, and delivered to the taker up, to be filed by him in the office of the County Clerk of such county; and, on the delivery of such certificate and the payment of all costs incurred in keeping and posting such estray, or estrays, to the taker up, shall be entitled to demand and receive such animal, or animals: Pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vided, That when the respectability of the witness aforesaid is not known to the officer administering the oath, the party claiming shall produce satisfactory evi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dence of the respectability of such witness, certified by a Notary Public of the county in which the witness resides; and provided further, That in all cases when the owner and taker up cannot agree upon the charge for keeping such estray, or estrays, the Justice before whom such animal, or animals, may have been posted, shall determine the amount to be paid by the owner to the taker up.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. If any person or persons estraying any horse, mare, colt, mule, jack, or jinnet, shall send or take away the same out of the State of Texas, through fraud, or swap, sell, or otherwise dispose of the same, for the purpose of gain, or for the purpose of holding such property, he, she, or they, so offending, shall be liable upon his, her, or their bond, in an action for damages, in favor of the party injured.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. Whenever any estray animal shall be found dead, or shall escape, the taker up shall, without delay, make report thereof to the Clerk of the County Court, under oath, which report shall be recorded in an estray book; and any per<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />son who shall be found guilty of making a false report, shall be liable to an indict<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment, and punished therefor as in other cases of perjury, and shall, moreover, be liable on his or her bond for the value of the animal, or animals, estrayed.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. Each and every estray shall be kept in the county in which such ani<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mal was taken up, and may be used in moderation: Provided, That if the same be abused, the taker up shall be liable upon his bond, in damages, for such abuse, and may be sued therefor, either by the owner, or by the Chief Justice for the use of the county.</p>
<p>Sec. 7. If any person having in charge any estray, or estrays, shall refuse to de<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />liver the same to the owner thereof on his complying with the requisitions of this act, such owner shall be entitled to his action therefor with damages.</p>
<p>Sec. 8. If any estray or estrays of any kind shall be found running at large, and not estrayed, and the owner of the same be unknown, it is hereby made the duty of the County Commissioners, or any of them, to return the same with a full de<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />scription thereof, to the County Clerks of their respective counties, who shall ad<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vertise the same in the manner specified in this act; and if such animal shall not he proved away by the owner within the time allowed by the provisions of this act, the commissioner returning the same, or his successor in office, shall proceed to sell such animal, or animals, and report the sale thereof to the Clerk of the County Courts, and after paying the Clerks fees, and retaining ten per cent. of the proceeds of such sale, he shall pay the remaining sum into the county treasury, there to re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />main during the present war, and one year thereafter, during which time, if any person, or persons, shall come forward, claim and prove up the property thus sold, he, she, or they shall be entitled to draw from the treasury the full amount of money thus retained; and if no claimant or claimants, shall appear as provided for in this article, said funds shall be appropriated for the use and benefit of the county.</p>
<p>Sec. 9. It shall be the duty of the Clerk of the Comity Court to record the papers transmitted to him, as provided in the second section of said act, in a sepa<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />rate book, to be kept in his office for that purpose, and for which he shall be en<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />titled to demand and receive, the same fees that are allowed by law for similar services, to be paid, in all cases, by the taker up: Provided, that when two or <pb n="687" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="33" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw> more animals are taken up at the time time, and by the same person, they shall be included in the same entry, and the justice of the peace and Clerk shall receive no more fees than for one such animal; and each County Clerk shall cause a statement of the appraisement, and a description of the animal so estrayed, to be advertised at least three times, in some newspaper published in the county where such animal, or animals, were estrayed, if there be one, and if there be no news<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />paper published in the county, then the clerk shall cause the same to be adver<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tised in the newspaper nearest to the county, and also by posting up notices at three public places in the county, one of which shall be at the court-house door thereof; and the printer of such notice shall furnish a copy of the paper contain<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing the same to said clerk, whose duty it shall be to file and preserve the same in his office, for the inspection of all persons who may be interested; and for such publication, the printer shall be entitled to receive from the party estraying the same, the sum of two dollars, to be collected by the County Clerk, and paid to the order of the printer.</p>
<p>Sec. 10. The property of every stray horse, mare, colt, mule, jack, jinnet, or work ox, taken up as aforesaid, and not proven away by the owner within twelve months after such appraisement, shall be deemed vested in the county wherein such estray or estrays may have been posted, and the taker up shall immediately thereafter proceed to sell the same, for cash, to the highest bidder, at the court<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />house door of the county, giving notice of the same as required in the case of sheriffs&#8217; or constables&#8217; sales, and within ten days after such sale, he shall pay into the county treasury of the county, seventy-five per cent. of the proceeds of the same, and retain the other twenty-five per cent. for his own use and benefit; Provided, that each and every return of sale shall be made to, and filed by the County Clerk of the county, and sworn to by the taker up; Provided, also, that the owner of the property so estrayed, may at any time during the continuance of the present war, or one year after the ratification of a treaty of peace between the United States and the Confederate States of America, come forward to the county treasurer, and upon proof of such ownership, shall be entitled to have and receive the amount so deposited, after paying such costs as may be necessary to establish his right thereto.</p>
<p>Sec. 11. Any citizen taking up any stray cattle, other than work oxen, hogs, sheep, or goats, shall proceed in the same manner as required in the case of horses, etc., except advertising in a newspaper; and any person estraying the same, at the expiration of six months from the date of appraisement, and shall proceed to give notice as required in cases of sheriffs&#8217; or constables&#8217; sales, and to sell such estrays, where they were taken up, if not less than three bidders attend such sale; Pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vided, that no animal of the kind enumerated in this section, except work oxen, shall be subject to be estrayed, unless the same shall have been on the plantation or land of the taker up, at least six months previous to the time of estraying the same; Provided, the proceeds of the sale of estrayed stock, sold under the provi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sions of this act, shall be paid into the treasury of the county in which said estray or estrays, were sold, and disposed of as in section ten of this act.</p>
<p>Sec. 12. That in making the returns of sales under this act, the taker up, shall, in all cases, give the names of at least three of the bidders, who were present at said sale.</p>
<p>Sec. 13. This Act shall take effect and be in force from and after its passage in the following named counties, and in no others, to-wit: Panola, Rusk, Red River, Bowie, Davis, Marion, Harrison, Shelby, Nacogdoches, San Augustine, Smith, An<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />gelina, Cherokee, Houston, Tyler, Hardin, Jasper, Newton, Sabine, Polk, Ander<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />son, Trinity, Wood, Fannin, Van Zandt, Hopkins and Lamar.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>December 16th, 1863</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
<pb n="688" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="34" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XLVIII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to amend Article 88, Chapter II and Article 123 Chapter VI, of the Penal Code.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That Article 88, Chapter II, and Article 123, Chapter VI, be so amended that they shall respect<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ively read as follows, to-wit:</p>
<p>Art. 88. The salaries of the Superintendant, Directors, Physician, and Chaplain, shall be paid quarterly by the Financial Agent, out of the funds of the Institution, and the salary of the Financial Agent shall be paid quarterly by the State Treas<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />urer, out of the funds of the State, on the warrant of the Comptroller.</p>
<p>Sec. 2.&#8212;Art. 123. He shall be the purchasing, selling and disbursing agent of the Penitentiary. Before entering on the discharge of his duties, he shall execute a bond in the sum of one hundred thousand dollars, payable to the State of Texas, with two or more good and sufficient securities, to be approved by the board of directors, conditioned as follows: That he wall honestly and faithfully dis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />charge the duties of his office as such agent; that he will deposit or pay over, all such sums of money, which may come into his hands as Financial Agent, not necessary for the current expenses of the Penitentiary, as may be directed by law, or may be ordered by the Governor; that he shall pay all accounts for services rendered, and purchases made on the presentation of proper vouchers; and that he shall pay all drafts drawn on him by the Superintendent for any purposes au<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />thorized by law. Said bond shall be recorded in the Directors book of minutes, and by them shall be transmitted to the Department of State, and the same shall remain, unless called for by the proper authorities, for necessary purposes.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That this Act take effect and be in force from and after its passage, and that all laws, and parts of laws, in conflict with the provisions of the same, be and the same are hereby repealed.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>December 16th, 1863</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XLIX.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act making an appropriation to defray the expenses of defending the Frontier for the years 1864 and 1865, in pursuance of the provisions of &#8220;An act to provide for the protection of the Frontier, and turning over the Frontier Regiment to the Confederate States service,&#8221; approved Dec. 15th, 1863.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the sum of one million dollars in Confederate States Treasury Notes, be and the same is hereby appropriated, to be expended in defraying the expenses of defending the Frontier for the years 1864 and 1865, as provided for in the act mentioned in the title hereof.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>December 16, 1863</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER L.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act supplementary to an act to provide for the Protection of the Frontier, and turning over the Frontier Regiment to the Confederate States service, approved December 15th, 1863.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the ammunition mentioned in the fourth and other sections of the act to which this is supplementary, shall be furnished to the men upon proper requisitions, at the cost of the State, and without charge to the men.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That the person to be appointed by the Governor, under the provi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sions of the act to which this is a supplement, to act as paymaster to said Frontier organization, shall have the rank and pay of a captain of cavalry, and <pb n="689" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="35" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw> before entering upon the duties of his office, give bond in such an amount as the Governor may require, with two or more responsible sureties for the faithful per<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />formance of the duties required of him, such bond to be approved by the Governor.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That the men are only to be paid for such time as they are actually on duty, and not for such time as they are at home; and, if at any time more than one-fourth of any one of said companies should be ordered on duty, no additional pay shall be allowed the men or officers, unless such additional duty was performed under orders from the Governor, or under orders approved by him. This act to take effect and be in force from its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>December 16th, 1863</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER LI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act supplemental to an act to provide for the protection of the Frontier, and for the transfer of the Frontier Regiment.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas That all that portion of Karnes County lying southwest of the San Antonio River, and all that part of Bee County lying southwest of the Medio River, be and the same are hereby embraced in the provisions of the above recited act.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. This act shall be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>December 16th, 1863</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER LII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act for the further relief of purchasers of University Lands.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the pur<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />chasers of University lands shall have until the expiration of twelve calendar months, from and after the declaration of peace between the Confederate States of America and the United States of America, or until otherwise provided by law, to make payment of the instalments and interest due the University fund for said lands: Provided, That all such payments shall be made in State bonds and State treasury warrants; that this act shall not be construed to prevent such persons, as may desire to do so, from paying the instalments due, or the interest, or the en<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tire purchase money, due for them; and provided further, that the sureties of each purchaser assent, in writing, to the extension of time, or the principal renew their notes, with two or more sureties, to be approved by the Comptroller.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That no forfeiture shall accrue by reason of failure of purchasers to pay their several debts due for University lands, previous to the expiration of the time mentioned in the first section of this act.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That the provisions of this act shall apply to all purchasers of University lands, as well to those who have paid in part as to those who have failed to pay any portion of their indebtedness.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. That an act, entitled &#8220;An act for the relief of purchasers of University lands.&#8221; approved January 4th, 1862, be and the same is hereby repealed.</p>
<p>Sec. 5, That this act shall take effect and be in force from, and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>December 16th, 1863</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER LIII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to amend the third section of the Act, entitled &#8220;An Act to change and pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vide an uniform time for terminating the Fiscal Year of the several Officers of the State Government, &#8220;approved December 11th, 1857.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the third section of &#8220;An Act to change and provide an uniform time for termin<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" /><pb n="690" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="36" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw> ating the fiscal year of the several officers of the State government, &#8220;approved December 11th, 1857, be amended so as to be in force as follows: Sec. 3. Twenty copies of the report of the Comptroller, and ten copies, respectively, of the reports of the Treasurer, Commissioner of the General Land Office, Secretary of State, At<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />torney General, Adjutant General, Directors of the State Penitentiary, and other public officers land managers of institutions, required to report to the Governor, shall be printed for the use of each member of the Legislature; and the Secretary of State shall send the same, in proper proportions, to the presiding officers of both Houses of the Legislature, at, the commencement of each regular session, for the use of the members.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>December 16th, 1863</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER LIV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to provide for the Manufacture of Iron by the Military Board.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That it shall be the duty of the Military Board to erect and put into operation one or more fur<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />naces and forges, and other suitable works, for the manufacture of iron, to be lo<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cated at such place, or places, as may be selected by said board.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That all iron manufactured by said board, or under their direction, not needed for the defense of the State or in the performance of their duties, shall be sold to the people, according to such regulations and on such terms as said Mili<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tary Board may establish, and the proceeds of such sales paid into the treasury of the State.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That one million of dollars, or so much thereof as may be necessary, be and the same is hereby appropriated for the purpose of carrying into effect the pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />visions of this bill.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. That this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>December 16th, 1863</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER LV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to amend Article 960 of the Code of Criminal Procedure.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That Article 960 of the Code of Criminal Procedure shall be so amended, as hereafter to read as follows: The Sheriff shall receive from the county, for each guard he may employ, and for the support and maintenance of each prisoner in his custody, such amount as the Chief Justice may, in his discretion, designate as necessary and sufficient; and that this act take effect from its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>December 16th, 1863</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER LVI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to punish certain offences committed on Sunday.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That any per<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />son, or persons, who shall compel his or her slaves, children, or apprentices, to labor on the Sabbath, the day known as Sunday, shall be deemed guilty of a misdemean<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />or, and, upon conviction, shall be fined not less than ten nor more than fifty dol<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lars: Provided, That household duties, works of necessity and charity, shall not be prohibited by this act: Provided further, That this act shall not apply to any work done on sugar plantations during the sugar-making season, or any work that may be necessary to save any crop.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That any person, or persons, who shall run or be engaged in running any horse races, or engage in the retail of spirituous or other intoxicating liquors. <pb n="691" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="37" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw> or who shall permit or allow the use of any nine or ten pin alley, or billiard table, or who shall be engaged in match shootings, on Sunday, shall be deemed guilty of a misdemeanor, and, upon conviction, shall be fined not less than fifteen nor more than fifty dollars.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>December 16th, 1863</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER LVII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act authorizing the Comptroller of State to receive from Railroad Companies in this State the interest that may be now due, or hereafter become due, on their Bonds.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Comptroller of the State be, and he is hereby, authorized to receive from the railroad companies in this State, who are indebted to the special school fund, all interest on their bonds that may now be or hereafter become due: Provided, the same is tendered in State boards, or in State treasury warrants, previous to the meeting of the next regular session of the State Legislature.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That for all sums so paid in, the Comptroller and Treasurer shall issue to the special school fund the bonds of the State, bearing six per cent. interest.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. This act take effect from its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>December 16th, 1863</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER LVIII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to regulate Publication Notices in certain cases.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That all legal publication notices, now required to be given by administrators, executors, County Clerks and Chief Justices of the several counties, and which said notices are required by the existing laws to be printed in some newspaper, shall hereafter be given by publication in such newspaper as shall be designated by the Chief Justice of the respective counties, by an order entered upon the records of the County Court.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this act be in force and effect from and after its passage, and all laws conflicting with the provisions of this act are hereby repealed.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>December 16th, 1863</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER LIX.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to amend the first Section of an act, to amend the fourth section of an act entitled &#8220;An act regulating attachments,&#8221; approved March 11th, 1848, passed July 24th, 1856.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the first section of the above recited act is hereby amended so that the same shall here<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />after read as follows, to-wit: The Judges and Clerks of the District Courts, and Justices of the Peace, may issue original attachments, returnable to their re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />spective courts, upon the party applying for the same, his agent or attorney; making an affidavit in writing, stating that the defendant is justly indebted to to the plaintiff, and the amount of said demand; also, that the defendant is not a resident of this State; or that he is about to remove out of this State; or has abandoned the country; or that he secretes himself so that the ordinary process of law cannot be served on him; or that he is about to remove his property beyond this State; or that he is about to remove his property beyond the county in which the suit is to be, or has been, commenced; or that he is about to transfer, or secrete, or has transferred or secreted, his property for the purpose of defrauding his creditors, and that thereby the plaintiff will probably <pb n="692" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="38" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw> lose his debt; and he shall also swear, that the attachment is not sued out for the purpose of injuring the defendant.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. That this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>December 16th, 1863</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER LX.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to raise Revenue by Taxation.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That there shall be levied and collected, for the use of the State, an annual tax, as provided in the following sections of this act:</p>
<p>Sec. 2. A tax of one-half of one per cent. shall be levied and collected, in kind, on all specie, treasury notes of the Confederate States of America, treasury warrants of the State of Texas, and bank notes, held or owned within this State; and all foreign bills of exchange and certificates of deposit, and other evidences of money being deposited, or credited, beyond the limits of this State, owned by persons residing therein, shall be considered as specie, and thereon shall be levied and collected a tax of one-half of one per cent. in specie: Provided, this act shall not be construed so as to tax a deposit at any place now in possession of the public enemy of the Confederate States and within their limits, in case such denosit was made prior to the possession of such place by the public enemy.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. There shall be levied and collected of each free male person, over the age of twenty-one years, resident in this State, idiots, lunatics, and persons other<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />wise non compos mentis excepted, a poll tax of one dollar.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. Each person, or firm, engaged in the sale of goods, wares, and mer<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />chandize, except distilled spirits, fermented liquors, and wines, shall pay a tax of fifty cents on each hundred dollars, proceeds of sales of such articles, pur<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />chased for sale, or received for sale as agent or auctioneer, by such persons, or firm; the tax on sales in specie to be paid in specie. It shall be the duty of each Assessor and Collector, once in every three months, or oftener, to call on each person, or firm, so occupied or engaged in his county, for an account of such sales on such purchases and consignments, to be made under oath, which account shall state such sales as were made for paper currency, and such as were made for specie. Each person, or firm, when so called on, who shall fail or refuse to furnish the Assessor and Collector such an account of sales made during the period for which the account is required, shall be fined in any sum not less than one hundred dollars, nor more than five thousand dollars, by any Court of com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />petent jurisdiction; and, on the verdict of a jury, the Court may add imprison<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment in the county jail not exceeding six months. It shall be the duty of the Assessor and Collector, whenever he shall have good reason to believe that any person has been guilty of violating the provisions of this section, to make com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />plaint of the same before some Magistrate, and to have such person bound to appear and answer before the District Court. Nothing herein contained shall he construed so as to require tax to be twice paid on any currency or money received for such sales; nor shall said goods, wares, and merchandize, be subject to the ad valorem tax.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. There shall be levied and collected of each person pursuing the occu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pation of hawker, or peddler of articles not produced, in the State, an annual direct tax of fifty dollars in each county wherein he may pursue such occupation; of each person, or firm, keeping a billiard table, for play and emolument, an annual direct tax of one hundred dollars for each table so kept; of each person, or firm, keeping a nine or ten pin alley, an annual direct tax of one hundred dollars for each alley so kept; of each person, or firm, keeping a hotel in a town having over five hundred, and not more than two thousand inhabitants, fifteen dollars; in a town having over two thousand, and not more than five thousand inhabitants, twenty dollars, and in a town having more than five thousand inhabitants, thirty dollars; on each person, or firm, keeping any res<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" /><pb n="693" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="39" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw> taurant, cook shop, or eating house, for pay or emolument, fifteen dollars; on each person, or firm, keeping an establishment for retailing distilled spirits, fermented liquors, and wines, all or any of such articles, twenty-five dollars; on each person, or firm, keeping a storage warehouse, ten dollars; on each person, or firm, engaged in re-pressing cotton, twenty-five dollars; on each insurance company, fifty dollars; on each person, or firm, keeping a livery stable, fifteen dollars; on each toll bridge, or ferry, kept and used for pay, as much as six months in a year, ten dollars; on each person engaged in the practice of dentistry, for pay or emolument, ten dol<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lars; on each person, or firm, pursuing the occupation of real estate broker, ship broker, cotton broker, or any commission business, for each establishment therefor, twenty dollars; on each person, or firm, engaged in the business of underwriting, ten dollars; on each pawnbroker, forty dollars; on each person engaged in negro trading, for each negro sold, fifty dollars. It shall be the duty of each person, or firm, proposing to engage in the occupation of hawker or peddler, keeper of a bil<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />liard table, keeper of a nine or ten pin alley, keeper of a cook shop, an eating house, or a restaurant, keeper of a race track, keeper of a hotel, an auctioneer, or a pawn<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />broker, before entering bn the occupation, as proposed, to call on the Assessor and Collector of the county wherein the occupation is to be pursued, and pay the tax as required, and take a receipt therefor, stating the occupation and the amount of tax paid, and file it with the Clerk of the County Court, who shall thereon issue to such person, or firm, a license to follow such occupation for the time for which the tax shall have been paid: Provided, no license shall be issued for a less time than three months; nor shall a license be issued to any person, or firm, until each interested person shall have taken and subscribed, before the Clerk, or some Notary Public, an oath of allegiance to the Confederate States of America. It shall be the further duty of the Clerk to keep a book, in which he shall enter the names of all persons obtaining licenses, with the amounts of taxes paid, and the dates of the licenses. This book shall be open, at all times, for inspection by the County Court, iand by tall other officers, executive or judicial, of the county. The Clerk shall trans<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mit to the Comptroller, on the first of June in each year, a transcript of so much of said book as shall relate to the licenses issued within the year next preceding such date; which transcript shall be authenticated by the certificate of the Chief Justice, under his official seal. And the Clerk, for his services in relation to such book and transcript, shall be entitled to a fee of one dollar, in each case, to be paid by the party obtaining the license.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. If any person, or firm, shall pursue any occupation, for which a license is required, as aforesaid, without first having obtained a license, each person inter<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ested as a party in pursuing such business, shall be guilty of a misdemeanor; and any such offender, on conviction, shall be fined not less than double the amount of the tax for such occupation, nor more than five times the amount of such tax, and may be imprisoned not exceeding thirty days. In case the prosecu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion shall have been instituted by an informer, the Court shall award to him one<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />half of the fine, to be paid to him when collected; and, with such exception, any such fine shall be paid to the Assessor and Collector, to be accounted for as other taxes collected by him.</p>
<p>Sec. 7. If any person shall be engaged in any business requiring a license, as aforesaid, without having first obtained a license therefor, he shall be liable to arrest of his person, seizure of his goods, and search of his premises, in the fol<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lowing manner: On affidavit of any respectable person, showing certainty, or probable cause for believing, that a particular person has committed some such specific offense within the county where such showing shall be made, any Dis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />trict Judge, or Justice of the Peace, having jurisdiction therein, may issue a warrant for arresting the person so accused; and, on the same or another affi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />davit of a respectable person, showing certainty, or probable cause for believing, that the person so accused will remove or secrete any of his property for the purpose of evading the payment of a fine, the Judge or Justice of the Peace, by warrant, may authorize the seizure of so much of the personal property of the <pb n="694" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="40" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw> accused, as may be necessary to secure payment of the highest fine allowed by law; and, on the same or another affidavit of a respectable person, showing certainty, or probable cause for believing, that property of the accused person, liable to such seizure, may be secreted or otherwise secured in any house, or other enclosure, de<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />scribed in the affidavit, the Judge or Justice of the Peace, by warrant, may author<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ize a search of said premises, for the purpose of such seizure. On the return of such warrant for arrest, executed by any officer authorized to execute such process, the accused person, as required by the warrant, shall be brought before some Judge or Justice of the Peace, having jurisdiction, for commitment in such case; and such tribunal, on examination of the case, shall discharge, bind, or commit, the accused person, as the evidence may justify; and, if the warrant for seizure of goods be legally executed, the seized articles shall be accounted for, so as to satisfy the tri<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />bunal, and, if the accused should be discharged, his goods shall be delivered to him; but otherwise the goods shall be in the keeping of such person as the tribunal may designate, to secure payment of a fine, if imposed: Provided, the property shall be subject to be replevied, as in ordinary cases of sequestration. And such process may be executed by the Assessor and Collector, or the Sheriff, or the Coroner, or a Constable.</p>
<p>Sec. 8. Any tax on property, as prescribed by law, when the property shall have been assessed, shall be a lien thereon for payment of the tax; and the lien shall continue, with liability for its enforcement, until the property shall have beeen re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lieved therefrom by legal payment or relinquishment of the tax.</p>
<p>Sec. 9. All laws that are incompatible with this law are repealed; but it shall not be construed as repealing the existing laws authorizing County Courts to levy and collect taxes.</p>
<p>Sec. 10. This act shall be in force from its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>December 16th, 1863</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER LXI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act making appropriations for the use and support of the State Government for the years 1864 and 1865.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the fol<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lowing sums be and they are hereby appropriated for the use and support of the State Government for the years 1864 and 1865, to be paid in Confederate Treasury notes.</p>
<p>Executive Department.</p>
<p>Salary of Governor......................... per annum, $3,000...... $6,000</p>
<p>Salary of Private Secretary.................... per annum, 1,200...... 2,400</p>
<p>Contingent expenses.................... per annum, 2,000...... 4,000</p>
<p>Recovering fugitives from justice.................... per annum, 6,000...... 12,000</p>
<p>Publishing proclamations.................... per annum, 5,000...... 10,000</p>
<p>Stationery .................... per annum, 1,000...... 2,000</p>
<p>Postage .................... per annum, 750...... 1,500</p>
<p>Furnishing Governor's mansion.................... per annum, 2,000...... 4,000</p>
<p>For repairs of premises on which the Governor's mansion is situated........ 2,000</p>
<p>Department of State.</p>
<p>Salary of Secretary of State.................... per annum, 1,800...... 3,600</p>
<p>Salary of Chief Clerk.................... per annum, 1,400...... 2,800</p>
<p>Printing........................... per annum, 600...... 1.200</p>
<p>Porter hire and wood.................... per annum, 500...... 1,000</p>
<p>Contingent expenses.................... per annum, 300...... 600</p>
<p>Stationery and books.................... per annum, 500 1,000</p>
<p>Postage.................... per annum, 500...... 1,000</p>
<p>Assistant Clerk.................... per annum, 1,000...... 2,000</p>
<p>Distributing Laws and Journals of Tenth Legislature........................ 5,000</p>
<pb n="695" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="41" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<p>Printing Laws and Journals of Tenth Legislature ....................... $12,000</p>
<p>Printing Biennial Reports ................................. 8,000</p>
<p>For purchase of fire-wood, lighting material, stationery, and fitting up the Capitol for the next Legislature, taking care of the Capitol, for repairing and taking care of the furniture, and for taking care of the Capitol square and out-buildings ...................................... 5,000</p>
<p>Comptroller's Department.</p>
<p>Salary of Comptroller .............................per annum, 1,800...... 3,600</p>
<p>Salary of Chief Clerk .............................per annum, 1,400...... 2,800</p>
<p>Salary of Tax Clerk .............................per annum, 1,200...... 2,400</p>
<p>Salary of Civil Accountant .............................per annum, 1,200...... 2,400</p>
<p>Salary of Military Accountant .............................per annum, 1,200...... 2,400</p>
<p>Salary of four Assistant Clerks .............................per annum, 3,600...... 7,200</p>
<p>Contingent expenses .............................per annum, 400...... <ref>800</ref></p>
<p>Books and stationery .............................per annum, 1,600...... 3,200</p>
<p>Printing .............................per annum, 1,500...... 3,000</p>
<p>Postage .............................per annum, 500...... 1,000</p>
<p>Blank assessment rolls .............................per annum, 1,000...... 2,000</p>
<p>Fire-wood for Treasury building .............................per annum, 1,000...... 2,000</p>
<p>Porter hire .............................per annum, 900...... 1,800</p>
<p>For the services of a Clerk to the Board on Funding Treasury Warrants, from the 20th of October, 1862, to the 20th of February, 1863 .......... <ref>300</ref></p>
<p>Deficiency for last year, viz:</p>
<p>Fire-wood for Treasury building ........................ 1,529</p>
<p>D. Richardson, for printing .............................. <ref>879</ref></p>
<p>Military Board, for stationery .............................. 4,441</p>
<p>Treasurer's Office.</p>
<p>Salary of Treasurer .............................per annum, 1,800...... 3,600</p>
<p>Salary of Chief Clerk .............................per annum, 1,200...... 2,400</p>
<p>Contingent expenses .............................per annum, 200...... <ref>400</ref></p>
<p>Stationery, postage, and printing .............................per annum, 150...... <ref>300</ref></p>
<p>General Land Office.</p>
<p>Salary of Commissioner .............................per annum, 2,000...... 4,000</p>
<p>Salary of Chief Clerk .............................per annum, 1,400...... 2,800</p>
<p>Salary of Receiver .............................per annum, 1,200...... 2,400</p>
<p>Salary of Translator .............................per annum, 1,200...... 2,400</p>
<p>Salary of File and Application Clerk .............................per annum, 1,200...... 2,400</p>
<p>Salary of Registering Clerk .............................per annum, 1,200...... 2,400</p>
<p>Salary of ten Assistant Clerks, each ....................per annum, 900...... 18,000</p>
<p>Salary of Chief Draughtsman .............................per annum, 1,200...... 2,400</p>
<p>Salary of three Assistant Draughtsmen, each .............................per annum, 1,100...... 6,600</p>
<p>Salary of six 2d Ass't Draughtsmen, each .............................per annum, 1,000...... 12,000</p>
<p>Stationery .............................per annum, 1,000...... 2,000</p>
<p>Contingent expenses ...............................per annum, 400...... <ref>800</ref></p>
<p>Postage .............................per annum, 800...... 1,600</p>
<p>Fire-wood .............................per annum, 1,200...... 2,400</p>
<p>Printing .............................per annum, 300...... <ref>600</ref></p>
<p>Porter hire .............................per annum, 900...... 1,800</p>
<p>Deficiency for wood for Land Office, 1863 ........................ <ref>740</ref></p>
<p>Adjutant General's Office.</p>
<p>Salary of Adjutant General .............................per annum, 2,000...... 4,000</p>
<p>Salary of Assistant Quartermaster General ..............per annum, 1,200...... 2,400</p>
<p>Four Clerks, each .............................per annum, 900...... 7,200</p>
<p>Books and stationery .............................per annum, 2,000...... 4,000</p>
<p>Porter hire and wood .............................per annum, 1,000...... 2,000</p>
<p>Postage .............................per annum, 500...... 1,000</p>
<p>Printing .............................per annum, 2,000...... 4,000</p>
<p>Contingent expenses .............................per annum, 1,000...... 2,000</p>
<p>Outstanding debts, due and unpaid, for the years 1862 &#38; &#39;63, for printing... 1,500</p>
<pb n="696" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="42" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<p>JudiciarySupreme Court.</p>
<p>Salary of three Judges, each .........................per annum, 3,000...... $18,000</p>
<p>Contingent expenses of the Supreme Court ..........per annual, 3,000...... 6,000</p>
<p>Pay of Sheriffs .............................per annum, 609...... 1,218</p>
<p>Porter hire .............................per annum, 300...... 600</p>
<p>Publishing Reports .............................per annum, 7,000...... 14,000</p>
<p>Clerks' fees in felony cases .............................per annum, 150...... 300</p>
<p>Salary of Librarian, at Galveston, for 1862 ........................ 300</p>
<p>District Courts.</p>
<p>Salary of twenty Judges, each .............................per annum, 2,250...... 90,000</p>
<p>Salary of twenty District Attorneys, each .............................per annum, 500...... 20,000</p>
<p>Costs due Clerks, Sheriffs and District Attorneys..per annum, 5,000...... 10,000</p>
<p>Attorney General's Office.</p>
<p>Salary of Attorney General .............................per annum, 1,800...... 3,600</p>
<p>Contingent fund .............................per annum, 100...... 200</p>
<p>Fees in felony cases .............................per annum, 250...... 500</p>
<p>Pensions.</p>
<p>Cynthia Ann Parker .............................per annum, 100...... 200</p>
<p>Allsbury, Juana Navarro . .............................per annum, 100...... 200</p>
<p>Anderson, W. H. ..............................per annum, 100...... 200</p>
<p>Barnett, Thomas .............................per annum, 100...... 200</p>
<p>Cole, David ..............................per annual, 100...... 200</p>
<p>Day, James M. .............................per annum, 100...... 200</p>
<p>Davis, Rolla M. .............................per annum, 100...... 200</p>
<p>Field, Joseph E. .............................per annum, 200...... 400</p>
<p>Nichols, James W. ...........................per annum, 100...... 200</p>
<p>Norris, Thomas .............................per annum, 100...... 200</p>
<p>Smith, H. M. .............................per annum, 250...... 500</p>
<p>Shepperd, Charles ..........................per annum, 125...... 250</p>
<p>Thacker, J. B. .............................per annum, 100...... 200</p>
<p>Webb, David .............................per annum, 100...... 200</p>
<p>Stump, John S. .............................per annum, 200...... 400</p>
<p>Cooper, Dillard .............................per annum, 200...... 400</p>
<p>Penitentiary.</p>
<p>Salary of Superintendent .............................per annum, 1,500...... 3,000</p>
<p>Salary of Financial Agent .............................per annum, 1,500...... 3,000</p>
<p>Salary of three Directors, each .............................per annum, 250 1,500</p>
<p>Salary of Chaplain .............................per annum, 250...... 500</p>
<p>Salary of Physician .............................per annum, 500...... 1,000</p>
<p>Stationery, postage, and printing ................per annum, 300...... 600</p>
<p>Transportation of convicts .......................................... 15,000</p>
<p>Asylums.</p>
<p>Support of Lunatic Asylum .............................per annum, 50,000...... 100,000</p>
<p>Support of Deaf and Dumb Asylum .........................per annum, 34,000...... 68,000</p>
<p>Support of Blind Asylum .............................per annum, 16,000...... 32,000</p>
<p>Miscellaneous.</p>
<p>Slaves executed .............................per annum, 4,000...... 8,000</p>
<p>Scholastic for 1864 and 1865, (interest on School Fund,) .................. 11,000</p>
<p>For support of Militia, embracing subsistence, expenses already accrued, transportation, pay, &#38;c., &#38;c............................ 80,000</p>
<p>For the Alabama, Coshattee and Muscogee Indians.per annum, 1,000...... 2,000</p>
<p>For defense of the State, in case of necessity, subject to the disposition of the Governor ..........................................2,000,000</p>
<p>State Armory.</p>
<p>For the State Armory .............................per annum, 7,000...... 14,000</p>
<p>Store house, (guard, &#38;c.,) .............................per annum, 9,800...... 19,600</p>
<p>For two Librarians .............................per annum, 600...... 1,200</p>
<p>To pay John C. Glover, Sheriff of Leon county, for taking a lunatic (B. F. Hardinett) to Lunatic Asylum .................................... 76</p>
<pb n="697" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="43" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<p>To pay compensation of the person, or persons, employed in negotiations as to the State cotton bonds, embracing the sale of them and the investment of proceeds, to be paid in specie, out of any such funds in the treasury not specifically appropriated to another purpose, or out of the proceeds of the bonds ............................................... $10,000</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this act take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<p>Approved December 16th, 1863.</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER LXII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to amend an act entitled an act for the erection and support of a Lunatic Asylum, approved August 28th, 1856, and an act entitled an act to provide for the organization of the State Lunatic Asylum, and for the care and maintenance of the Insane, approved July 5th, 1858.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Su<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />perintendent of the Lunatic Asylum shall make report quarterly, to the Comp<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />troller, of all the expenses of said Asylum, instead of the semi-annual report required by the act to which this is an amendment, to be made to the Governor. The Super<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />intendent, hereafter, shall make annual reports to the Governor, on the first of Octo<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ber, of the condition of the Asylum and its inmates.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That the eighth section of said act be so amended as hereafter to read as follows:</p>
<p>If information in writing be given to any Chief Justice of a county, that any per<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />son in his county is an idiot, or lunatic, or non compos mentis, and that the welfare of himself, or of others, require that he be placed under restraint, and said Chief Justice shall believe such information to be true, he shall order such person to be brought before him, and twelve competent jurors of the county to be summoned, who shall be sworn to inquire and a true verdict render, whether said person is of sound mind or not; whereupon the matter shall be tried, and if the jury shall return a verdict that the person is not of sound mind, and that foe should be placed under restraint, the same shall be recorded, and the Chief Justice shall thereupon order him to be sent to the Lunatic Asylum. Upon the trial and inquiry herein provided for, the examination of the insane, and the testimony of the witnesses, shall be re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />duced to writing and filed. The proceedings of the Chief Justice, in relation to in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sane persons, shall be minuted in the records of his court appertaining to estates of deceased persons.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That the tenth section of said act be so amended as hereafter to read as follows:</p>
<p>Before sending a patient to the Asylum, the Chief Justice shall, without delay, cause authenticated copies to be made of the proceedings, evidence and decree of the original inquisition, and of the record of all subsequent inquisitions and orders, to be forwarded, by mail, to the Superintendent of the Lunatic Asylum; and in all eases, shall, before sending said person, ascertain from the Superintendent, by appli<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cation in writing, that there is a vacancy, and that the officers of the Asylum can<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />not send for him. Thereupon, the Chief Justice shall issue his warrant to the Sher<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />iff, or other suitable individual, ordering him to convey said person to the Asylum without delay; and when satisfied of the necessity for assistants; he shall prescribe, in such warrant, the number to be allowed, which shall, in no case, exceed two; and he shall see that the patient is provided with two good and full suits of summer and one of winter clothing.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. That the eleventh section of said act be so amended as hereafter to read as follows:</p>
<p>If any person charged with, or convicted of, any criminal offence, be found to be insane, in the court before which he is so charged or convicted, said court shall order him to be conveyed to, and retained in, the State Lunatic Asylum; and he shall be received and retained until removed by order of the court, or of the Judge thereof, by which he was committed to the Asylum. Provided, <pb n="698" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="44" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw> the person so committed to the Asylum, may be removed to the custody of the Sher<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />iff of the county in which he is charged or convicted as aforesaid, by the order of any Judge of the District Court, or discharged upon the order of a Judge author<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ized to issue the writ of Habeas Corpus, as in other cases authorized by law.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. That the eighteenth section of said act be so amended as hereafter to read as follows:</p>
<p>The expenses of removing to, and from the Asylum, clothing and maintenance therein, of every person received upon the order of any Chief Justice, shall be paid by the Treasurer of the county, when, and as they become due and payable. And the County Court shall have the right to require every individual legally liable for the support of such patient, to reimburse the amount so paid, with interest from the time of paving the same.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. That the twenty-second section of said act be so amended as hereafter to read as follows:</p>
<p>The officer complying with the order of the court, or the Superintendent, in carrying a patient to the Asylum, shall be paid at the rate of ten cents per mile for himself, and each guard, (authorized by the court,) going and returning, besides tolls and ferriages, and the same for the patient going. The compensation for re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />turning fugitives to be paid out of the Treasury of the Asylum, upon proper vouch<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ers, and for all others, out of the County Treasury, as provided by the fifth section of this act.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted that this act take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>December 16th, 1863</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">LXIII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to provide for the Defense of the State.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Gov<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ernor of the State is hereby empowered to continue in the service of the State, the State Militia now in the field, for the term of six months after their present term of service expires. He is hereby further empowered, to order into the same service, the Militia now remaining at home. These powers are to be exercised when he shall deem the said Militia necessary to enforce the laws, suppress insurrections or to repel invasion, and are to be subject to the restrictions hereinafter expressed.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. The Governor shall order all the Militia, not now in the field, to be en<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />rolled, and without loss of time after such enrollment, the men so enrolled, shall proceed to, and become members of, the companies, battalions and regiments raised in their several counties and brigade districts. Such enrollment shall be made within one month preceding the expiration of the term of service of the Militia now in the field, and in time to allow those enrolled to join their companies before the expira<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion of said term of service.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. When the time shall have arrived for the term of service of the Militia now in the field to expire, there shall be a reorganization of the Militia, by the elec<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion of company and field officers. At said election, all those shall be allowed to vote who are now in the field, and also those who shall have joined their companies prior to such reorganization.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. The whole number of Militia, except commissioned officers, thus organized, shall be divided into three classes, to be called the First Class, the Second Class, and the Third Class. The third class shall be com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />posed of those who are not now in the field, and who shall be ordered there under the provisions of this law. The commanding officers of brigades, unattached companies, battalions and regiments, shall divide the Militia now in the field, into two classes, in the following manner: There shall be put in a hat, for each company now in the field, as many tickets as there are private soldiers in such company. One-half of these tickets shall be numbered one, and one-half shall be num<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />bered two. The roll shall be called, and each man, as his name is called, shall draw <pb n="699" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="45" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw> out a ticket. Those drawing a ticket marked one, shall be of the first class, and those drawing a ticket marked two, shall be of the second class. Should any man be absent, then the officer in command of such company, shall draw for him. This classification shall be made at the time of the reorganization, as ordered in section three of this act. The non-commissioned officers shall, at the same time, and in the same manner, be classified, but shall draw separately from the private soldiers. But persons in the Militia liable to service in the army of the Confederate States, shall not be classified, or furloughed, as hereinafter provided.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. Such reorganization and classification being completed, all those of the first class shall be furloughed for the term of three months, at the expiration of which, they shall return to their respective companies, and at that time all those of the second class shall be furloughed for a like time, and so, also, with the third class. Commanders of brigades shall devise a system of leaves of absence for commissioned officers, in such manner as to grant them, without detriment to the country, rea<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sonable time to visit their families and attend to necessary business.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. If any person not now in the Militia in the field, but liable, under this act, to be called into service, shall be called into service, and shall fail, without reason<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />able excuse, to join his company or regiment, as herein required, he shall be deemed guilty of desertion, and may be proceeded against, tried and punished according to the articles of war and regulations for the army of the Confederate States.</p>
<p>Sec. 7. The Militia of this State, organized according to the provisions of this act, and under the immediate command of officers appointed by the Governor, may by him be put under the orders of the commander of the army of the Confederate States in the District of Texas, the Confederate States paying, subsisting and cloth<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing the said Militia as Confederate troops. Said Militia shall not be sworn into the service of the Confederate States, but shall always remain liable to the ultimate control of the Governor, if he deem it proper at any time to exercise such control; and they may, at any time, by him withdrawn or disbanded.</p>
<p>Sec. 8. In all cases when the Militia of this State shall be in the field, under an order from the Governor, or act of the Legislature, and the Confederate States shall refuse to grant them pay, subsistence and allowances as to Confederate troops, then the Militia shall have pay, subsistence and allowances, the same as allowed to Con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />federate troops, to be furnished by this State.</p>
<p>Sec. 9. Should, the Governor disband the Militia, the said classification and or<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ganization shall not be destroyed. In that case the Militia shall be a reserve force, to be again called out should accasion require, and such call shall be made upon the two classes whose turn it is to be in the field, it being the object of this act to retain always at home, one-third of the Militia of the State, and to keep two<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />thirds of the Militia in active service during the present war, whenever there shall be necessity of such service.</p>
<p>Sec. 10. No person who has a substitute in the Militia now in the field, and who, if he had not such substitute, would be liable to Militia duty, shall because of having furnished a substitute, be deemed exempt from Militia duty, after the expiration of the present term of service of the Militia now in the field; but such person shall be<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />long to the first or second class of Militia, as shall be determined by lot, and when the lots are drawn, as provided in section three, he shall draw with the rest, if he be present, and if not, the officer in command of the company shall draw for him, and the substitute, if liable to Militia duty, shall belong to the third class.</p>
<p>Any person belonging to either of the classes may, with the consent of the com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />manding officer of his company, exchange places with another of a different class in the same company.</p>
<p>Sec. 11. This Act shall be in force from and after its passage, and shall remain in force until the termination of the present war between the Confederate States and the United States.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>December 16th, 1863</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
<pb n="700" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="46" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER LXIV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to amend the second, third and seventh sections of and supplemental to an &#8220;Act to perfect the organization of State Troops, and place the same on a war footing,&#8221; approved December 25th, 1861, and to repeal &#8220;An Act to amend the 2d section of and supplemental to an Act to perfect the organization of the State Troops, and place the same on a war footing,&#8221; approved December 25th, 1861,&#8221; passed March 7th, 1863.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted, by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the second section of the act recited above, shall hereafter read as follows: All offi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cers, State and County, of the State of Texas, except Justices of the Peace, County Commissioners, Coroners, County Surveyors, Constables and Notaries Public; and all officers of the Confederate States, except Postmasters, Deputy Marshals and Deputy Receivers; Officers&#8217; Clerks, Directory and Guards of the Penitentiary, Superintend<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ents and Teachers in the Deaf and Dumb, Blind and Lunatic Asylums; in schools and academies, not more than one teacher for every twenty scholars actually at<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tending school; one Captain, two Pilots, and two Engineers to each steamboat ac<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tually employed in the service of the State or the Confederate States; Telegraph operators actually engaged as such; Presidents&#8217; Secretaries and Superintendents, En<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />gineers, Conductors and Rail Road Masters of Rail Roads; the Reporter of the Decisions of the Supreme Court; original Mail Contractors and one stage driver for every twenty miles on every regular mail stage route; Mechanics actually engaged in the manufacture of spinning jennies or cotton cards; such Millers to each steam or water mill that grinds for the public; and as many Engineers for each steam mill in actual operation, as may be adjudged necessary by the Enrolling officer; one Miller, engaged in person, for every ox or horse mill, grinding for the public, capable of grinding thirty-five bushels per day; one Carder for every one carding machine engaged in carding for the public; one machinist for each turning lathe used for boring or dressing iron; one tanner for each tannery turning off one thousand sides of leather per annum; such Machinists to keep up the mechanical department of all regular foundries working for the public, as may be deemed necessary by the Enrolling Officers; all regular Blacksmiths working in person for the public; all persons engaged in the manufacture of salt for sale to the public, not exceeding one person for every twenty bushels made per day; and such persons engaged in the manufacture of arms, powder, sulphur, and saltpetre as the Governor may deem necessary; and persons having substitutes in the army of the Confederate States, who were exempt from military service to the State, shall be exempt from military duty to the State of Texas; Provided, That no person liable to military service under the provisions of this act, shall hereafter be allowed to furnish a substitute and thereby be exempt from duty; and provided further, that the exemption of millers, blacksmiths and other mechanics working for the public, shall only extend so long as they work or sell the proceeds of their labor at a cost of not more than fifty per cent. over and above the original cost of the same; and it is hereby made the duty of all persons charged with the duty of enrolling the militia, to diligently inquire into the provisions of this proviso, and to see that all persons offending against the same are enrolled and placed in the service; and provided, that such respectable physicians, as the County Court may certify, are absolutely necessary for the wants of the county, such certificate of exemption to be approved by the Brigadier General of the District; and the Aid de Camp of the Governor, provided for by the act to which this is supplementary, are also to be exempt from military duty.</p>
<p>Sec 2. That the third section of the act to which this is supplementary shall hereafter read as follows: The whole of this State shall be divided by the Governor into six Military Brigades.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That the seventh section of the act to which this is supplementary, shall hereafter read as follows: There shall be appointed, by the Governor, one Major General for this State; one Brigadier General for each Brigade District <pb n="701" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="47" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw> herein provided for, and such general officers, to hold their respective offices for four years, unless sooner removed by the sentence of a Court Martial, as provided by the 25th section of this act, and shall be entitled to receive the same pay as officers of like grade in the Confederate States army, when on duty, acting under orders from the Governor. They shall also be entitled to the same staff officers, with the same pay as such staff officers, with officers of like grade in the Confederate army; but no pay to be allowed such staff officers, or any one of them, unless when on actual duty under orders approved by the Governor. Whenever the Governor deems it necessary, he shall order any one or more of said general officers to take command of the State Militia now in the field, or that may bereafter be called to the field, or to such other duty as he may think proper for the necessary military organization and defence of the State. The Governor shall also appoint surgeons and assistant surgeons to the militia now in the field, or that may at any time hereafter be called into service.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. That whenever, in the opinion of the Governor, the interest of the State demands that the militia of the State, or any portion thereof, should be called into service to repel invasion, suppress insurrection or rebellion, or whenever the militia of the State shall be called into active service by the President of the Confederate States in pursuance of law, to execute the laws of the Confederate States within this State, or to suppress insurrection or rebellion therein, or to Tepel an invasion thereof, the Governor shall, by proclamation, order into camps a sufficient number of troops to repel such invasion, rebellion, or insurrection, or to fill the requisition for State Militia made upon him by the President of the Confederate States, in pursuance of law, in the following manner, to-wit: He shall order the Brigadier General, of such Brigades, as to him may seem proper, to cause each Captain within his Brigade to muster his company on any designated day, and cause the name of each commissioned officer, non-commissioned officer and private to be placed in a hat or box, and the proportion of said company which may be ordered by the Brigadier General, under the authority of the Governor, shall be drawn by the Captain, or any person he may designate, from the hat or box; and such persons as are drawn shall immediately repair to the camp desig<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />nated by the Governor or Brigadier General.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. That it shall be the duty of the Brigadier General to proceed imme<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />diately to cause the militia drawn into service within his Brigade, to be organized into companies of not less than sixty-four rank and file, and to be officered in accordance with the laws of the State; the militia called out by the Governor, and officered as aforesaid, to repel an invasion of the State, or to repress insurrection or rebellion therein, shall remain in the service of the State, until discharged by the Governor, or by his authority, or the militia so called out, may be placed under the orders of the commanding general of the Confederate forces in this State, for such length of time, not to exceed twelve months, as the Governor may deem proper; Provided, That before placing the militia under orders of the commanding general, as aforesaid, the Governor shall have the same organized into battalions and regiments; and, if the number is sufficient, into a brigade or brigades; and the Governor is hereby authorized to assign to the command of such brigade, or brigades, any one or more of the Brigadier Generals of the State; and provided further, That the State militia shall not, by any commander, be carried beyond the limits of this State without their voluntary consent.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. That the Brigadier Generals provided for in this act, when commissioned by the Governor, shall supercede the Brigadier Generals appointed or elected under the provisions of the act to which this is supplementary; and all officers elected or appointed under said act of 25th of December. 1861, who are not exempt under the provisions of this act, and who are within militia age, shall be subject to militia</p>
<p>Sec. 7. That it is hereby made the duty of the Brigadier General, so soon as he shall receive an order from the Governor, to call out any portion of the militia, under this act, to appoint three physicians, of good standing, in each <pb n="702" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="48" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw> county in his brigade, whose duty it shall be, on a day to be named by them, of which notice shall be given, to attend at the Court-house of their respective counties for the purpose of examining all applicants for discharges on account of physical disability, which examinations shall take place at least five days before the day of draft. The said physicians, or a majority of them, shall, after a critical personal examination, determine whether the applicant be unable to per<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />form the duties of a soldier in the field, and if so, they shall give the person so determined to be unable to perform military duty, a certificate setting forth the character of his disability in full, and upon the presentation of such certificate to the Enrolling Officer of said county, he shall erase the name of the party from his roll. The physicians, for said service, shall receive five dollars per days, each, for the time actually employed, to be paid out of the State Treasury, upon account approved by the Brigadier General commanding said brigade.</p>
<p>Sec. 8. That any person who shall fail or refuse to do and perform military service under this act, without sufficient excuse, shall be deemed guilty of the crime of desertion, and on conviction thereof, by a Court Martial, shall suffer such punishment to be determined by said Court Martial, not inconsistent with the rules and regulations governing the army of the Confederate States.</p>
<p>Sec. 9. That company, battalion and regimental drill is suspended during the continuance of the present war. Enrolling Officers, whilst engaged as such, shall be entitled to the pay as 2d Lieutenant of Cavalry, to be paid out of the Treasury of the State of Texas, the same to be approved by the Brigade commander.</p>
<p>Sec. 10. That it shall be the duty of the several Brigadier Generals herein provided for, under such directions as the Governor may cause to be devised, to encourage and form volunteer companies, and organizations of such persons as are not subject to militia or other duty, for local defense, and all necessary police regulations in the counties where such companies may be raised, and for service in the field in an emergency; but in no event shall such companies or organizations, when constituted of one or more companies, be marched beyond the limits of their Brigade District, without their consent; and when any such company or organiza<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion shall go beyond the limits of their district, they shall be allowed to return at their own option. It shall also be the duty of the Brigadier Generals of Districts, to appoint proper Enrolling Officers, and all such persons as have heretofore been exempt from duty on account of physical disability, and in such cases as the Enrolling Officer may think are able to perform military duty in the field, shall be required to present themselves before the board of physicians, as herein provided, for re-examination, and those found fit for duty in the field, shall be enrolled and sub<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ject for duty. That the physicians appointed by the Brigadier Generals, to ex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />amine applicants for discharge on account of disability, shall be required to dis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />charge such duties, and in case of refusal, shall be enrolled in the militia, and subject to duty, unless otherwise exempt.</p>
<p>Sec. 11. That all laws and parts of laws conflicting with the provisions of this act be, and the same are hereby repealed, and that this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>December 16th, 1863</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER LXV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to regulate Distilleries and to repeal the lair, authorizing Licenses therefor.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, as follows: The County Court of any county, in the administration of its police, shall have authority at any time, under current circumstances, to determine and declare the distilling of spirits to be prejudicial to public subsistence. On such declara<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion being properly entered on the minutes of proceedings of the County Court, the District Court shall have jurisdiction of the subject; and the County Court, <pb n="703" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="49" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw> or any person, may prosecute for any such offence; and, according to the law for other like offenses against public policy and economy and health, the offender under this act may be punished and the business restrained: Provided, That pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ceedings under this law shall not be conducted so as to deprive any person of his privilege from a legal license for distilling, without adequate compensation being made, unless by the consent of such person.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. The law which imposes an occupation tax of one thousand dollars on a distiller for each still employed in distilling, is repealed.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. This act shall be in force from its passage, and shall be in force until the termination of the present war, at which time it shall cease to be the law.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Passed <date>December 16th, 1863</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER LXVI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>All Act to provide for the election of Senators and Representatives to the Eleventh Legislature, for the year 1865, in Counties occupied by a public enemy.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That in all cases where Senatorial or Representative districts are, in whole or in part, occu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pied by a public enemy, so that elections cannot be held in such districts for mem<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />bers of the eleventh Legislature, as required by law, the legally qualified electors of such district, or districts, may cast their votes at any precinct, or precincts, in the State, for a citizen, or citizens, of their respective districts, for Senator, or Representatives, to represent them in the eleventh Legislature: Provided, That the Judges of any election precinct shall not permit any person to vote, under the provisions of this act, unless he shall first swear that he is a citizen and an elector of the representative or senatorial district for whose Representative or Senator he proposes to east his vote; and the several Chief Justices of the counties where such votes shall be cast, are hereby required to certify such votes so cast, and return the same to the Secretary of State, specifically stating the district for which such votes were given, and whether for Senator or Representative, under the same regulations as are prescribed in other cases; and the person, or persons, having the highest number of votes for the respective offices, shall, on the pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />duction of a certificate of the fact from the Secretary of State, be entitled to repre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sent the district for which they are elected, in the Senate or House of Representa<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tives of the eleventh Legislature, as the case may be.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Passed <date>December 16th, 1863</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER LXVII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to amend. Articles 412 and 418 of &#8220;An Act to adopt and establish a Penal Code for the State of Texas,&#8221; approved August 28th, 1856.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That article 412, of the above recited act, shall hereafter read as follows, to wit: &#8220;If any person shall keep or exhibit for the purpose of gaming, any gaming table or bank, of any name or description whatever, or any table or bank, used for gaming, which has no name, or shall be in any manner interested in keeping or exhibiting such table or bank at any place, he shall be fined not less than five hundred dollars, nor more than one thousand dollars.&#8221;</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That for each game upon which any of the games enumerated in the first section of this act, or in the fourth chapter of the Penal Code, shall be played or exhibited, shall constitute a separate offence; and that, in all cases arising under the provisions of this act, where Justices of the Peace, Mayors, and Recorders, have not jurisdiction finally to try, it shall be their duty to bind, as in other cases, the person accused to answer such <pb n="704" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="50" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw> charge at the next term of the District Court to be held in the county in which such offence shall have been committed.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That article 418, of the above recited, act, shall hereafter read as follows, to wit: &#8220;If any person shall bet at any gaming table or bank, such as are in the six preceding articles mentioned, he shall be fined not less than one hundred dollars, nor more than two hundred and fifty dollars.&#8221;</p>
<p>Sec. 4. That this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>December 16th, 1863</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
<pb n="705" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="51" />
</div3>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">JOINT RESOLUTIONS.</head>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER I. JOINT RESOLUTION.</head>
<p>1. Resolved, by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That in consideration of the patriotic service, personal sacrifice, and distinguished gallantry of all Texian Soldiers who have been, and who are now, in the Armies of the Confederate States and State of Texas, battling for Southern honor and independence, we, the Repre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sentatives of the State of Texas, for ourselves and in behalf of our constituents, tender to them, both officers and men, the sincere, heartfelt thanks of the people of the State of Texas; and that, recognizing them as the brave defenders of our common liberties, we hereby pledge ourselves, and the State, to the support and maintenance of their families during their absence from home.</p>
<p>2. Resolved, by the Legislature, That the Governor is hereby requested to have the above resolution printed and forwarded to each regiment, battalion, and inde<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pendent company, raised in the State of Texas, with a request of their respective commanders to have the same read on dress parade.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>November 24th, 1863</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER II. JOINT RESOLUTION.</head>
<p>1. Resolved by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That our Senators in Congress be and they are hereby instructed, and our Representatives in Congress be respectfully requested, to use their best efforts to repeal all laws exempting persons from conscription, on account of their being the owners of property of any description whatever.</p>
<p>2. Resolved, That the Governor be requested to transmit a copy of this resolu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion to each of our Senators and Representatives in Congress.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Passed <date>December 3d, 1863</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER III.</head>
<p>Joint Resolution requesting our Senators and Representatives in Congress to in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />crease the wages of the non-commissioned officers and privates in the Army and Navy of the Confederate States of America.</p>
<p>Resolved by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That our Senators in Congress, and our Representatives, are requested to use their influence to increase the wages of the non-commissioned officers and privates in the Army and Navy of the Con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />federate States of America; and that Congress increase, the tax, so as to meet the increase of pay.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Passed <date>December 16th, 1863</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
<pb n="706" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="52" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER IV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>Joint Resolution to provide for the Payment of State Troops.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Whereas, the State troops were called out by the proclamation of His Excel<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lency Governor Lubbock, in 1862, and these troops were transferred to the Con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />federate Commander of the State of Texas; and, whereas, supplies to meet the wants of these troops were furnished by individual advancement and credit, &#38;c., which have not been reimbursed or met by either State or Confederacy:</p>
<p>Therefore, be it resolved by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Adjutant and Inspector General of the State be and is hereby instructed to inquire into the cause of the non-payment of any or all claims in the premises, and to take such steps as will properly adjust the rights of all concerned.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>December 16th, 1863</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER V.</head>
<opener>
<salute>Joint Resolution in relation to Public Printing for the Tenth Legislature.</salute>
</opener>
<p>1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Secretary of State, Comptroller and Treasurer, or a majority of them, be required to proceed immediately after the adjournment of the Tenth Legislature, to contract for the Public Printing, as nearly as may be in accordance with existing laws; and that this resolution take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>December 16th, 1863</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER VI. JOINT RESOLUTION.</head>
<p>Whereas, the present war, waged by the Government of the United States upon the Government, people and property of the Confederate States, is without prece<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dent in its atrocious and unchristian character; and, whereas, the comparative exemption of our own dear State from many of the more dire concomitants of war, may have been construed as a cause for our unanimity in sustaining our Govern<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment:</p>
<p>1. Therefore, be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That now that our presumptuous enemy treads our soil in heavy number and menacing atti<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tude, we bid him a proud and scornful defiance.</p>
<p>2. That we pledge to our sister States, that in this struggle, our authorities and our people will evince a patriotism and endurance as great as the occasion and as prolonged as the conflict.</p>
<p>3. That although as a free people, we have exercised the right of criticism upon the acts of our President and his Cabinet, yet we here record our full con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fidence in the patriotism and ability of President Davis; and do furthermore de<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />clare, that if remitted now to our option, we would not exchange him for any citi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />zen of the Confederacy, as the pilot to carry us through the present stormy strug<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />gle for liberty as a people, and for independence as a nation.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>December 16th, 1863</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
<pb n="707" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="53" />
</div3>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">INDEX TO THE GENERAL LAWS.</head>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">A</head>
<p>Administrators. Page.</p>
<p>To hire or rent property at public auction......................... <ref>12</ref></p>
<p>Alien Enemies. Stay law not to effect debts due by............................ <ref>5</ref></p>
<p>Appropriations.</p>
<p>Contingent expenses, Tenth Legislature.................. <ref>3</ref></p>
<p>Mileage and per diem. Tenth Legislature.................. <ref>7</ref></p>
<p>To supply deficits in appropriations for Frontier Regiment.......... <ref>16</ref></p>
<p>For support of Frontier Regiment.................. <ref>16</ref></p>
<p>For auditing claims of the State against the Confederate States........ <ref>16</ref></p>
<p>For hospital fund.................................................... <ref>21</ref></p>
<p>For support of families and dependents of Texian soldiers........ <ref>21</ref></p>
<p>For re-covering public buildings................................... <ref>25</ref></p>
<p>For protection of the frontier for 1864 and 1865.................. <ref>34</ref></p>
<p>For support of the State Government for 1864 and 1865 40 Asylums, State.</p>
<p>Punishing persons removing or destroying timber, &#38;c., belonging thereto................................................ <ref>12</ref></p>
<p>Asylums, Lunatic. See &#8220;Lunatic Asylum.&#8221;</p>
<p>Attachments. Writs of, to issue in certain cases, notwithstanding Stay laws............ <ref>5</ref></p>
<p>Former law amended................................................ <ref>37</ref></p>
<p>Attorneys, District.</p>
<p>To report to Comptroller the condition of suits brought against de<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />faulters.............................................. <ref>7</ref></p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">B</head>
<p>Bail Bonds. Not to be forfeited in certain cases...................................... <ref>10</ref></p>
<p>Beef Cattle. Regulating the sale of.................................... <ref>30</ref></p>
<p>List of those sold must be kept, &#38;c........................... <ref>30</ref></p>
<p>Board, Military.</p>
<p>Reorganized............................................ <ref>26</ref></p>
<p>Bonds.</p>
<p>Suits are in certain cases suspended........................... <ref>5</ref></p>
<p>Bonds of R. R. Companies.</p>
<p>See &#8220;Rail Road Companies.&#8221; Bonds, Cotton.</p>
<p>Two millions of dollars to be raised by the sale of, for defensive pur<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />poses................................. <ref>9</ref></p>
<p>To provide for the payment of................................ <ref>29</ref></p>
<p>Bills of Exchange.</p>
<p>Collection of suspended..................................... <ref>5</ref></p>
</div3>
<pb n="708" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="54" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">C</head>
<p>Calves. Page.</p>
<p>For sale or slaughter must be branded.................................... <ref>30</ref></p>
<p>Clerks. Salary of Governor&#8217;s Private Secretary fixed.................. <ref>8</ref></p>
<p>Code. Penal. Article 231 amended............................................ <ref>12</ref></p>
<p>Treason against the State defined.......................................... <ref>12</ref></p>
<p>Actual communication with the public enemy not necessary to con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />stitute the offence of...................................... <ref>12</ref></p>
<p>Meaning of &#8220;Overt Act&#8221; defined......................................... <ref>13</ref></p>
<p>Article 233 amended......................................................... <ref>13</ref></p>
<p>&#8220;Misprision of Treason&#8221; defined........................................... <ref>13</ref></p>
<p>Not giving information of treason committed, constitutes Misprision of Treason.................. <ref>13</ref></p>
<p>Husband and wife excepted................................. <ref>13</ref></p>
<p>Article 233a added................................... <ref>13</ref></p>
<p>Definition of an intention to commit treason................................... <ref>13</ref></p>
<p>Article 234a added............................................. <ref>13</ref></p>
<p>Definition of the offence of &#8220;Encouraging Treason &#8220;. ................... <ref>13</ref></p>
<p>Advising one to join the public enemy, or that he owes obedience or duty to the public enemy, punished, and how <ref>13</ref></p>
<p>Writing, printing, or causing to be written or printed, any book, pa<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />per, pamphlet, &#38;c., tending to encourage treason, punished, and how 13 Article 780.............................................. <ref>13</ref></p>
<p>&#8220;Conspiracy, &#8220;defined and punishment therefor affixed.................. <ref>13</ref></p>
<p>Article 412 amended.................. <ref>49</ref></p>
<p>&#8220;Gaming,&#8221; defined and how punished.............................. <ref>49</ref></p>
<p>Code of Criminal Procedure.</p>
<p>Article 960 amended 36 Common Carriers.</p>
<p>To further define their liabilities............................ <ref>7</ref></p>
<p>Commissioner for sale of cotton Bonds.</p>
<p>Appointment of............................................. <ref>9</ref></p>
<p>Salary of...................................................... <ref>9</ref></p>
<p>Confederate States.</p>
<p>Act of 1849 to cede jurisdiction in certain cases, amended................................... <ref>4</ref></p>
<p>Claims of the State against, to be audited......................................... <ref>16</ref></p>
<p>Conspiracy.</p>
<p>See &#8220;Code, Penal.&#8221; Conscription.</p>
<p>Joint Resolution requesting Congress to repeal property, exemption from..................................... <ref>50</ref></p>
<p>Cotton Bonds. $2,000,000 to be raised by sale of, for the defense of the State and for purchase of machinery................................... <ref>9</ref></p>
<p>Cotton. To provide for the purchase of, to meet the payment of cotton bonds.. <ref>29</ref></p>
<p>Counties. Jails of to be used for the custody of deserters, &#38;c................... <ref>4</ref></p>
<p>County Courts. To regulate the pay of Sheriff in certain cases.................. <ref>11</ref></p>
<p>71st section of the act of 1848, regulating proceeding therein, amended, <ref>12</ref></p>
<p>58th section of same act, amended......................... <ref>14</ref></p>
<p>Amending the law organizing.................................... <ref>15</ref></p>
<p>Regular terms thereof to be held, and when.................. <ref>15</ref></p>
<p>To regulate the quality of spirits offered for sale.................. <ref>19</ref></p>
<p>County Boundaries. To provide for ascertaining conflicts in................................. <ref>27</ref></p>
<p>Courts, District. Act of 1846, regulating proceedings therein, amended.................. <ref>10</ref></p>
<p>How and where suits must be brought.................. <ref>10</ref></p>
</div3>
<pb n="709" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="55" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">D</head>
<p>Deeds of Trust. Page.</p>
<p>How affected by Stay Law............................ <ref>6</ref></p>
<p>Defaulters, State. District Attorneys to report condition of suits brought against, to Comptroller.............................................. <ref>7</ref></p>
<p>Deceased Persons, Estates of. See &#8220;Estates of Deceased Persons.&#8221;</p>
<p>Deserters, &#38;c. County Jails to be used for their custody.................. <ref>4</ref></p>
<p>Punishment for persons harboring....................... <ref>30</ref></p>
<p>Punishment for encouraging................................. <ref>31</ref></p>
<p>Defense of the State. See &#8220;State.&#8221;</p>
<p>Desertion. To further provide punishment for.................. <ref>48</ref></p>
<p>Disloyalty. Offence defined and punishment fixed.................. <ref>20</ref></p>
<p>Disaffection to the State. Offence defined and punishment fixed.................. <ref>20</ref></p>
<p>District Courts. Act regulating proceeding therein amended........................ <ref>10</ref></p>
<p>Special terms thereof provided for.................. <ref>27</ref></p>
<p>District Clerks. May administer oaths.......................... <ref>37</ref></p>
<p>Powers relating to attachments................................. <ref>37</ref></p>
<p>Distilleries.</p>
<p>Law granting licences therefor, repealed.................. <ref>49</ref></p>
<p>May be declared nuisances.................. <ref>48</ref></p>
<p>Domain, Public. Relief of pre-emption settlers thereon.................. <ref>4</ref></p>
<p>Location, survey and sale of, suspended, except in certain cases...... <ref>15</ref></p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">E</head>
<p>Encouragement of Treason. See &#8220;Code, Penal.&#8221;</p>
<p>Enrolling Officers. To aid them in discharge of their duties.................. <ref>11</ref></p>
<p>May call on Sheriff.................. <ref>11</ref></p>
<p>Of the State, how appointed and paid.................... <ref>48</ref></p>
<p>Estates of deceased Persons.</p>
<p>Law regulating proceedings in County Courts pertaining thereto amended.................. <ref>12</ref></p>
<p>Property belonging to must be rented or hired at public auction.... <ref>12</ref></p>
<p>71st section of the act regulating proceedings pertaining thereto amended......................................... <ref>12</ref></p>
<p>58th section, same act, amended....................... <ref>14</ref></p>
<p>Enemy, Public.</p>
<p>Persons communicating with, punished............................. <ref>21</ref></p>
<p>Punishment for adhering to.................................... <ref>21</ref></p>
<p>Estray Law. Law suspending the operation of, amended.................. <ref>8</ref></p>
<p>Certain stock may be estrayed.................................. <ref>8</ref></p>
<p>Persons who estrayed stock prior to Feb. 25th, 1863, shall now sell.................. <ref>8</ref></p>
<p>Persons estraying shall not bid................................. <ref>8</ref></p>
<p>Regulated in certain counties................................ <ref>31</ref></p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">F</head>
<p>Financial Agent of Penitentiary. Bond, how made............................................. <ref>34</ref></p>
<p>To employ additional labor for the Penitentary.................. <ref>6</ref></p>
<p>Fiscal Year. Of State officers, established.................................. <ref>35</ref></p>
<p>Forfeitures of Bail Bonds. Provided against in certain cases......................... <ref>10</ref></p>
<pb n="710" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="56" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<p>Frontier. Page.</p>
<p>Providing for defense of.................................. <ref>23</ref></p>
<p>Section 1, designates the frontier counties.................. <ref>23</ref></p>
<p>Section 2, divided into three Districts, and of the organization...... <ref>24</ref></p>
<p>Section 6, one-fourth of men must be in aetive service continuously, <ref>24</ref></p>
<p>Section 7, oath required..................................... <ref>24</ref></p>
<p>Section 8, pay of officers and privates.................. <ref>24</ref></p>
<p>Section 9, Court Martial, how and when convened.................. <ref>24</ref></p>
<p>Section 10, Governor to appoint a pay master.................. <ref>25</ref></p>
<p>Section 11, Ammunition, how furnished.................. <ref>25</ref></p>
<p>Section 12, present regiment turned over to the C. S. service....... <ref>25</ref></p>
<p>Disposition regimental property.............................. <ref>25</ref></p>
<p>Section 13, Governor to make necessary regulations tor government of the organization...................................... <ref>25</ref></p>
<p>Further provisions for defense of other counties, added.................. <ref>34</ref></p>
<p>Rank of Paymaster................................. <ref>34</ref></p>
<p>Frontier Regiment. Appropriation for support of, &#38;c.............................. <ref>16</ref></p>
<p>Turned over to C. S. service........................................ <ref>23</ref></p>
<p>Auditing and settling claims of the State against C. S. Government for defense of......................................... <ref>16</ref></p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">G</head>
<p>Gaming. See &#8220;Code, Penal.&#8221;</p>
<p>Glover, John C. For relief of............................................. <ref>42</ref></p>
<p>Guardian. To rent or hire property of their wards at public auction.................. <ref>12</ref></p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">H</head>
<p>Hospital. Appropriation for............................................. <ref>21</ref></p>
<p>Husband. Not to inform of an intention of his wife to commit treason, &#38;c....... <ref>13</ref></p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">I</head>
<p>Injunction. Judge of District Court may bear motions for dissolution of, and when.................. <ref>27</ref></p>
<p>Interest on R. R. Bonds. See &#8220;R. R. Companies.&#8221;</p>
<p>Iron. Military Board to provide for the manufacture of.................. <ref>36</ref></p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">J</head>
<p>Jails, County. Used for custody of deserters, &#38;c................................ <ref>4</ref></p>
<p>Judges, District. To hold special terms of court for criminal trials, &#38;c................... <ref>27</ref></p>
<p>Jurisdiction. See &#8220;Confederate States.&#8221;</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">L</head>
<p>Land. Donated to persons erecting manufactures, &#38;c. 22 For relief of owners of when sold for taxes.................. <ref>25</ref></p>
<p>Lands, University. See &#8220;University Lands.&#8221;</p>
<p>Legislature. See &#8220;Secretary of State.&#8221;</p>
<p>Legislature, 11th. Providing for the election of members to, in counties occupied by the public enemy.................. <ref>49</ref></p>
<p>Legal Notices.</p>
<p>Act regulating.................. <ref>37</ref></p>
<pb n="711" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="57" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<p>Library, State.</p>
<p>Secretary of State to have control of.......................... <ref>14</ref></p>
<p>Liquor.</p>
<p>Income tax upon sale of................................... <ref>16</ref></p>
<p>Lunatic Asylum.</p>
<p>Act organizing, amended.............................. <ref>43</ref></p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">M</head>
<p>Machinery. Money for purchase of to be raised by sale of cotton bonds.................. <ref>9</ref></p>
<p>Manufactures. Land donated to persons erecting....................................... <ref>22</ref></p>
<p>Militia. See &#8220;State Troops.&#8221;</p>
<p>Military Board. Reorganized.......................................... <ref>26</ref></p>
<p>To provide for manufacture of spinning jinnies.................. <ref>8</ref></p>
<p>To provide for the manufacture of iron.................. <ref>36</ref></p>
<p>Military Districts.</p>
<p>Frontier counties divided into.................................... <ref>24</ref></p>
<p>State brigaded.................. <ref>46</ref></p>
<p>Military Duty. Punishment for refusing to perform.................. <ref>48</ref></p>
<p>Punishment for encouraging others to refuse to perform.................. <ref>31</ref></p>
<p>Misprision of Treason.</p>
<p>See &#8220;Code, Penal.&#8221;</p>
<p>Mortgages. Effect of Stay Law on.................. <ref>6</ref></p>
<p>Mother. Not guilty for shielding a deserter.................. <ref>13</ref></p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">N</head>
<p>Notice, Legal.</p>
<p>Publication of regulated.................. <ref>37</ref></p>
<p>Nuisances.</p>
<p>Distilleries may be declared.................. <ref>48</ref></p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">O</head>
<p>Officers. See &#8220;Enrolling Officers.&#8221;</p>
<p>Officers, State. Termination of fiscal year......................................... <ref>35</ref></p>
<p>Officers, Non-Commissioned. Requesting Congress to increase the wages of.................................. <ref>51</ref></p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">P</head>
<p>Penal Code. See &#8220;Code.&#8221;</p>
<p>Penitentiary. Employment of additional labor therein.................. <ref>6</ref></p>
<p>Bond of Financial Agent................................... <ref>34</ref></p>
<p>Manner of paying officers of..................................... <ref>34</ref></p>
<p>Pensioners. Appropriations for................................................ <ref>42</ref></p>
<p>Percussion Caps. State Quartermaster to dispose of a certain amount.................. <ref>14</ref></p>
<p>President. Joint Resolution concerning.................. <ref>52</ref></p>
<p>Privates. Joint Resolution requesting Congress to increase the pay of.................. <ref>51</ref></p>
<p>Promissory Notes. Collection of suspended.......................... <ref>5</ref></p>
<p>Public Buildings. Certain ones to be re-covered............................. <ref>25</ref></p>
<p>Public Domain. For relief of settlers thereon......................................... <ref>4</ref></p>
<p>Location, survey and sale of suspended, except in certain cases........ <ref>15</ref></p>
<pb n="712" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="58" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<p>Public Printing.</p>
<p>Joint Resolution relating to................................ <ref>52</ref></p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">Q</head>
<p>Quarter Master, State. To dispose of certain caps.................................... <ref>14</ref></p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">R</head>
<p>Railroad Companies. Comptroller to receive interest due on their Bonds.................................. <ref>37</ref></p>
<p>Recognizances, &#38;c. Not forfeited in certain cases................................... <ref>10</ref></p>
<p>Renegades. Liabilities not affected by Stay Law................................... <ref>27</ref></p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">S</head>
<p>Secretary of State. Act of 1849, defining the duties of, amended.......................................... <ref>14</ref></p>
<p>Sedition. Act defining and punishing amended.................. <ref>20</ref></p>
<p>Sequestration. Writs of to issue in certain cases.................. <ref>6</ref></p>
<p>Settlers&#8217; Pre-Emption. For the relief of.......................... <ref>4</ref></p>
<p>Sheriffs.</p>
<p>Compensation of, for employing guards.................. <ref>36</ref></p>
<p>County Courts to regulate the pay of, in certain cases.................. <ref>11</ref></p>
<p>Enrolling Officers may call on them for assistance.................. <ref>11</ref></p>
<p>Punishment for refusing assistance.................. <ref>11</ref></p>
<p>Enrolling Officers.................. <ref>11</ref></p>
<p>Compensation for employing guards........................ <ref>36</ref></p>
<p>Soldiers.</p>
<p>Providing for the support of families and dependents of.................. <ref>21</ref></p>
<p>Former laws providing for the support of families and dependents of, amended.................. <ref>28</ref></p>
<p>Joint Resolution of thanks to............................ <ref>51</ref></p>
<p>Speculation.</p>
<p>Act to prevent speculation, of 1862, amended 3 Spinning Jennies.</p>
<p>Manufacture of provided for....................... <ref>8</ref></p>
<p>Stay Law.</p>
<p>Re-enacted.................. <ref>5</ref></p>
<p>Supplemented, and amended....................... <ref>26</ref></p>
<p>State.</p>
<p>To provide for defence of.................. <ref>44</ref></p>
<p>Section 1. Governor to continue Militia in the field.................. <ref>44</ref></p>
<p>Section 2. Militia now in the field to be enrolled.................. <ref>44</ref></p>
<p>Section 3. At the expiration of the time of service of the active Militia a re-organization to be had.................. <ref>44</ref></p>
<p>Sections 4 &#38; 5. Classification of.................. <ref>44</ref></p>
<p>Section 6. Punishment for persons refusing to perform duty......... <ref>45</ref></p>
<p>Section 7. Transferable to the Confederate service, and how...... <ref>45</ref></p>
<p>Section 8. Providing for the pay of.................. <ref>45</ref></p>
<p>Section 9. Disbanding does not destroy the organization of............. <ref>45</ref></p>
<p>Section 10. Persons having substitutes liable, when and how......... <ref>45</ref></p>
<p>State Troops.</p>
<p>Section 1. Who is exempt........................... <ref>46</ref></p>
<p>Section 2. Military division of the State.................. <ref>46</ref></p>
<p>Section 3. Appointment of General and Staff Officers.................. <ref>46</ref></p>
<p>Section 4. How ordered into active service.................. <ref>47</ref></p>
<p>Draft, how made.......................................... <ref>47</ref></p>
<p>Section 5. Organization and turning over of the drafted men........... <ref>47</ref></p>
<p>Section 6. Present Brigadier-Generals superceded.................. <ref>47</ref></p>
<p>Section 7. Appointment and compensation of Surgeons.................. <ref>47</ref></p>
<p>Section 8. Refusing to perform duty equivalent to desertion.............. <ref>48</ref></p>
<p>Section 9. Drill suspended&#8212;Enrolling Officers............................... <ref>48</ref></p>
<pb n="713" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="59" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<p>State Troops.</p>
<p>Section 10. Volunteer Exempt Companies encouraged.................. <ref>48</ref></p>
<p>Not to be marched, beyond the limits of their Brigade District.................. <ref>48</ref></p>
<p>Persons heretofore exempted to be re-examined.................. <ref>48</ref></p>
<p>Joint Resolution concerning pay of.............. <ref>51</ref></p>
<p>Suits.</p>
<p>In District Courts, where to be instituted................. <ref>10</ref></p>
<p>Sunday.</p>
<p>Offences Committed on punished.................. <ref>36</ref></p>
<p>Sugar Plantations.</p>
<p>Exempted, from Sunday law, in certain cases........................ <ref>36</ref></p>
<p>Supreme Court.</p>
<p>Of the Galveston District to hold its Spring term at Austin or else<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />where........................................ <ref>4</ref></p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">T</head>
<p>Taxes.</p>
<p>Income Taxes levied upon the sale of Distilled Spirits, &#38;c................... <ref>16</ref></p>
<p>Confederate Treasury notes the standard of valuation.................. <ref>18</ref></p>
<p>Portion of, donated for the support of families and dependents of soldiers......................................... <ref>22</ref></p>
<p>For the relief of the owners of Land sold for.................. <ref>25</ref></p>
<p>General Revenue Act................................ <ref>38</ref></p>
<p>Treason.</p>
<p>See &#8220;Code, Penal.&#8220;</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">U</head>
<p>University Lands. Further relief of purchasers of.............................. <ref>35</ref></p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">V</head>
<p>Venditioni Exponas. See &#8220;Stay Law.&#8220;</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">W</head>
<p>Wards. See &#8220;Guardians.&#8221;</p>
<p>War, The. Joint Resolution relating to........................... <ref>52</ref></p>
<p>Wages.</p>
<p>Of non-commissioned officers and privates requested to be increased.. <ref>51</ref></p>
<p>Wife.</p>
<p>Not to report intention of husband to commit treason, &#38;c................. <ref>13</ref></p>
<p>Not guilty when shielding deserter, and when............ <ref>31</ref></p>
<p>Wines, Foreign.</p>
<p>Income Tax levied upon............................................. <ref>16</ref></p>
</div3>
</div2>
<pb n="714" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="60" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">THE STATE OF TEXAS, Department of State.</head>
<p>I, Robert J. Townes, Secretary of State of the State of Texas, do certify that I have compared the foregoing Laws and Joint Resolutions of the Tenth Legisla<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ture with the originals now on file in the Department of State, and that they are true copies of such originals.</p>
<p>I further certify, that the Tenth Legislature of the Texas of Texas assembled on Monday, the second day of November, A. D. 1863, and adjourned on the six<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />teenth day of December, at 11 o&#8217;clock, P. M., of the same year.</p>
<p>In testimony whereof, I have hereunto signed my name, and caused the Seal of <floatingText rend="left"><body><p>[L. S.]</p></body></floatingText>the Department of State to be affixed, at Austin, this twelfth day of February, A. D. 1864.</p>
<closer>
<signed>E. J. TOWNES, Secretary of State.</signed>
</closer>
</div2>
</div1>
</body>
</text>