<text xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 UNTtite%20(1.3).xsd" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="TEI">
<body>
<pb n="759" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="1" />
<div1 type="article">
<head type="main">GENERAL AND SPECIAL <lb/>LAWS <lb/>OF THE <lb/>CALLED SESSION <lb/>TENTH LEGISLATURE <lb/>OF <lb/>THE STATE OF TEXAS</head>
<byline>HOUSTON 1864</byline>
<pb n="760" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="2" />
<pb n="761" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="3" />
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">GENERAL LAWS.</head>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER I.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to amend the 2d and 3d sections of an Act entitled &#8220;An Act to reorganize the 16th Judicial District and define the time of holding Courts therein, &#8220;ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />proved February 2d, 1861.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the 2d section of the above recited act be amended so as to read as follows: &#8220;The District Court shall be held twice in each year, in said District, as follows, to wit: In the County of Ellis on the 1st Mondays in March and September, in each year, and may continue in session two weeks; in the County of Johnson on the 3d Mondays in March and September, and may continue in session one week; in the County of Parker, on the 4th Mondays in March and September, and may continue in session two weeks; in the County of Tarrant, on the 2d Monday after the 4th Mondays in March and September, and may continue in session two weeks; in the County of Dallas, on the 4th Monday after the 4th Mondays in March and September, and may continue in session two weeks; in the County of Kaufman, on the 6th Monday after the 4th Mondays in March and September, and may continue in session two weeks; in the County of Van Zandt, on the 8th Monday after the 4th Mondays in March and September, and may continue in session until the business is disposed of.&#8221;</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That the third section of the act above recited be so amended as to read as follows: &#8220;That all writs and other process issued from the District Courts, of any of the counties named in this act, shall be made returnable to the terms of said Courts as established by this act, and all cases of appeals, or writs of error from judgments of the District Court in this District, shall be returnable to the Supreme Court at Austin, except the Counties of Kaufman and Van Zandt, which shall be returnable to the Supreme Court at Tyler.&#8221;</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That all laws conflicting herewith be, and the same are, hereby repealed, and that this act take effect, and be in force, from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>May 20th, 1864</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER II.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act making an appropriation to defray the Contingent Expenses of the Extra Session of the Tenth Legislature.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the sum of twenty thousand dollars, Confederate Treasury notes, or so much thereof as may be necessary, be, and the same is hereby appropriated to pay the contingent ex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />penses of the Extra Session of the Tenth Legislature.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this act take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>May 23d, 1864</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<pb n="762" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="4" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER III.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to reorganize the Seventeenth Judicial District and to prescribe the time for holding Courts therein.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Sev<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />enteenth Judicial District shall hereafter be composed of the Counties of William<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />son, Burnet, Llano, Mason, San Saba, McCulloch, Brown and Lampasas, and the District Court shall be held twice in each year, in each of said counties, as follows: In the County of Williamson, on the 1st Mondays in March and September, and may continue in session four weeks; in the County of Burnet, on the 4th Monday after the 1st Mondays in March and September, and may continue in session one week; in the County of Llano, on the 5th Monday after the 1st Mondays in March and September, and may continue in session one week; in the County of Mason, on the 6th Monday after the 1st Mondays in March and September, and may continue in session one week; in the County of San Saba, on the 7th Monday after the 1st Mondays in March and September, and may continue in session one week; in the County of McCulloch, on the 8th Monday after the 1st Mondays in March and Sep<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tember, and may continue in session one week; in the County of Brown, on the 9th Monday after the 1st Mondays in March and September, and may continue in ses<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sion one week; in the County of Lampasas, on the 10th Monday after the 1st Mon<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />days in March and September, and may continue in session until the business is dis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />posed of.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That all writs, and other process issued from the District Court of any of the counties named in this act, shall be made returnable to the terms of said Courts as established by this act.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That this act take effect from its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>May 23d, 1864</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER IV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to amend an Act entitled &#8220;An Act to amend an Act entitled an Act to or<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ganize County Courts.&#8221; Approved February 16th, 1862.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the first section of the above recited act be, and the same is hereby so amended as to read as follows:</p>
<p>&#8220;Section 20. The regular terms of the County Court shall commence and be held at the Court-house of each county, in this State, oh the last Monday in every month for the probate of wills, the granting of letters testamentary, of administration, and of guardianship, and the transaction of all business growing out of, or connected with the powers and jurisdiction of the County Courts, over executors, administra<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tors and guardians, and estates of deceased persons, minors, idiots, lunatics, and persons non compos mentis. Such terms shall be held by the Chief Justice, without the Assistance of any of the County Commissioners, and may be continued from day to day, for one week, but not longer; and the Chief Justice shall have the author<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ity to transact such business growing out of, or connected with such powers and jurisdiction, during the vacation between said terms of said court, as may be au<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />thorized by law.&#8221;</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this act be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>May 23d, 1864</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER V.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to prevent Slaves from exercising pretended ownership over property.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That it shall <pb n="763" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="5" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw> be unlawful for any slave owner to knowingly permit any slave to have, or exer<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cise, any pretended ownership or control, in his or her own right, over any horses, cattle, sheep or hogs, within this State. And where any such pretended right of ownership now exists, the master, or other person having the control of such slave, shall, within six months after the passage of this act, dispose of such property by sale or otherwise.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. The owner offending under the first section of this act, may be indicted and tried in the District Court, and upon conviction, shall be fined in any sum not exceeding the value of the horses, cattle, sheep, goats or hogs, over which such negro may exercise a pretended right of ownership, or on which such negro shall have a brand or ear mark.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That this act take effect and be in force from its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>May 26th, 1864</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER VI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to provide for the revision of the Laws.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Gov<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ernor be, and he is hereby authorized, to appoint a competent person to revise, di<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />gest, and arrange the Laws, Civil and Criminal, of this State.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That said Reviser shall, in performance of the duties imposed by this act, reduce the several subjects into proper chapters and sections, bringing into each chapter, as near as may be, a condensation of all the public laws appertaining to the subject treated in each chapter; that the Reviser shall not simply transfer the Statutes, but shall, (without changing the sense,) so alter their phraseology as to exclude all redundancy of expression; and where there shall be several acts relating to the same subject, they shall be condensed into one, and so expressed as clearly to set forth the sense of the whole, having regard to judicial expositions thereof; and he shall simplify and arrange, under distinct heads, the manner of procedure in the several Courts of this State.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That whenever it shall be apparent that there may be Legislative omis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sions in any Statute, said Reviser shall supply the same so as to perfect such Stat<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ute, and render its operations complete.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. That said Reviser shall prepare appropriate titles, and sub-divisions of titles for each chapter, clearly and briefly expressive of the subjects treated; also, shall make an index, for easy reference to the manuscript copy of the Code; shall add such marginal notes to the Acts as shall be proper for the clear elucidation of them, and for easy reference to the several laws from which he may compile, with references to the decisions of the Supreme Court, in which construction may be given to the acts.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. That said Reviser shall prepare said Code and report the same to the Gov<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ernor, whose duty it shall be, after said Code has been reported to him, to have at least two hundred copies of the same, together with the report of the Reviser, printed, and report the same to the Legislature as soon as practicable.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. That said Reviser shall have the right to take from the office of the Secre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tary of State, and the library of the Supreme Court, any books necessary for the performance of his duties under this act, upon giving his receipt therefor, and he shall be responsible for the return of the same within a reasonable time.</p>
<p>Sec. 7. That said Reviser shall receive for his services such compensation as the Legislature may bereafter provide.</p>
<p>Sec. 8. That this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>May 27, 1864</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
<pb n="764" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="6" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER VII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to regulate the reception and disposal of Confederate Notes and Bonds, now and hereafter, in the Treasury.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, as follows: After the last day of next June, Assessors and Collectors of Taxes, and other Re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />iceivers of funds for the State, or in its name, or for counties, shall not receive any Confederate notes of the old issue of the denomination of one hundred dollars: Provided, however, that the County Courts of the several counties, by order duly entered on the minutes thereof, either at regular or special terms, may fix any other day than the said last day of June after the passage of this act, and before the said last day of June, after which day so fixed, it shall not be lawful for any Assessor arid Collector to receive said notes in payment of any county taxes, and they may also require their Assessors and Collectors to pay over to the County Treasurer all such notes on or before that day.</p>
<p>All notes of this denomination, not bearing interest, and at the date aforesaid in the Treasury, or belonging to the State, shall be funded by the Comptroller ac<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cording to the provision therefor by the present or any future law of the Confed<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />erate States of America; and the Governor is authorized to make the necessary certificate to determine the notes to be so funded.</p>
<p>The bonds, obtained by such, funding, shall be deposited in the Treasury in sub<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />stitution for the notes so funded, and shall so remain until otherwise disposed of, either by future legislation or by sale, which may be made by a, Commission, con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sisting of the Governor, the Comptroller, and the Treasurer; but such sale shall not be made unless the Commission shall consider that it would be advantageous to the State; in which case the Commission may exchange the whole or any part of said bonds for any indebtedness of the State or for current treasury notes of the Confederacy of the new issues, in such manner as may be deemed best for the interest of the State.</p>
<p>All Confedrate treasury notes continued in circulation, or put therein as cur<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />rency, without being subjected to any provision for necessary funding, by a law now or hereafter made by the Confederate Congress, shall be recognized as the new issue of Confederate treasury notes, in contradistinction from all Confederate treasury notes, now or hereafter subjected to some provision of Confederate law for necessary funding, to be known as the old issue of Confederate treasury notes.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Confederate treasury notes, bearing interest, shall not be received for taxes or other public dues after the last day of next June; and all such notes, now or hereafter in the Treasury, shall so remain, or may be otherwise disposed of as provided in the first section for the disposal of bonds.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. Confederate treasury notes of the old issue, as defined in the first section, shall not be receivable at par for public dues after the last day of next June; but such notes, except those disposed of otherwise by the first and second sections, may be thereafter received for public dues until the last day of next October, in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cluding that day, but not longer, at the rate of three for two, or one-third less than the nominal amount; and all such notes now or hereafter in the Treasury, shall be exchanged for Confederate treasury notes of the new issue, as defined in the first section, according to the law for such exchange, and the Comptroller shall make such exchange of these notes as soon as may be conveniently done after their reception into the Treasury; provided such notes may be paid by the Treasurer on any warrant of the Comptroller at said rate of three for two, if the creditor be willing so to receive payment.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. Every law heretofore or hereafter provided, in general terms, for the re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ception or disbursement of Confederate treasury notes, shall be construed as em<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />bracing such notes of the new issue, and excluding those of the old issue, as de<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fined in the first section, and shall have corresponding effect.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. So far as any existing law may be incompatible with this act, such <pb n="765" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="7" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw> inconsistent law is suspended as to the subjects of this act, so that its provisions may be enforced as to its subjects without repealing the existing law as to other subjects.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. That this act shall be in force from its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>May 27, 1864</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER VIII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to punish unlawful interference with private property or private rights.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That if any person or persons shall, without lawful authority, take, molest or disturb, or cause to be taken, molested or disturbed the personal or moveable property of any person or persons in this State; or if any person or persons, without lawful authority, molest or disturb any person or persons in the free use and enjoyment of his, her or their personal or moveable property, or unlawfully cause any person to be molested or disturbed; or if any person or persons shall, without lawful authority, prevent or prohibit, or cause to be prevented or pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />hibited, any person from lawfully transporting, or exporting, or disposing of his, her or their personal or moveable property, by threats, force, exaction, or any other means whatever; or if any person or persons shall, under the semblance of legal order, or authority, unlawfully take, molest or disturb the personal or mov<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />able property of any person or persons, or by any means whatever interfere with, or cause to be interfered with, the free use, transportation, exportation or dis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />position of the same, or shall, in the exercise of lawful authority, act unlawfully or oppressively towards the owner thereof; he, she or they, thus offending, and every person in so offending, shall be deemed guilty of an offence, and, upon conviction, shall be fined in any sum not less than one hundred dollars, or by im<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />prisonment in the County Jail not longer than twelve months, or by confine<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment at hard labor in the Penitentiary for any term not less than two years, or by fine and imprisonment as aforesaid, at the discretion of the Jury.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. If any person shall violate any provision of the first section of this act, under the false pretence of acting under orders from lawful authority, when, in fact, he has no such orders, it shall be deemed an aggravation of the offence, and punished by fine of not less than two hundred dollars, or by confinement, at hard labor, in the Penitentiary not less than four years, or by fine and imprisonment as aforesaid, at the discretion of the Jury.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>May 28th, 1864</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER IX.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act making an appropriation to meet any deficiency that may accrue in the appropriation to pay the expenses of the Comptroller&#8217;s Department for the years 1864 and 1865.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the sum of live thousand dollars, or so much thereof as may be necessary, be and is hereby appropriated to meet any deficiency that may accrue in the appropria<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion made for paying the expenses of the Comptroller&#8217;s Department for the years 1864 and 1865.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. This act to take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>May 28th, 1864</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER X.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act supplemental to, and amendatory of &#8220;An Act to adopt and establish, a Penal Code.&#8221;</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the act above recited be amended by adding the following article to the same, to<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" /><pb n="766" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="8" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw> wit: &#8220;Article 348.A.&#8212;If any officer of the law shall wilfully or negligently fail to perform any duty imposed on him by the Penal Code, or Code of Criminal Pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cedure; he shall, when the act or omission is not otherwise defined, be deemed guilty of a misdemeanor, and punished as prescribed in Article 349 of this Code.&#8220;</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>May 28th, 1864</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to amend the third section of &#8220;An Act to provide for the support of the Families and Dependents of Texas Soldiers.&#8221; Approved December 15th, 1863.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, as follows, to<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />wit: That the third section of the above recited act be amended so as to read as follows, to-wit:</p>
<p>&#8220;Sec. 3. It shall be the duty of the Comptroller of the State, immediately after the passage of this act, to forward to the Chief Justice of each county in the State a copy of this act, with such instructions and forms as may be necessary to carry its provisions into effect, and the Chief Justices shall immediately upon the receipt of the Same, ascertain, or cause to be ascertained, in such manner as they may deem best, the number of indigent persons in their respective counties entitled to relief under this act, and shall make an accurate return of the same to the Comp<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />troller&#8217;s office, on or before the first day of September, 1864, and a like return shall be made, by them on or before the first day of March, 1865, which return shall be made officially, by the Chief Justices or County Commissioners (when the Chief Justices fail, refuse or neglect to act,) and they shall certify that the return is a just, time and correct return of all the dependents of Texas officers and soldiers, entitled to relief under this act, who are indigent and supported in whole or in part by the County Court, and that only such are therein returned, which certificates shall be signed by the officer or officers making the same and attested by the seal of the Court, and shall be considered as under oath.&#8221;</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That all laws and parts of laws, in conflict with this act, be repealed, and this Act take effect from its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>May 28th, 1864</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to furnish the Reporter of the Decisions of the Supreme Court Stationery.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Military Board of the State be authorized and required to furnish the Reporter of the Decisions of the Supreme Court with the stationery necessary to enable him to prepare the Decisions of said Court for publication.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this act take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>May 28th, 1864</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XIII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to authorize the Governor to appoint certain officers to represent the in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />terests of the State, and of the citizens and soldiers of the State, at the Head Quarters of the Trans-Mississippi Department, and at the Head Quarters of the District of Texas, New Mexico and Arizona.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Governor is authorized to appoint two persons, whose duty it shall be to keep the Governor advised of all matters of importance pertaining to the in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />terests of the State, that may occur at the Head Quarters of the Trans-Missis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sippi Department and at the Head Quarters of the District of Texas, New Mex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" /><pb n="767" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="9" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw> ico and Arizona; and to take in charge and represent the interests of the Sol<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />diers and Citizens of Texas, having business at said Head Quarters.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That the persons so appointed shall have the rank and pay of Colonels of cavalry in the Confederate States service, and shall be paid out of the appro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />priation made for the defense of the State by the Tenth Legislature.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. This act to be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>May 28th, 1864</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XIV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to further provide the manner of proving a written will.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That where the subscribing witnesses to a will are in the army, and beyond the limits of the State, said will may be probated, on proof, by two witnesses of the hand writing of the subscribing witnesses to said will, and also of the testator if he was able to write; which proof may be either by affidavit taken in open Court, and subscribed by the witness, or by deposition, and this act shall take effect from its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>May 28th, 1864</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act making an appropriation to pay for Stationery and Lighting Materials purchased for the 10th Legislature.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the sum of five hundred dollars in specie, or so much thereof as may be necessary, be, and the same is hereby appropriated, to pay for stationery and lighting ma<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />terial purchased for the use of the Tenth Legislature by Maj. S. Hart, said money to be paid on the presentation of the claim approved by the Secretary of State, Provided, that this appropriation may be paid out of any money subject to the control of the Governor or Military Board for any other purpose.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this act shall take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>May 28th, 1864</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XVI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act amending &#8220;An Act authorizing the Comptroller of the State to receive from Railroad Companies in this State the interest that may now be due, or hereafter become due on their Bonds.&#8221;</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the provisions of the Act, of which this is amendatory, shall not apply to Railroad Companies that fail or refuse to receive State Bonds or State Treasury Warrants at par for freight or passage, at the prices or rates established by law.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That whenever satisfactory evidence is produced or furnished to the Comptroller of the State that any Railroad Company has failed or refused to re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ceive the State Bonds or State Treasury Warrants at par, for freights or passage, at the rates established by law, he is required to refuse to receive the State Bonds or Treasury Warrants for the interest due by said Railroad upon its Bond.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That the President of any Railroad in this State be, and is hereby required to post in a conspicuous place in the Railroad offices, and in the passenger cars, the provisions and terms of this act, under a penalty of one hundred dollars, to be recovered for the benefit of the State, by suit before any Court of competent jurisdiction upon the information of any party.</p>
<pb n="768" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="10" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<p>Sec. 4. That all laws or parts of laws conflicting with this act, be, and the same are hereby repealed, and that this act take effect from and after its passsage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>May 28th, 1864</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XVII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to make an additional appropriation for the support of the Lunatic Asylum for the years 1864 and 1865.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That in addition to the unexpended balance of the appropriation made at the last regu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lar session of the 10th Legislature, for the support of the Lunatic Asylum for the years 1864 and 1865, the further sum of one hundred and fifty thousand dol<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lars, or so much thereof as may be necessary, be, and the same is hereby appro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />priated for the support of said Asylum for the years 1864 and 1865.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>May 28th, 1864</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XVIII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to regulate the disposal of unappropriated Specie.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, as follows: Any unappropriated specie that may be in the Treasury, from time to time, on any account, shall not be paid nor withdrawn therefrom, except by specific appropria<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tions therefor; and this provision is explanatory of laws making general appro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />priations.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. This act shall be in force from its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>May 28th, 1864</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER SIX.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to regulate the manner of liquidating claims for payment under appropria<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tions made by the Legislature.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted, by the Legislature of the State of Texas, as follows: For liquidating tie appropriations which have been or may be made by the Tenth Legislature of the State, for support during the years 1864 and 1865, of the civil departments of the Government of the State, and of families and other dependents of Texan officers and soldiers in military service of the State, and of the Confederate States of America, and for payment of the Adjutant and Inspector General, and the Quartermaster, and all employees of their Departments, and for the payment of the superintendents and employees of all public offices and works conducted by the State, and for the general support of the public asylums, the Comptroller shall draw Warrants on the Treasurer as prescribed by &#8220;An Act to repeal An Act author<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />izing unpaid Warrants to draw interest, approved February 14, 1860, and other<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />wise to regulate the issuance of Treasury Warrants, approved January 10, 1862, for want of appropriate funds for payment.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. For liquidating appropriations in general, except those specified in the first section, and those specifically providing for payment in specie, the comp<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />troller shall draw Warrants on the Treasurer, payable in Confederate treasury notes of the new issue; Provided, when there shall not be such notes in the Treasury, such Warrants may be paid in Confederate Treasury notes of the old issue, at the rate of three dollars for two, or in bank notes at par, if the payee be willing so to receive payment.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. In the same manner, and to the same extent that Treasury War<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />rants in general may be receivable for public dues, under the laws now or here<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" /><pb n="769" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="11" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw> after providing therefor, the Treasury Warrants to be issued under the first sec<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion of this act, shall be receivable for all public dues, except those payable in specie by special provision of law; and in addition, after twelve months from ratification of a treaty of peace between the Confederate States of America and the United States of America, these Warrants may be funded in Bonds of the State, bearing interest at the rate of six per centum per annum, to be paid semi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />annually, the interest and principal of the Bonds being payable in specie; but no Bonds shall be issued, nor tax assessed for the payment of interest or principal thereof, until the expiration of the term aforesaid.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. Whenever there shall be a surplus of specie in the Treasury, (beyond special appropriations for such funds, subject to appropriations for general pur<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />poses, or for the purpose specified in this section, to the amount of thirty thousand dollars, the Governor shall cause the same to be applied to the purchase of Treasury Warrants, issued under the first section of this act, at the lowest prices offered, after advertisements for bids for six consecutive weeks in some three newspapers in the State, published at different places, and having, large circula<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. So far as any existing law may be incompatible with this act, such in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />consistent law is suspended as to the subjects of this act, so that its provisions may be enforced as to its subjects without repealing the existing law as to other subjects.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. This act shall be in force from its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>May 28th, 1864</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XX.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to appropriate portions of the Specie Funds that have been or may be<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />received from sales of Cotton belonging to the State.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That in case there is not sufficient specie funds in the Treasury, accruing from sources now provided by law, to pay the interest on the Public Debt of the State, from time to time, when said interest becomes due, the Governor is authorized and required to use for the payment of said interest, such specie funds as he may have under his control, belonging to the State, accruing for the sale of State cotton, or otherwise, and required to take such steps and adopt such measures as will secure the payment of said interest promptly, as it becomes due.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That after retaining in the Treasury a sufficient amount of specie, arising from the sale of cotton belonging to the State, to pay the interest on the Bonds of the State outstanding, from time to time, as it accrues, the remainder of the specie so acquired shall be applied to the purchase and liquidation of the Treasury War<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />Pants of the State, authorized to be issued by the present session of the 10th Legislature, except so much as may be necessary to purchase arms and ammunition for the frontier organization; and all laws and parts of laws conflicting with this act be, and the same are hereby repealed.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. This act to take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>May 28th, 1864</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act making an appreciation for the Mileage and Per Diem Pay of the Mem<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />bers and the Per Diem Pay of the Officers of the Extra Session of the Tenth Legislature of the State of Texas.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, Tha the sum of fifty thousand dollars, or so much thereof as may be necessary, be, and <pb n="770" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="12" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw> the same, is hereby appropriated, out of any money in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated, for the mileage and per diem pay of the members, and the per diem pay of the officers, of the extra session of the Tenth Legislature.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That the certificate of the Secretary of the Senate, and the certificate of the Chief Clerk of the House, shall be sufficient evidence to the Comptroller, upon which he shall audit the claims and draw his warrants upon the Treasury for the respective amounts.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. This act to take effect and be in force from and after its passage</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>May 28th, 1864</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to transfer the State Troops to the Confederate States service, and to re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />peal an Act entitled &#8220;An Act to provide for the defense of the State,&#8221; approved December 16th, 1863.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That an act entitled &#8220;an act to provide for the defense of the State,&#8221; approved Decem<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ber 16th, 1863, be and the same is hereby repealed, and that the State troops, or<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ganized under said act be, and the same are hereby transferred to the military service of the Confederate States, to be organized in accordance with the laws of Congress; provided, that nothing herein contained shall be so construed as to turn over to the Confederate military authorities any officer of the State Government or other person not subject to conscription under the laws of Congress.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this act take effect from its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>May 28th, 1864</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXIII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to relinquish the right of the State to forty-seven hundred dollars, now in the hands of Colonel J. E. McCord, commanding the Frontier Regiment, the proceeds of sales of property, captured by said regiment from Indians while in the State service, and authorizing said McCord to hold said money as a hospital fund for said regiment.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the State of Texas hereby relinquishes all right and claim to the money, amount<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing to forty-seven Hundred dollars, the proceeds of the sale of property, captured by the Frontier Regiment from the Indians, while in the service of the State, and that Col. James E. McCord, commanding said regiment, be, and he is hereby au<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />thorized to hold said money as a hospital fund for said regiment.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this act take effect from its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>May 28th, 1864</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXIV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to define and punish the unlawful interference with the exportation and transportation of Cotton, or other articles, and the unlawful impressment of property.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That if any person or persons within this State, in any manner not sanctioned by a law of the Confederate Congress, shall establish, or attempt to establish, any re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />strictions, or impose any tax or duty upon the exportation or transportation of cotton, or other article, from the State of Texas, or shall unlawfully issue, pur<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />chase or sell any paper or instrument of writing, known as a permit to export cotton, shall be deemed guilty of an offence, and, upon conviction thereof, shall he punished by fine, in any sum not exceeding the value of the cotton or other <pb n="771" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="13" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw> article so taxed, or embraced in such permit, or by confinement in the County jail not exceeding one year: Provided, that parties who have in good faith, purchased exemptions for the transportation of cotton, and turned over to the military au<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />thorities of the Trans-Mississippi Department a portion of their cotton, to secure the same, where the same has been done previous to this act, shall not be held liable to the pains and penalties herein contained, for the use of the said permits, in conformity with the contract under which they were granted.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. If any person or persons shall in any manner, not sanctioned by law im<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />press or attempt to impress any property within the State of Texas, for any pur<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pose whatever, or shall aid, assist, encourage, order or abet any person or persons iso to do; or having impressed any property, shall fail or refuse to pay a just compensation for the same, or give such evidence of the impressment as required by law, such person or persons shall be deemed guilty of an offence, and, on con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />viction thereof, shall be punished by fine, not exceeding double the value of the property, and confinement in the County Jail for a period not exceeding one year at the discretion of the Jury. And it shall be the duty of the Judges of the Dis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />trict Courts to give this act specially in charge to the Grand Jury</p>
<p>Sec. 3. Prosecutions for offences, committed under this act, may be commenced in any county in which the offender is found, or in which such tax or restrictions are enforced, or attempted to be enforced.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. That in addition to the penalty imposed in the first section of this act any person or persons, guilty of the offence therein defined, shall be liable to a civil action for damages, by any person affected: thereby, to be prosecuted in any county where the plaintiff may reside, or if a non-resident plaintiff, in any county where the offence was committed, or the damage sustained</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>May 31st, 1864</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act supplementary to &#8220;An Act to provide for the protection of the Frontier, and turning over the Frontier Regiment to the Confederate States service.&#8221; Ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />proved December 15th, 1863.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Governor of the State shall cause to be enrolled into the companies already organized within the Frontier Districts, all persons between the ages of seventeen and eighteen years of age.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That should the Confederate military authorities authorize the with<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />drawal of the reserve corps from field and camps, and the persons in the State composing the reserve corps, be allowed by such authority to return to their homes, either permanently or temporarily, the Governor shall direct the same course to be pursued towards persons of like age in the frontier organization; pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vided, such persons shall hold themselves in readiness to repair to their respective companies when ordered.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That, in each one of the Frontier Districts there shall be organized, under the direction of the Governor, a provost guard, to consist of not exceeding two companies of sixty-four men each, rank and file, for constant duty. That the companies so organized, shall he armed by the State, and shall be placed on the same footing as to pay, rations and everything else as Confederate State troops.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. That the pay of officers and privates of this organization, except that of the provost guards, while engaged in actual service, shall be the same as pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vided for in the act to which this is supplementary.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. That fractions of companies of less than twenty-five men may <pb n="772" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="14" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw> be attached to and become parts of companies hereafter organized, and so much of the act, to which this is supplemental, as restricts companies to sixty-four men rank and file, is hereby repealed.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. That the Governor cause to be furnished to the commanding officers of the Frontier Districts such stationery, camp and garrison equipage, and transporta<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion as may be actually necessary.</p>
<p>Sec. 7. That in addition to the oath heretofore required, the officers and men of this organization shall swear allegiance to the Confederate and State Govern<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ments, to obey the Constitutions and laws thereof, and to obey the orders of their superior officers.</p>
<p>Sec. 8. That in the event of an invasion, by the enemy, of any part of the frontier or of any portion of the State contiguous thereto, the Governor shall have authority to order out the entire force of this organization or any part thereof, for such length of time as he may judge necessary, to aid in repelling such invasion. In the event any such contingency should occur, and extraordinary ex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />penditure be incurred, the same shall be paid out of the general appropriation made by the First Session of the Tenth Legislature for the defence of the State.</p>
<p>Sec. 9. That whenever the Governor deems it proper, he snall assign to duty within the limits of the Frontier District such of the State Brigadier-Generals as may be necessary, to make more efficient the frontier organization. When any such officer is so assigned to duty, he shall make his Headquarters within the limits of his command, at such point as will keep him in direct communication with all the forces of the frontier.</p>
<p>Sec. 10. This act shall be in force from its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>May 31st, 1864</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
</div2>
<pb n="773" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="15" />
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">JOINT RESOLUTIONS.</head>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER I.</head>
<opener>
<salute>Joint Resolution in regard to the manufacture of Salt.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Whereas, the Conscript Bureau of this Department has decided, that Salt makers, between the ages of eighteen and forty-five years of age, are not entitled to de<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tails, under the operations of the recent Acts of Congress:</p>
<p>1. Be it resolved by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That Gen. E. Kirby Smith, commanding the Trans-Mississippi Department, be requested to grant de<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tails in the State of Texas, of such persons liable to conscription, as may be now, or hereafter, engaged as superintendents in the manufacture of Salt, to the extent of twenty bushels per day.</p>
<p>2. Resolved That the Governor is hereby requested to furnish Gen. Smith with a copy of this resolution.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>May 20th, 1864</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER II.</head>
<opener>
<salute>Joint Resolution.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Resolved by the Legislature of the State of Texas: 1st. That so soon as the Governor has assurances from Gen. Smith of the frontier organization of this State remaining undisturbed, it shall be his duty to cause all persons within the Frontier District, between the ages of eighteen and forty-five years, who were not residents of said district, prior to July, eighteeen hundred and sixty-three, to be immediately turned over to the nearest Confederate military authority.</p>
<p>2d. That the Governor issue his proclamation forbidding the immigration to, and settlement in, any of the unorganized counties of this State; and after such proclamation, any person so offending, during the present war with the United States, shall become liable to conscription; and it shall be the duty of the officers of the frontier organization to arrest such persons, and turn them over to the Confederate States military authorities.</p>
<p>3d. That the Governor be required to take immediate steps to lay before Gen. E. Kirby Smith the late orders of the officers of the Bureau of Conscription, in regard to the enrollment and conscription of the frontier organization; and to ask of Gen. Smith that the said organization be left under the control and manage<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment of the State authorities; and, further, to request that all orders heretofore issued by the officers of conscription, in regard to the conscription of this organiza<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion, be withdrawn.</p>
<p>4th. That the Governor make such arrangements with Gen. Smith as he may be able to do, for the payment, subsistence, &#38;c., of the frontier organization, pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vided the forces so organized are not to be withdrawn from the control of the Governor, and the officers appointed by him.</p>
<p>5th. That the Governor be authorized to make such other arrange<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ments with Gen. Smith as will insure the harmonious and energetic action of the <pb n="774" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="16" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw> Confederate military authorities and the officers of the frontier organization, when<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ever it may be necessary for them to act in conjunction.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>May 24th, 1864</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER III.</head>
<opener>
<salute>Joint Resolution.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Whereas, information has been received of the destitute condition of many of our wounded and sick soldiers, citizens of Texas, now in the army of Arkansas and Louisiana: Therefore,</p>
<p>1. Be it resolved by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Governor is hereby authorized to send a commissioner to each of the above named States, with funds for the relief of all destitute, sick and wounded soldiers from Texas, now in the Confederate army. in the above, named States.</p>
<p>2d. The Governor is hereby authorized to use such amount as may be necessary for the object to be attained by these resolutions, of the fund heretofore appro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />priated as the hospital fund.</p>
<p>3d. The commissioners, appointed by these resolutions, may not only be re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />quired to offer material aid to the said sick and wounded while in hospital, but may be authorized, in all proper eases, to furnish transportation to them to their respective homes.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>May 26th 1864</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER IV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>Joint Resolutions concerning the Acts of the Confederate Congress, to regulate impressments, and abuses under the same.</salute>
</opener>
<p>1st. Be it resolved by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Constitu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion of the Confederate States, having provided that &#8220;private property shall not be taken for public use, without just compensation,&#8221; and the Constitution of this State having provided, that &#8220;no property shall be taken or applied to public use, without adequate compensation,&#8221; it is believed by this Legislature, that the Congress of the Confederate States could not have intended, in the enactment of the acts, to regulate impressments, to cause to be paid to individuals, less than the fair and current market value of their property, seized for the use of the Gov<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ernment.</p>
<p>2. That the valuation of the property so seized, should be in the currency in which payment is made, and ought to be controlled by the fair value of the article seized, in the local market where the seizure is made.</p>
<p>3d. That the schedule of prices, heretofore published in this State, are notori<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ously below the market value of the articles set forth in such schedules, and com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pensation for the same, at those rates, is neither just nor adequate.</p>
<p>4th. That the uniform appraisement of every article, at the same price in every part of the State, or in districts of the State, thus disregarding the cost and consequent increased value which transportation adds to commodities, is mani<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />festly unjust.</p>
<p>5th. That the first section of the original &#8220;Act to regulate impressments, &#8220;au<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />thorized impressments of &#8220;forage, articles of subsistence, or other property,&#8221; only when such articles are &#8220;absolutely necessary for the exigencies of the army in the field,&#8221; and the seventh section of said act, exempted from impressment, all &#8220;prop<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />erty necessary for the support of the owner and his family, and to carry on his or<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dinary agricultural and mechanical business,&#8221; yet these plain requirements of the law have been frequently and grievously violated by persons acting under color of authority of the Confederate States, as this Legislature is well informed.</p>
<p>6th. That in some sections of our country there is a great scarcity of bread<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" /><pb n="775" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="17" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw> stuffs, and other family necessaries, and when efforts have been made to transport such articles, to supply such needful wants of our people, the teams and supplies have been unwarrantably impressed. This practice should be forbidden by positive law, or an imperative order from officers having the authority to correct the evil.</p>
<p>7th. That the Governor communicate these resolutions to the Confederate au<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />thorities.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>May 27th, 1864</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER V.</head>
<opener>
<salute>Joint Resolution.</salute>
</opener>
<p>1st. Be it resolved by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That no officer of a sovereign State can be placed in the military service of the Confederate States, without his consent; that the claim of a right in Congress to conscribe certain classes of officers, is contrary to the theory of our Government, and if allowed will render the term of all officers subject to the action of Congress, and State officers will exercise their functions at the will and pleasure of Congress, and not under the Constitution and laws of their State.</p>
<p>2d. That the Governor of the State be and he is hereby authorized and re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />quested to issue his proclamation, in accordance with the foregoing resolution, de<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />claring that all civil officers, elected or appointed in accordance with the Consti<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tution and laws of the State, are necessary to carry on the State Government, and are not liable to military duty in the Confederate States army.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>May 28th, 1864</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER VI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>Joint Resolution.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Resolved by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Secretary of State be required to have published, with the volumes of the General Laws of this ses<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sion, the Constitution of the State and of the Confederate States.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>May 28th 1864</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER VII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>Joint Resolutions requesting the return of the 1st, 4th and 5th Texas Regiments.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Whereas, The troops comprising the various companies, battalions and regiments of Texas, serving east of the Mississippi river have become, from long and arduous services, greatly reduced in number, and in many instances the organization being almost destroyed; And, whereas, this gallant soldiery have served their country with so much fidelity and uncomplaining firmness&#8212;</p>
<p>Therefore, be it Resolved. 1st. That our gratitude as a people is due the brave men who have so long represented Texas on the many battlefields of the revolu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion.</p>
<p>2d. That we mourn the death of those whose lives have been offered as willing sacrifices upon the altar of freedom.</p>
<p>3d. That we return our grateful thanks to those who still survive for their sacrifices and gallantry, and tender our assurances that the deeds of the living and the dead are appreciated in our heart of hearts, and will be enshrined there by a grateful people as long as there remains on earth, in the minds of men, admira<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion for deeds of heroism, devotion to country, and a love of liberty.</p>
<p>4th. That we most respectfully ask of our military authorities to permit the <pb n="776" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="18" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw> various companies, battalions and regiments of Texas troops, east of the Missis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sippi river, to return home for the purpose of recruiting their decimated ranks, at such time and in such manner as will be prudent, when the public service will permit.</p>
<p>5th. That a copy of these resolutions be forwarded to the Secretary of War, and to the various Brigade Commanders of Texas troops, east of the Mississippi, by the Governor, at the earliest practicable moment.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>May 28th, 1864</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER VIII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>Joint Resolution.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Be it resolved by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That, approving, as we do, the Legislation of Congress, tending to strengthen the effective force of the army, by requiring all clerks and employees, who are able to perform active mili<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tary duty, to be placed in the ranks, and their places supplied by crippled soldiers, or persons unfit for active duty in the field, and though various military orders have been issued, to enforce the law of Congress upon the subject, we find the orders are disregarded.</p>
<p>Resolved further, That in the name and in behalf of the people of the State, we do most solemnly appeal to the authorities, to arrest the many flagrant violations of law and army regulations, so palpable to every observing man. If the confidence of the soldiers and people of the State be necessary, in this hour of peril and danger, it can only be held and maintained by changing the present course of proceedings. Put the stout and able men in the field, stop the extravagant and improvident use of the public property, put all but cripples out of an ambulance and four mules, with a white soldier driver; send experienced practical men to make improvements where necessary, and let the people feel and realize, that the cause in which we are engaged is common, demanding a hearty and willing co-operation of all.</p>
<p>Resolved, That the Governor cause a copy of the foregoing resolutions to be forwarded to Gen. E. Kirby Smith, and to Major General Magruder, commander of the District of Texas, New Mexico and Arizona, and to the commanders of the several Sub-Military Districts of the District of Texas and to our members in the Confederate Congress.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Passed <date>May 28th, 1864</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER IX.</head>
<opener>
<salute>Joint Resolution.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Resolved, by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That each and every mem<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ber of the Legislature and officer now in attendance, may receive from the Mili<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tary Board two pair of Cards each, upon the payment, to said board, of the cost and carriage upon the same: Provided such disposition of the Cards can be made without detriment to the pre-existing engagements.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Passed <date>May 28th, 1864</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
</div2>
<pb n="777" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="19" />
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">INDEX TO GENERAL LAWS.</head>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">A</head>
<p>Appropriations,</p>
<p>Contingent expenses, Extra Session Tenth Legislature, in Confederate Notes ..................................... <ref>3</ref></p>
<p>Further for Comptroller's Department ................ <ref>7</ref></p>
<p>For Stationery, &#38;c., for Tenth Legislature, in Specie.................. <ref>9</ref></p>
<p>Additional for support of Lunatic Asylum ......................... <ref>10</ref></p>
<p>Special, necessary to draw specie from the treasury................ <ref>10</ref></p>
<p>Manner of liquidating ctaims under .................... <ref>10</ref></p>
<p>A part of the proceeds from sale of cotton appropriated................. <ref>11</ref></p>
<p>For sick and wounded soldiers in the army of Arkansas and Louisiana <ref>16</ref></p>
<p>Mileage and Per Diem, Extra Session Tenth Legislature................ <ref>11</ref></p>
<p>Asylum, Lunatic,</p>
<p>Further appropriation for support of..................... <ref>10</ref></p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">B</head>
<p>Bonds of Railroad Companies.</p>
<p>See &#8220;Railroad Companies.&#8221;</p>
<p>Bonds, State,</p>
<p>Providing for the payment of the interest on................... <ref>11</ref></p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">C</head>
<p>Cards,</p>
<p>To be sold to certain officers........................... <ref>18</ref></p>
<p>Civil Departments,</p>
<p>Appropriations for support of, to be paid in Treasury Warrants..... <ref>10</ref></p>
<p>Code, Penal,</p>
<p>Article 348a added. Punishment affixed for the willful neglect of official duties .............................. <ref>7</ref></p>
<p>Punishment affixed for unlawful interference with private rights and property ............................. <ref>7</ref></p>
<p>Punishment affixed for unlawful interference with the exportation and transportation of cotton ............................... <ref>12</ref></p>
<p>Confederate Notes and Bonds,</p>
<p>Reception into, and disposal of, from Treasury regulated.................. <ref>6</ref></p>
<p>Conscription,</p>
<p>Joint resolution concerning the conscribing of officers................... <ref>17</ref></p>
<p>Constitution,</p>
<p>Of State and Confederacy, to be printed............................. <ref>17</ref></p>
<p>Cotton,</p>
<p>Portion of the proceeds from sale of, appropriated...................... <ref>11</ref></p>
<p>Unlawful interference with the exportation and transportation of, punished .................................. <ref>12</ref></p>
<p>County Courts,</p>
<p>Act organizing amended ................................ <ref>4</ref></p>
<p>Courts, District,</p>
<p>The time of holding Courts in the 16th District defined............... <ref>3</ref></p>
<p>The time of holding Courts in, defined, and reorganization of 17th District .................................. <ref>4</ref></p>
</div3>
<pb n="778" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="20" /><fw type="header" place="top">Index.</fw>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">D</head>
<p>District Court, See &#8220;Courts.&#8221;</p>
<p>Defence of the State, See &#8220;State.&#8220;</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">F</head>
<p>Frontier, Supplemental Act to provide for defence of................................... <ref>13</ref></p>
<p>Section 1, all persons between the ages of 17 and 18 years to be en<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />rolled.............................................</p>
<p>Section 2, furloughs to be given in the same manner as they are in future to be granted to the Reserve Corps..............................</p>
<p>Section 3, provides for the disposition of the Reserve Corps in the Fron<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tier Organization of, &#38;c............................</p>
<p>Section 4, Provost Guards organized.....................</p>
<p>Section 5, repeals former clause restricting number of men in com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />panies....................................</p>
<p>Section 6, Stationery, &#38;c., furnished officers of............................</p>
<p>Section 7, the Oath required........................................</p>
<p>Section 8, gives the Governor authority to order into the field said or<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ganization......................</p>
<p>Section 9, Governor may assign a State Brigadier General to duty on the Frontier..........................</p>
<p>Governor to issue his proclamation, forbidding the settlement in the unorganized counties of................................... <ref>15</ref></p>
<p>Governor to make arrangements for the retention of said organization <ref>15</ref></p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">G</head>
<p>Governor of the State, Joint Resolution in relation to................................... <ref>15</ref></p>
<p>To appoint a competent person to revise the laws................................... <ref>5</ref></p>
<p>To appoint officers to represent the interests of Texans at Military Head Quarters................................... <ref>8</ref></p>
<p>To appoint Commissioners to visit the sick and wounded soldiers in Arkansas and Louisiana................................... <ref>16</ref></p>
<p>See &#8220;Frontier.&#8220;</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">H</head>
<p>Hand Writing, Of Testator and subscribing witnesses to a will, bow proven.................. <ref>9</ref></p>
<p>Head Quarters Military Districts, Representatives to be appointed to represent Texans at................ <ref>8</ref></p>
<p>Hospital Fund, Money relinquished to the Frontier Regiment for.................. <ref>12</ref></p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">I</head>
<p>Impressments, Punishments for interference with private rights and private property <ref>7</ref></p>
<p>Punishment for unlawful................................... <ref>12</ref></p>
<p>Joint Resolution in relation to................................... <ref>16</ref></p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">L</head>
<p>Laws, A revision of, provided for................................... <ref>5</ref></p>
<p>Lunatic Asylum, See &#8220;Asylum.&#8221;</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">O</head>
<p>Officers, State, Punishment for willful omission of................................... <ref>7</ref></p>
<p>Not liable to conscription................................... <ref>17</ref></p>
<p>Officers, Army. Joint Resolution in relation to the employees of................................... <ref>18</ref></p>
</div3>
<pb n="779" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="21" /><fw type="header" place="top">Index.</fw>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">D</head>
<p>District Court, See &#8220;Courts.&#8221;</p>
<p>Defence of the State, See &#8220;State.&#8220;</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">F</head>
<p>Frontier, Supplemental Act to provide for defence of................................... <ref>13</ref></p>
<p>Section 1, all persons between the ages of 17 and 18 years to be en<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />rolled.........................................</p>
<p>Section 2, furloughs to be given in the same manner as they are in future to be granted to the Reserve Corps...........................................</p>
<p>Section 3, provides for the disposition of the Reserve Corps in the Fron<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tier Organization of, &#38;c.................................</p>
<p>Section 4, Provost Guards organized....................................</p>
<p>Section 5, repeals former clause restricting number of men in com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />panies..............................</p>
<p>Section 6, Stationery, &#38;c., furnished officers of............................................</p>
<p>Section 7, the Oath required.................................................</p>
<p>Section 8, gives the Governor authority to order into the field said or<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ganization..........................................</p>
<p>Section 9, Governor may assign a State Brigadier General to duty on the Frontier...................................</p>
<p>Governor to issue his proclamation, forbidding the settlement in the unorganized counties of................................... <ref>15</ref></p>
<p>Governor to make arrangements for the retention of said organization <ref>15</ref></p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">G</head>
<p>Governor of the State, Joint Resolution in relation to................................... <ref>15</ref></p>
<p>To appoint a competent person to revise the laws................... <ref>5</ref></p>
<p>To appoint officers to represent the interests of Texans at Military Head Quarters................................... <ref>8</ref></p>
<p>To appoint Commissioners to visit the sick and wounded soldiers in Arkansas and Louisiana................................... <ref>16</ref></p>
<p>See &#8220;Frontier.&#8220;</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">H</head>
<p>Hand Writing, Of Testator and subscribing witnesses to a will, how proven.................... <ref>9</ref></p>
<p>Head Quarters Military Districts, Representatives to be appointed to represent Texans at.................. <ref>8</ref></p>
<p>Hospital Fund, Money relinquished to the Frontier Regiment for...................... <ref>12</ref></p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">I</head>
<p>Impressments, Punishments for interference with private rights and private property................................... <ref>7</ref></p>
<p>Punishment for unlawful............................</p>
<p>Joint Resolution in relation to................................... <ref>16</ref></p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">L</head>
<p>Laws, A revision of, provided for................................... <ref>5</ref></p>
<p>Lunatic Asylum, See &#8220;Asylum.&#8221;</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">O</head>
<p>Officers, State, Punishment for willful omission of................................... <ref>7</ref></p>
<p>Not liable to conscription................................... <ref>17</ref></p>
<p>Officers, Army, Joint Resolution in relation to the employees of................................... <ref>18</ref></p>
</div3>
<pb n="780" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="22" /><fw type="header" place="top">Index.</fw>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">P</head>
<p>Permits for Exportation of Cotton, Punishment for granting, buying or selling....................... <ref>12</ref></p>
<p>Penal Code, See &#8220;Code, Penal.&#8221;</p>
<p>Property, Pretended ownership over not to be exercised by a slave....................... <ref>4</ref></p>
<p>Unlawful interference with, punished...................... <ref>7</ref></p>
<p>Valuation of, when impressed................................... <ref>16</ref></p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">R</head>
<p>Railroad Companies, Act amended, authorizing the reception of interest on the Bonds of... <ref>9</ref></p>
<p>Regiments, 1st, 4th and 5th, Return of requested................................... <ref>17</ref></p>
<p>Reporter of the Decisions of the Supreme Court, To be furnished Stationery................................... <ref>8</ref></p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">S</head>
<p>Salt Makers, Joint Resolution regulating the detail of................................... <ref>15</ref></p>
<p>Slaves, Prevented from exercising pretended ownership over property....... <ref>4</ref></p>
<p>Soldiers, Act providing for the support of families and dependents of, amended. <ref>8</ref></p>
<p>Appropriations for, to be paid in Treasury Warrants................................... <ref>16</ref></p>
<p>Joint Resolution to provide for the relief of the sick and wounded in Arkansas and Louisiana................................... <ref>16</ref></p>
<p>Return of soldiers east of the Mississippi River requested............... <ref>17</ref></p>
<p>Specie, The disposal of unappropriated, regulated................................... <ref>10</ref></p>
<p>Surplus of, to be used for buying Treasury Warrants................................... <ref>11</ref></p>
<p>Part of, arising from sale of cotton, appropriated as a sinking fund, &#38;c............................................ <ref>11</ref></p>
<p>State, Right of to certain money, relinquished................................... <ref>12</ref></p>
<p>State Bonds, See &#8220;Bonds.&#8221;</p>
<p>State, Defence of, Act providing for, repealed................................... <ref>12</ref></p>
<p>State Troops, Transferred to Confederate State service................................... <ref>12</ref></p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">T</head>
<p>Taxes, In what funds to be collected................................... <ref>6</ref></p>
<p>Treasury Warrants, To be issued and for what purposes................................... <ref>10</ref></p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">W</head>
<p>Will Manner of proving................................... <ref>9</ref></p>
</div3>
</div2>
<pb n="780" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="22" />
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">THE STATE OE TEXAS, Department of State.</head>
<p>I, Robert J. Townes, Secretary of State of the State of Texas, do certify that I have compared the foregoing Laws and Joint Resolutions of the Extra Session of the Tenth Legislature with the originals now on file in this Department, and that they are true copies of such originals.</p>
<p>I further certify that the Extra Session of the Tenth Legislature of the State of Texas, in compliance with the Proclamation of the Governor, assembled on Monday, the ninth day of May, A. D. 1864, and adjourned on the twenty-eighth day of May, in the same year.</p>
<p>In testimony whereof, I have hereunio signed my name, and caused the seal of the Department of State to be affixed, at Austin, this 20th of July, <floatingText rend="left"><body><p>[L. S.]</p></body></floatingText>A. D. 1864.</p>
<closer>
<signed>R. J. TOWNES, Secretary of State.</signed>
</closer>
</div2>
</div1>
</body>
</text>