<text xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 UNTtite%20(1.3).xsd" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="TEI">
<body>
<pb n="589" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="1" />
<div1 type="article">
<head type="main">GENERAL LAWS <lb/>OF THE <lb/>EXTRA SESSION <lb/>OF <lb/>THE NINTH LEGISLATURE <lb/>OF <lb/>THE STATE OF TEXAS</head>
<byline>PUBLISHED BY AUTHORITY</byline>
<byline>AUSTIN 1863</byline>
<pb n="590" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="2" />
<pb n="591" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="3" />
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">GENERAL LAWS.</head>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER I.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to authorize the Supreme Court of the State, for the Galveston District, to hold its Spring term at the city of Austin.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Su<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />preme Court of the State, for the Galveston District, is hereby authorized to hold its Spring term, for the year 1863, at the city of Austin.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That the Judges of said Court are hereby authorized to have the records and papers appertaining to the Supreme Court of said Galveston District removed to the city of Austin, to be kept separate and apart from the records and papers of the Austin District, and to be returned to the Galveston District upon the adjourn<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment of said Court.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That this act shall take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>February 9th, 1863</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER II.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act in relation to Judicial Proceedings in Counties in possession of, or endan<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />gered by the enemy.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That during the continuance of the war between the Confederate States and the United States, should any enemy of the Confederate States take possession of any territory within any county of this State, or apparently threaten so to do, so as, in the judgment of the Chief Justice, or County Court of said county, or of the Judge of the District Court of the District in which such county is situated, to render it unsafe or im<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />proper, in view of the public interest, to hold the District or County Courts of such county at the court-house of the same, or to keep the records of such District Court, or of such county, at the count-house of the same, it shall be the duty of the Chief Justice, County Court dr District Judge, to certify such facts upon the records of the County or District Court of such county, either in term time or vacation, or to publish the same in some public manner, which act may be done either within, or without such county, as may be necessary or convenient to the Chief Justice, County Court or District Judge acting. And after such certificate may have been made, it shall be lawful for the Chief Justice, the County Court, the Clerk of the County Court, the Clerk of the District Court, and the Sheriff of such county, in the possession of, or endangered by the enemy, to keep their offices, and to discharge the duties of the same at any safe place within the limits of such county that may be indicated by the Chief Justice or <pb n="592" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="4" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw> County Court of such county, or by the Judge of the District Court in which such county is situated; and the sessions of the District and County Courts of such county may be held at such indicated place until it may be safe to keep said of<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fices and hold said court at the regular places now established by law. But in case it shall, in the judgment of such District Judge, Chief Justice, or County Court, be unsafe to keep said offices and hold the sessions of said courts within the limits of such county, such facts shall be certified in the manner hereinbefore provided.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. In case said offices cannot be kept, and courts held, as provided in the foregoing section, it shall be lawful for any person or persons, corporation or asso<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ciation, having any right of action which, under the laws in force at the time, could be sued, upon, and which it would be necessary under existing laws to bring suits upon in the District Court of such county occupied or endangered by the enemy, to commence suit thereon in the District Court of any county in which any defendant in such suit may be found, or of the county not in like manner occupied or endan<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />gered by the enemy, the court-house of which is nearest to the court-house of the county in which such suits would, but for the provisions of this act, be required to be commenced; and all process issued in such causes, necessary or proper to be executed in such county occupied or endangered by the enemy, may be executed and returned by the Sheriff of the county in which the cause is pending, or by the Sheriff of the county in which the process is to be executed, or by any lawful deputy of either of such Sheriffs. And, in like ease, the estates of deceased persons which, un<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />der existing laws, would be required to be opened in such occupied or endangered county, may be opened in the County Court of the county not in like manner occu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pied or endangered by the enemy, the court-house of which is nearest to the court<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />house of the uounty in which such estate would, but for the provisions of this act, be required to be opened; and administrators and executors may be appointed, wills probated, and such estates administered upon in the county where they may be opened. In like ease, all persons who have violated any criminal law of the State, or shall hereafter do so, for which, under existing laws, they would be liable to be tried in any such county occupied or endangered by the enemy, shall be liable to be proceeded against and tried in the District Court of the county not in like manner occupied or endangered by the enemy, the court-house of which is nearest to the court-house of the county in which the crimes for which the party is to be tried may be charged to have been committed.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. Immediately upon the termination of the war between the Confederate States and the United States, all civil and criminal causes and all administrations and proceedings in relation to the estates of deceased persons which may have been commenced and may then be pending and undetermined in any county in which such cause or proceeding could not have been commenced but for the provisions of this act, shall be transferred, unless the parties to the record in such causes shall other<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />wise agree, in writing, to the proper court of the county in which such cause or proceeding would have been required to have been commenced but for the passage of this act, and like proceedings shall there be had therein as though such cause or pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ceedings had originally been commenced in such court; and, for the purpose of mak<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing such transfer, the clerk of the court in which such cause or proceeding may be pending, shall make out and certify, under the seal of the court, a correct transcript of all the proceedings had in such cause in such court; and transmit the same, to<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />gether with all of the original papers in the cause, to the proper court.</p>
<pb n="593" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="5" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<p>Sec. 4. . This act is not intended to be construed to repeal any laws now in force, but to be an addition thereto; and so far as it may conflict with the provisions of any existing law, such provisions shall so far as relates to the matters herein pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vided for, be suspended during the time this act shall be in force; and this act shall take effect from its passage, and shall be in force during the continuance of the war between the Confederate States and the United States, and no longer.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>February 25th, 1863</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER III.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to prescribe the residences of County Surveyors.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the County Surveyors of the several counties of this State shall reside within their respective counties, and keep their offices at the county seats thereof; and in all cases where the County Surveyors do not reside, at the county seats of their respective coun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ties, they shall, and are hereby required to have deputies in their respective of<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fices residing at said county seats, who shall keep their offices open, and the records thereof subject to the examination of any person interested therein.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That all laws, so far as they conflict with the provisions of this act, be and the same are hereby repealed, and that this act take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>February 25th, 1863</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER IV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to amend the nineteenth, twentieth and forty-seventh sections of An Act entitled &#8220;An Act to regulate proceedings in the County Courts, pertaining to estates of deceased persons,&#8221; approved March 20th, A. D., 1848.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That section nineteen of the act recited in the caption hereof, shall hereafter read as follows: Before the issuance of letters testamentary, or of administration with the will annexed, the person named executor, or appointed administrator with the will annexed, shall, before the Clerk or Chief Justice of any County Court in this State, or before any Justice of the Peace in the county where the application for such let<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ters is made, take and subscribe an oath, in form, as follows: I do solemnly swear that the writing which has been offered for probate is the last will of &#8212; so far as I know or believe; and that I will well and truly perform all the duties of executor of said will, or of administrator with the will annexed, of the estate of the said &#8212; (as the case may be.)</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That section twenty of said act shall hereafter read as follows: Before the issuance of letters of administration, the person appointed administrator shall, before the Clerk, or Chief Justice of any county in the State, or before any Justice of the Peace in the county where application for such letters is made, take and subscribe an oath, in form, as follows: I do solemnly swear that &#8212; deceased, died without leaving any lawful will, so far as I know or believe, and that I will well and truly perform all the duties of administrator of the estate of said &#8212;.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That section forty-seven of said act shall hereafter read as follows: That every claim for money against a testator or intestate, shall be presented to the executor or administrator within twelve months after the <pb n="594" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="6" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw> original grant of letters testamentary, or of administration, or the payment thereof shall be postponed until the claims which have been presented within said twelve months, and allowed by the executor or administrator, and approved by the Chief Justice, or established by suit, shall have been first entirely paid: Provided, how<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ever, That if the executor or administrator be absent from the State any time dur<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing the said twelve months, the time of such absence shall not be computed against the holder of such claim, nor taken as a part of the time limited by this action.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. That this act shall take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>February 25th, 1863</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER V.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to suspend the operations of the Stray Laws for and during the existence of the present war, and for six months after its termination, except in certain cases.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That from and after the passage of this act, all laivs and parts of laws providing for the estraying of stock and prescribing the course of proceedings in the same, and of selling stock heretofore estrayed, shall be, in all things, suspended for and during the existence of the present war, and until six months after peace shall be con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cluded, with the exceptions hereinafter mentioned.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That any person may have the right, under the regulations now in force for estraying stock, to estray any vicious animal or breachy stock that is likely to injure the stock in the range or the property of any person, and any person desiring to estray any such stock shall, in addition to the conditions heretofore prescribed, prove by two credible witnesses, by an affidavit in writing, to be filed with the papers in the County Clerk&#8217;s office, that the property estrayed is vicious, breachy, or so unruly as to be dangerous and unfit to run at large.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That this act take effect and be in force forty days after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>February 25th, 1863</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER VI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to suspend all Statutes of Limitations on civil rights of action of every kind, whether real or personal, until one year after the close of the war between the Confederate States and the United States.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted, by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That all statutes of limitations on all civil rights of action of every kind, whether real or personal, are hereby suspended until one year after the close of the war between the Confederate States and the United States:</p>
<p>Provided, That the limitation upon all rights of action for injuries done to the person of another, as of assault and battery, wounding, or imprisonment and for injuries done the character or reputation of another, as of libel or slander, shall not be suspended by the provisions of this act.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. This act shall be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>February 26th, 1863</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
<pb n="595" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="7" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER VII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to attach the county of Kendall to the Fourth Judicial District, and to amend an Act entitled an &#8220;Act to attach the county of Blanco to the Fourth, Judicial District, and to amend an Act entitled an Act to provide for the time of holding the courts of the several counties in the Fourth Judicial District, ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />proved 2d February, 1858.&#8221;</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the county of Kendall be, and is hereby attached to the Fourth Judicial District, and that the first section of the above recited act be so amended,as to reiad as follows: That the county of Blanco be, and hereby is attached to the Fourth Judicial Dis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />trict.</p>
<p>The District Courts of the several counties of the said District shall be held as follows, viz: Beginning in the county of Bexar on the first Mondays of March and September, and may continue is session seven weeks.</p>
<p>In the county of Comal on the eighth Mondays after the first Mondays of March and September, and may continue in session one week.</p>
<p>In the county of Blanco on the ninth Mondays after the first Mondays in March and September, and may continue in session one week.</p>
<p>In the county of Gillespie on the tenth Mondays after the first Mondays in March and September, and may continue in session two weeks.</p>
<p>In the county of Kerr on the twelfth Mondays after the first Mondays of March and September, and may continue in session one week.</p>
<p>And in the county of Kendall on the thirteenth Mondays after the first Mondays in March and September, and continue in session until the business or the term is disposed of.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That all writs, bonds, recognizances and process of all kinds that have been or may be issued, taken, and made returnable to the times heretofore ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pointed for the terms of said courts, shall be considered and taken as made for the times herein provided for said courts.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That all laws or parts of laws in conflict with the provisions of this act be, and are hereby repealed, and that this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>March 2d, 1863</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER VIII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act making an appropriation to defray the contingent expenses, of the Extra Session of the Ninth Legislature.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the sum of six thousand dollars, or so much thereof as may be necessary, be, and the same is hereby appropriated to pay the contingent expenses of the Extra Session of the Ninth Legislature.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>March 2d, 1863</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER IX.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act making an appropriation for the mileage and per diem pay of the members and the per diem pay of the Officers of the Extra Session of the Ninth Legislature of the State of Texas.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the sum of forty thousand dollars, or so much thereof as may be necessary, be, and the same is hereby appropriated out of any money in the treasury not <pb n="596" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="8" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw> otherwise appropriated, for the mileage and per diem pay of the members and the per diem pay of the officers of the Extra Session of the Ninth Legislature of the State of Texas.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That the certificate of the Secretary of the Senate and the certificate of the Chief Clerk of the House shall be sufficient evidence to the Comptroller, upon which he shall audit the claims and draw his warrants upon the Treasurer for the respective amounts.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That in case there be no funds in the treasury, the Comptroller shall draw his warrants upon the Treasurer; one-tenth of each claim may be issued, if the claimant desires it, in one dollar warrants. For the other nine-tenths of the claim no Warrant shall be drawn of a less denomination than five dollars.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. That this act take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>March 3d, 1863</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER X.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to procure specie to enable the people to pay the Specie Tax.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Military Board be, and they are hereby authorized to procure an amount of specie equal to four cents on each one hundred dollars of the assessment of the State taxes for the year A. D. 1862, and the like amount upon the amount of assess<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ments thereafter, and place the same in the treasury of the State, to the credit and interest of the sinking fund created, and provided for under &#8220;an act authorizing a loan and imposing a specific tax to meet the principal and interest thereof, under the provisions of the 33d section of the 7th article of the Constitution of the State. &#8220;approved April 8th, 1861, and that the same be appropriated to no other use or purpose whatever.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That to enable the Military Board to do and perform the duties imposed on them by the first section of this act, they are hereby authorized, and, if necessary, required to employ some competent person or persons to purchase cotton and have the same transported to Mexico, or elsewhere, and sold for specie, and to bring the specie thus obtained to the treasury of the State, where it shall be deposited as pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vided in the 1st section of this act.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. It shall be the duty of the Assessor and Collector to receive from the tax<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />payers, instead of the specie taxes, like amounts of such other funds as may be receivable for ordinary taxes, giving receipts therefor, not in absolute payments, but to be exchanged for specie at the treasury so as to obtain therefor the necessary specie for complete payments; and it shall further be the duty of the Collector to forward the funds so received, and co-operate with the Comptroller in making said exchange.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. That the sum of one hundred and fifty thousand dollars, or so much thereof as may be necessary, be, and the same is hereby appropriated to enable the Military Board to carry into effect the provisions of this bill, and they are hereby empowered to use, for the same purpose, any securities which they may have in their possession under appropriations heretofore made, and that this act be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>March 3d, 1863</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<pb n="597" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="9" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act entitled an act authorizing judgments to be rendered in certain cases, requiring property levied upon by execution or sale under deeds of trust or mort<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />gage, to bring nine-tenths of its appraised value.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That in all suits now pending, or hereafter to be brought in any of the courts of this State for the collection of money, the defendant shall be allowed to plead and prove on the trial of the same, that he had tendered to plaintiff, or owner, or persons in possession of the claim sued on, or their agent, in bonds or notes of the Confederate States, or the State bonds of this State, the sum due on the same, and that the per<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />son to whom the tender was made had failed or refused to receive the same in full satisfaction of the debt sued on, and upon proof of the tender and refusal, the court, if satisfied there is any amount due, shall render a judgment for the amount really due; and shall further order, that no property shall be sold under any execution that may issue on said judgment, unless it shall bring nine-tenths of its appraised value, as hereinafter directed.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. On all executions issued upon judgments rendered as provided in the preceding section of this act, the defendant shall have the right to point out the property to be levied upon, and shall have a reasonable time for that purpose, after called upon by the officer for a levy; and after the Sheriff or other officer shall have made a levy under an execution, as aforesaid, the defendant in execution shall select one man, the Sheriff or officer making the levy another, and they two a third, to act as appraisers, who shall be sworn by the Sheriff or officer making the levy, who shall make their appraisement in writing, two, at least, of whom shall sign the same, which shall be delivered to the officer making the levy, and the property so levied upon and appraised shall, on the day of sale, bring nine-tenths of its ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />praised value, or there shall be no sale; and if there be no sale, the property shall be restored to the defendant in execution.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. Not more than one execution shall issue in each year, after the issuance of the first execution, upon judgments rendered as provided in the first section of this act, upon each of which like proceedings shall in all respects be had as is pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vided in the second section of this act; but in no case shall property be sold unless it shall tiring nine-tenths of its appraised value.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. That in all cases where judgments have heretofore been rendered for money, in any of the courts of this State, and the same or any part thereof remain unpaid, and the defendants in the same has or shall tender to the plaintiff in such judgment, his agent or attorney, the full amount of the principal and interest due on the same, in bonds or treasury notes of the Confederate States, or bonds of this State, and the plaintiff in such judgment, his agent or attorney, has or shall refuse to receive the same in full satisfaction of such judgment, the defendant in such judg<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment shall have the right to file his petition in the court where such judgment was rendered, setting forth the facts, and cause the plaintiff in the judgment to he summoned as in other cases; and upon proof of the tender and refusal aforesaid, it shall be the duty of the court to enter a decree or judgment, directing the proceed<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing thereafter to be had on said judgment, to be in all things Conducted as provided in the second and third sections of this act.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. In all sales authorized to be made by or under any deed of trust, or to satisfy any mortgage, and the amount due shall have been tendered as provided in the first, section of this act, no sale shall be made ex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cept by appraisement and for nine-tenths of its appraised value, as provided in the second and third sections of this act: Provided, That in all cases under the provi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" /><pb n="598" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="10" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw> sions of this act to entitle the defendant to the benefit of the same, he shall prove on the trial that the tender was within twelve months after the close of the present war between the Confederate States and the United States.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. This act take effect and be in force from and after its passage: Pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vided, That nothing in this act shall be so construed as repealing an act entitled &#8220;an act suspending all laws for the collection of debts and liabilities on bonds, promissory notes, bills of exchange and contracts for the payment of money, until the first day of January, 1864, or until six months after the close of the present war, should it terminate before the date named, or until otherwise provided by law, approved December 7th, 1861.&#8221; But the same shall remain in full force and effect, notwith<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />standing the passage of this act.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>March 4th, 1863</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to regulate the sale of Beef Cattle, and to require Butchers to keep and return lists of the cattle slaughtered by them, and to prevent the sale of calves for slaughter without branding.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That every purchaser of beeves, for the purpose of slaughter for the Confederate armies within the county where purchased, or elsewhere, or for the purpose of exportation, or driving to market, out of the county where purchased, shall, before slaughtering as aforesaid, or exporting or driving the same out of the county where purchased, take from each and every person from whom he purchases any such beef or beeves, a bill of sale of the same, fully describing the marks and brand, or brands, (if more than one) of each animal, signed by the party selling; which bill, or bills of sale, shall be verfied by the oath of the purchaser of such beeves, as genuine; and the said bill of sale and oath attached, shall be filed by the said purchaser with the Clerk of the County Court of the county in which said beeves were purchased, to be recorded in a book kept for that purpose, which shall be open to the inspection of the public: Provided, In case there shall not be any such clerk ready to receive and record such bill of sale and affidavit, the same shall be filed and recorded in like manner in some adjoining county; and such record, in the one county or the other, shall be made without any unreasonable delay, but the recording in such adjoining county shall not dispense with the filing and recording in the county first indicated whenever there shall be therein a County Clerk prepared for the business, with whom the bill of sale and affidavit shall be filed for record, without unreasonable de<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lay, whereupon they shall be promptly recorded by said clerk.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That any purchaser of beef or beeves, who shall fail to comply with the provisions of the first section of this act, shall be deemed guilty of an offence against the laws of this State, and shall be liable to indictment therefore, and, upon con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />viction, shall be fined in the sum of five hundred dollars, one hundred of which shall go to the informer, and the balance to be paid into the County Treasury, to be added to the jury fund.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That certified copies of said bills of sales, duly attested by the clerk having charge of the same, under the seal of his office, shall be received in our courts as prima facia evidence against the vendor of any such beef or beeves in any civil suit or criminal action brought against him.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. Every person who shall butcher beef for the market of any town or village, shall keep lists of the marks and brands of all the cattle slaughtered by him, and stating from whom purchased, and, at least once in each month, shall return the same, verified by his oath, to the Clerk of the County Court, <pb n="599" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="11" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw> who shall cause the same to be recorded in his office, and keep them subject to the inspection of the public, which oath may be taken before any person authorized by law to administer oaths; and the clerks shall be entitled to such fees as is provided by law for similar services.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. Should any butcher fail to render such list for any month, by the 15th day of the next succeeding month, he shall be deemed guilty of a misdemeanor, and, on conviction, shall be fined not less than fifty, or more than one hundred dollars for each offence, one half of which shall go to the informer, and the other to the jury fund, as above provided; and if he return a false list, shall be guilty of false swear<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing and liable to prosecution therefor, as in other cases.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. It is hereby declared a penal offence to sell calves for slaughter or ship<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment without branding them, and any person so offending, shall be subject to in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dictment, and a fine of ten dollars per head for every calf thus sold.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>March 4th, 1863</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XIII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to amend the first section of an Act entitled &#8220;An Act to amend the 1st and llth sections of an Act to authorize the sale of the Public Domain, approved February llth, 1858,&#8221; approved January 1st, 1862&#8212;and to amend the second section of an Act entitled &#8220;An Act to authorize the sale of the Public Domain,&#8221; approved February llth, 1858.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted, by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the first section of the above recited act shall hereafter read as follows: That the Commissioner of the General Land Office is authorized to issue land scrip in cer<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tificates of not less than one hundred and sixty acres (except in the cases herein provided,) which certificates may be sold at the price of two dollars per acre, shall issue in the name of the purchaser, and may be located upon any vacant unappro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />priated public domain, not being set apart, held in reservation, or the location of which is prohibited by law.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That the second section of the above recited act &#8220;to authorize the sale of the public domain, &#8220;approved February 11th, 1858&#8212;shall hereafter read as fol<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lows:&#8212;Sec. 2.&#8212;That the alternate sections of the land surveyed and reserved to the State, under the provisions of the laws to encourage the construction of railroads by donations of land, and the act granting land to the Galveston and Brazos Naviga<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion Company, and the islands heretofore reserved, and all other reserved sections, may be sold at five dollars per acre.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. This act shall take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>March 4th, 1863</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XIV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act appropriating two hundred thousand dollars, to be expended for the relief of the sick and wounded Soldiers&#8217; of the State of Texas, in the army of the Con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />federate States.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the sum of two hundred thousand dollars, or so much thereof as may be necessary, be, and the same is hereby appropriated as a Hospital Fund, which shall be admin<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />istered, according to the provisions of an act, approved January 8th, 1862, entitled an act to create a Hospital Fund, to be expended for the benefit of the sick and wounded soldiers of the State of Texas, in the Confederate army.</p>
<pb n="600" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="12" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<p>Sec. 2. That any part of the appropriation made in this act, may be drawn from the treasury by warrants of the Comptroller in such sums and denominations as may be directed by the Governer.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That this act, shall be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>March 5th, 1863</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>&#8220;An Act to amend an Act to amend An Act to establish a Penal Code, &#8220;approved August 26th, 1856; approved February 12th, 1858.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas. That Article 34 of &#8220;An Act to amend An Act to establish a Penal Code, &#8220;approved august 26th, 1856; approved February 12th, 1858, be amended so as hereafter to read as follows:&#8212;Article 34. &#8220;All free white persons who have less than one-eighth African blood come within the meaning of the term &#8220;free white persons; &#8220;and all free white persons who have that, or a quarter proportion of African blood come within the meaning of the terms &#8220;free persons of color.&#8221; Slaves are all such per<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sons of African descent as are held in slavery by the laws of this State, or of any of the States or Territories of the Confederate States, or of any foreign country.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That Article 349 of said Act be amended so as hereafter to read as fol<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lows: Article 349. Wherever, in the Penal Code or Code of Criminal Procedure, it is declared, that an officer is guilty of an offence, on account of any particular act or omission, and there is not, in the Penal Code, any punishment assigned for the same, such offcer shall be deemed guilty of a misdemeanor and shall be fined not ex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ceeding two hundred dollars.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That said act be so amended by adding the following article thereto, which shall read as follows:&#8212;Article 669a. If any person shall sell, give, or loan, to a slave or slaves, a gun, pistol, sword, bowie knife or dagger, or any gun-powder or percussion caps, without the written consent of his or her master, mistress or over<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />seer, he or she shall be confined at hard labor in the Penitentiary not less than two nor more than five years.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. That Article 745a, of said act, be amended so as hereafter to read as follows:</p>
<p>Article 745a. If any person shall receive or conceal property which has been ac<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />quired by another, in such manner as that the acquisition comes within the mean<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing of the term theft, knowing the same to have been so acquired, he shall be pun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ished in the same manner as, by law, the person stealing the same would be liable to be punished: Provided, That if a free white person shall receive or conceal such property stolen by a slave or free person of color he shall be punished in the same manner as, by law, a free white person stealing the same would be liable to be punished.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>March 5th, 1853</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XVI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to exclude from office, serving on juries, taking or holding property, and from the rights of suffrage, all persons who take the alien oath, leave our country, to avoid the service, or who join the enemy, or in anywise give them aid and comfort.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That no person, being a resident of the State, or of any one of the Confederate States, who may, during the existing war between the Confederate States and the</p>
<pb n="601" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="13" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<p>United States, take the oath commonly known as the alien oath, whereby he claims the protection of any foreign government, as a shield from serving in the cause of the Confederate States in their present struggle, or who may leave, or having left, remain absent from this State, nr any of the Confederate States, or who may join, or having joined, continue in the army or service, or employment of the United States, or who may conceal himself, and thereby avoid service in our cause, or who may, in anywise, give aid and comfort to the enemy, shall upon conviction thereof be<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fore any court of competent jurisdiction, take or hold any estate, real, personal, or mixed, whether by purchase, gift, devise, or descent, in this State, nor hold any office of trust, profit, or honor, nor vote at any election, nor serve on any juries in any Court within this State: Provided, That persons who shall prove themselves to be bona fide neutrals and citizens of a friendly power, shall not be subject to the provisions of this act.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That the judgment of the Court upon the verdict of a jury in any one of the causes enumerated in the preceding section, shall be sufficient evidence of the guilt of the party, in any suit or proceeding that may subsequently arise, on any issue made upon any question involved in the said first section.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That for the offences enumerated in the first section of this act, the party may be prosecuted at any time within five years after the ratification of a treaty of peace between the Confederate States and the United States.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. That this act take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>March 5th, 1863</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XVII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to provide for the support of the families of Texan Soldiers.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the sum of six hundred thousand dollars is hereby appropriated, to be distributed by the Comptroller according to such regulations as he shall adopt, to the County Courts of each county in the State, according to the scholastic returns and esti<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mates for the years 1861 and 1862, taking as a basis for the distribution to those counties which have not returned their lists for both years, the year for which there is a return of the county, to be administered by the said County Courts, for the support and assistance of the widows, families and dependents of the officers and soldiers of Texas, who have been or may be in the Army of the Confederate States, or in the active Militia or Volunteer Service of the State of Texas, and which widows, families or dependents may need the support or assistance of the State.</p>
<p>Sec. 2.&#8212;That this Act shall take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>March 5th, 1863</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XVIII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to define the offence of inciting insurrection or insubordination of slaves in certain cases, and to prescribe the punishment therefor.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Whereas, in the prosecution of the unholy war now being waged by the United States against the Confederate States and the people thereof, our enemies are seek<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing to bring upon us a servile war by arming our slaves and placing them in the ranks of their armies, as well as otherwise, through the action of their government and the commissioned officers of their armies, inciting insurrection and insubordi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />nation: &#8212;therefore&#8212;</p>
<pb n="602" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="14" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<p>Section. 1. Be it enacted, by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That it shall be an offence, to be denominated inciting insurrection or insubordination of slaves, for any commissioned officer of the army, navy, or marine service of the government of the United States, during the present war between said United States and the Confederate States, to invade or enter upon, with hostile intent, the Terri<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tory or soil of this State, or with like intent, to enter within the waters of this State.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That any person guilty of inciting insurrection or insubordination, as in this act defined, shall, on conviction thereof, be punished by confinement in the Penitentiary not less than five nor more than fifteen years.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. This act not being intended to produce any conflict btween the State authorities and the government or authorities of the Confederate States, in relation to the management of any matters growing out of the existing war, therefore, only such persons shall be subject to be tried under its provisions as may be, by the proper authorities of the Confederate States, delivered over to the civil authorities of this State, for the purpose of being so tried&#8212;and, any person convicted under the provisions of this act, shall, at any time after such conviction, on demand made therefor by the President of the Confederate States on the Governor of this State, be delivered up to the proper authorities of the Confederate States.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. This act is not designed to be in lieu of existing laws defining the exciting or insubordination of slaves, and shall not be construed in any manner to effect such laws.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. This act shall be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>March 5th, 1863</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XIX.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act supplemental to an Act entitled an Act, defining the office and duties of Notaries Public, passed May 13th, 1846, and to amend the first section of said Act.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the first section of the above entitled act be so amended as to read as follows: There shall be appointed by the Governor, by and with the advice and consent of two-thirds of the Senate, a convenient number of Notaries Public, not exceeding six for each county, who shall hold their office for four years from the day of their qualification, and no longer, any law to the contrary notwithstanding. The office of Notary Public shall become vacant by removal from the county, by becoming in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sane, by accepting any civil office under the State Government, (except the office of Justice of the Peace,) or any office under the Confederate or other government; and the office of Deputy Clerk, Deputy Sheriff and Deputy Marshal, come within the meaning of this act.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That when a Notary is appointed, the Secretary of State shall forward the commission to the Clerk of the County Court of the County where the party resides, who shall notify him to appear before the County Court within thirty days from the day of the notice, if there will be a regular term of said court, if not, before the Clerk in vacation, and qualify according to law. The Clerk shall endorse on the commission the day when the notice was given, and if the party does not qualify within the time limited the appointment shall be void, and the Clerk shall certify on the back of the Commission, under the seal of the court, that the party has failed to qualify, and return it to the Secretary of State. When the party qualifies in vacation, the Clerk shall approve the bond, and record it as in other cases.</p>
<pb n="603" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="15" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<p>Sec. 3. Be it further enacted, That whenever a Notary Public qualifies, or vacates his office, by death or otherwise, the Clerk of the County Court shall immediately report the fact to the Secretary of State, giving the date of qualification, and show<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing when and by what way the office became vacant.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. Be it further enacted, That whenever a Notary Public voluntarily vacates his office, or when the office becomes vacant by expiration of time, he shall deliver to the Clerk of the County Court his seal and books, and the records of his office. If any notary public fails to comply with this provision, he shall be subject to a fine of one hundred dollars, recoverable by motion in the District Court, in the name of the State, to be prosecuted by said Clerk.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. Be it further enacted, That if the Clerk fails to comply with the pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />visions of this act, he shall be subject to a fine of one hundred dollars, recoverable by motion in the District Court, in the name of the county; and on trial of the motion, the certificate of the Secretary of State, showing default on the part of the Clerk, shall be presumptive evidence of the facts therein stated.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. Be it further enacted, That the Clerk shall be entitled to a fee of two dol<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lars from every Notary who qualifies, and this act take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>March 5th, 1863</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XX.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act appropriating money to defray the expenses incurred for rations and forage, ordered by Brigadier General Wm. Hudson, 21st Brigade, State Troops.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Whereas, About the 1st of October, 1862, it become known that a secret organiza<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion existed in the county of Cooke and adjoining counties, having for its object the overthrow of this government: And Whereas, The Texas State Troops, of the 21st Brigade, were called out by Brig. Gen. Wm. Hudson, of said Brigade: And Whereas, Said rebellion has been effectually crushed, and harmony is restored in that portion of the State; therefore</p>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Comptroller be, and he is hereby required to audit and pay, by his warrants upon the Treasurer, all accounts for forage and subsistence of the Texas State Troops, of the 21st Brigade, called into service by Brig. Gen. Hudson, of said Brigade: Provided, Such claims shall be duly sworn to by the claimants, before some Justice of the Peace, or Notary Public, within said Brigade, to be also approved by the Acting Quartermaster and Commissary of said 21st Brigade.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That the sum of four thousand five hundred dollars, or so much thereof as may be necessary, be, and is hereby appropriated out of any unappropriated money in the treasury, in payment of all such claims, and that this act take effect from its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>March 5th, 1863</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act declaring void any sale made by the Public Enemy who may occupy any portion of the Territoiy of the State of Texas.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enaeted by the Legislature of the State of Texas. That if at any time pending a war between the Confederate States Government and any other government, State or Power, any of the Territory within the limits of the State of Texas shall be occupied by the enemy, and, during such occu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" /><pb n="604" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="16" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw> pancy, any sales or transfers of property shall be made by them, either by private or public act, or under any pretence of proceeding whatever, or real, personal, or mixed property, belonging to any citizen or citizens of the State of Texas, such sales shall be deemed void and of no effect, and all deeds made under such sales, and all transfers and evidences of title conveyed, shall be considered void, and not ad<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />missible as evidence in any courts of the State of Texas.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. This act take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>March 5th, 1863</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to amend the 12th and 15th sections of an Act, entitled &#8220;an Act regulating Elections,&#8221; passed March 16th, 1848, and to amend the 9th and 14th sections of an Act entitled &#8220;an Act supplementary to an Act regulating Elections, passed February 11th, 1S50.&#8221;</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the 12th section of the act first recited in the caption hereof be so amended as hereafter to read as follows:</p>
<p>Sec. 12. That immediately after closing the polls, the managers of the election shall proceed to count the votes, make out a correct return, signed by the managers, which together with the ballots, and one of the poll-books, shall be sealed up and delivered to the Chief Justice of the county, (or in his absence, the Clerk of the County Court, who shall file the same in his office, and deliver said return to the Chief Justice on the day appointed to open and compare the polls,) by one of the managers, or some other respectable person, who shall swear that he re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ceived the package from one of the managers, or the returning officer, and that the seals have not been broken since; which delivery shall be upon oath, before the return day of said election, a duplicate of which return shall be kept by the presiding officer.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That the 15th section of the act first recited in the caption hereof, be so amended as hereafter to read as follows:</p>
<p>Sec. 15. That the election returns shall not be opened by the officer to whom they are returned, before return day, or tenth day, and exclusive of the day of election; at the expiration of that time he shall open them and estimate the result, making a tabular statement thereof, showing the number of votes east at each pre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cinct for the several candidates, which table he shall record in a book to be kept for that purpose, and he shall also record in said book the names of the persons elected to the county and precinct offices; and he shall thereupon deliver to the per<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sons elected certificates of election, showing when and to what office the parties were elected, and shall sign the same, and cause the seal of the County Court to be thereon impressed.</p>
<p>At the expiration of thirty days after the election, and from time to time there<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />after, as the officers may qualify, the Chief Justice shall make out and certify to the Secretary of State, a tabular statement, showing who were elected, and to what office, and the date of qualification, giving the number of the precinct, (if precinct officers,) and he shall also certify the result of the vote for members of the Legislature; and he shall, in like manner, report to the Secretary of State all special elections to fill vacancies in any county or precinct office, and certifying when and how the vacancy occurred; and when any State or District officer, member of Congress, or of the Leg<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />islature, or Notary Public, shall depart this life, the Chief Justice of the county where such death occurs shall immediately certify the fact thereof to the Secretary of State: and if any Chief Justice shall neglect to comply with any of the <pb n="605" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="17" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw> provisions of this act, he shall be fined one hundred dollars, recoverable by motion in the District Court of the county in which he resides, after reasonable notice of such motion: Provided, however, Such Chief Justice may acquit himself of such neglect by affidavit made before any officer authorized to administer oaths.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That the 9th section of the act last recited in the caption hereof shall be so amended as to read as follows: Sec. 9. That when an election has been held for Governor and Lieutenant Governor, the Secretary of State shall make a table, con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />taining an alphabetical list of the counties, with columns for the candidates and the number of votes; and he shall, in the presence of the Governor or Attorney Gen<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />eral, open the returns and enter on the table the number of votes given for the can<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />didates respectively, and then place the returns back in the envelope, seal it, endorse upon it the date of its reception, and carefully file it away in his office: the table thus kept shall be open to public inspection, and, together with all the returns, shall be delivered to the Speaker of the House of Representatives on the first day of the next regular session of the Legislature. That when elections are held for other State officers, and for District officers, the Secretary shall, in like manner, make alpha<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />betical tables of the counties in the State, or of the Districts, and, as the returns are received, he shall enter the number of votes received by each candidate, then endorse thereon the date of the receipt, and carefully preserve the same in his office. If the returns are all in before the expiration of sixty days, the Secretary of State, in presence of the Governor and Attorney General, or in case of vacancy or inability of either to act, then any two of said officers shall count the returns which shall have been made, and the Governor shall thereupon deliver a certificate of election to the person or persons who shall have received the highest number of votes for each or any of said offices. If the returns are not all in before the sixtieth day from the day of the election, the same officers shall proceed on that day and count the returns, and issue certificates as before provided for. If any of the returns are defective, or if there is unreasonable delay in making returns, the Secretary shall notify the Chief Justice, or other proper officer, of the defect or neglect, and to cause proper returns to be made. The Chief Justice, or other officer, failing to make re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />turns promptly, shall be subject to a fine of one hundred dollars, recoverable by motion in the District Court of the county in which he resides, after reasonable notice of such motion: Provided, however, Such Chief Justice may acquit himself of such neglect by sufficient affidavit made before any officer authorized to administer oaths; and on the trial of such motion the certificate of the Secretary of State, charging default upon the Chief Justice, shall be presumptive evidence of the facts therein contained.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. That section 14th of the act last recited be so amended as to read as fol<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lows: Sec. 14. That any person who shall intend to contest an election for any office mentioned in the 11th, 12th and 13th sections of this act, shall, within ninety days after the day of election, give notice to the person in whose favor the cer<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tificate shall have been made, of the grounds upon which he intends to rely on the trial of such contest, and shall, within the same period, cause a copy thereof to be filed in the office of the District Clerk of the county where such contest is to be tried.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. That this act take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<pb n="606" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="18" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>March 6th, 1863</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXIII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to authorize the Directors of the State Penitentiary to allow the Financial Agent of the same to purchase additional machinery, and to employ outside labor for the same.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Directors of the State Penitentiary be, and they are hereby authorized to direct the Financial Agent thereof to purchase, on the best terms possible, any machinery hat may be necessary to supply the worn-out machinery of said Penitentiary, or any additional machinery that they may deem expedient to enlarge the works of the same, by ordering or sending any agent therefor at the risk of the State of Texas.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That the said Directors are further authorized to direct the said Financial Agent to employ such outside labor as they may deem ex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pedient, in addition to the convict labor, to carry on the workshops and factories of said Penitentiary.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>March 6th, 1863</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXIV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to amend an Act entitled an Act to amend an Act to establish a Code of Criminal Proceedure for the State of Texas, approved August 26th, 1856; approved February 15th, 1858.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That articles 156, 190a, 280, 644 and 960, of an act entitled an act to amend an act to establish a Code of Criminal Proceedure for the State of Texas, approved August 26th, 1856, ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />proved February 15th, 1858, be amended so as hereafter to read as follows: Art. 156. Whenever the District Attorney of the proper district is in the county where a cause is heard under habeas corpus, it is his duty, if the defendant is accused of a felony, to be present at the hearing and represent the State, for which service he shall be paid twenty-five dollars; and if the District Attorney is not present at the hearing of such cause, the Judge shall appoint some well qualified practising attorney to represent the State, who shall be paid the same fee as is allowed District Attor<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />neys for like services. Art. 190a. The offence of forgery may be prosecuted in any county where the written instrument is forged, or where the same is used or passed, or attempted to be used or passed; and the offence of counterfeiting may be prose<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cuted in any county where the offence is committed, or where the counterfeit coin is passed, or attempted to be passed; and the offences of perjury and false swear<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing may be prosecuted in the county where the offence was committed, or in the county where the false statement is used or attempted to be used. Art. 280. In cases of felony the Sheriff cannot, during the term of the court, take the bail, but must bring the accused before the court, that he may there enter into recog<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />nizance, but if, from any cause, the term of the court should end before such recognizance can be, or is entered into, then and in that event the Sheriff may take bail in such amount as may have been fixed in the case by the court. Art. 644. The following persons only are incompetent to testify in criminal actions: 1. Insane persons who are in an insane condition of mind at the time when they are offered as witnesses, or who were in that condition when the events happened of which they are called to testify. 2. Children, or other persons, who, after being examined by the court, appear not to possess sufficient intellect to relate transactions with respect to which they are interrogated, or who do <pb n="607" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="19" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw> not understand the obligation of an oath. 3. A slave or free person of color shall not testify, except where the prosecution is against a person who is a slave or free person of color. 4. In prosecutions for seduction under the provisions of the Penal Code, the female alleged to have been seduced. 5. All persons who have been, or may be convicted of felony in this, or in any other State of the Confederate States, or of any other State or kingdom, unless such person or persons may have been par<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />doned for such crime: Provided, that no person convicted of the crime of perjury or false swearing within this State, or out of it, shall have his .competency as a wit<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ness restored by a pardon, unless the pardon so obtained shall by its terms specific<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ally restore his competency to testify in a court of justice, or unless his competency be otherwise restored by the proper authorities of this State. Art. 960. The sherilf shall receive from the county one dollar a day for each guard he employs, and the reasonable expense of such guard, not exceeding one dollar a day; and for the sup<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />port and maintenance of each prisoner in his custody fifty cents a day during the time he has charge of such prisoner, but in localities where the price of provisions may demand it, the presiding judge may, in his discretion, allow and approve a greater sum, not to exceed one dollar a day.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>March 6th, 1863</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to provide for the defence of the Frontier, and repealing certain provisions of an Act entitled &#8220;An Act to provide for the protection of the Frontier,&#8221; approved December 21st, 1861.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Whereas, under the provisions of &#8220;An Act to provide for the protection,of the Frontier of the State of Texas,&#8221; approved December 21st, 1861, a regiment, com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />posed of nine companies of cavalry, was organized and sworn into the service of the State of Texas for the term of twelve months: And, whereas, by the provisions of the seventh section of said act, the Governor was required to urge the acceptance of said regiment in the service of the Confederate States for the purpose of frontier protection: And, whereas, by reason of the provisions of said act, and the organiza<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion of said regiment, being inconsistent with the army regulations of the Confed<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />erate States, said regiment was not received into the service of the said Confederate States: And, whereas, to meet a provision of said army regulations, that each regi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment shall be composed of ten companies, the Governor disbanded said regiment, and on the 11th day of February, 1863, of the same material, completed the organi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />zation of another regiment composed of ten companies, denominated &#8220;the Mounted Regiment of Texas State Troops,&#8221; and mustered the same into the service of the State of Texas, under the command of Colonel James E. McCord, for the term of three years or during the war: Therefore,</p>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That said mounted regiment of Texas State Troops, organized and commanded as aforesaid, be, and the same is hereby recognized and acknowledged as the Frontier Regiment, con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />templated to be raised by the act of this Legislature aforesaid, subject to the pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />visions of said act, except as may be herein otherwise provided, and that the sum of eight hundred thousand dollars, ($800,000) or so much thereof as may be neces<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sary, be, and the same is hereby appropriated for the pay and support of said regi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment for the term of twelve months from the said 11th day of February, 1863, or until further action of the Legislature of this State.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That the Governor be, and he is hereby authorized to transfer said regiment to the service of the Confederate States: Provided such trans<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" /><pb n="608" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="20" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw> fer can be made upon the condition, and with the express understanding, that said regiment shall be retained and remain upon the Indian frontier of the State of Texas, for its protection; in which event said regiment shall be subject solely to the military authorities of the Confederate States, and no further charge for the pay or support thereof shall thereafter accrue against the State of Texas, but in the event no transfer of said regiment is made under the provisions of this act, said regiment shall remain upon said frontier for the full term of twelve months from the said February 11th, 1863, or until otherwise provided by law.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That so much of the &#8220;Act to provide for the protection of the frontier of the State of Texas,&#8221; approved December 21, 1861, or of any other act, as con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />flicts with the provisions of this act, are hereby repealed, and that this act take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>March 6th, 1863</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXVI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to regulate the distribution of cloth manufactured at the State Penitentiary among the families of Soldiers in the Confederate Army.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted bg the Legislature of the State of Texas, That no cloth shall be hereafter furnished by the Financial Agent of the State Penitentiary, on application by, or on behalf of the families of soldiers, unless the Chief Justice of the county in which the applicant shall reside shall certify, in his official capacity, to the truth of the facts stated in said application.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this act shall take effect from its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>March 6th, 1863</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXVII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to provide against the hostile invasion of the State of Texas by persons of color.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That any person of color invading or coming into the State of Texas during the present war between the Confederate States and the United States, with any armed force of the enemy, or for the purpose of waging war against the people of said State of Texas, or the people of any of the Confederate States, or of exciting insurrection amongst our slaves, or who being within the jurisdiction of said State, shall volun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tarily join or be found in the ranks of our enemies, rendering them any character of service, or in any manner whatever giving them aid and comfort, shall be dealt with as is hereinafter provided.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Upon the apprehension or capture of any such person by the authorities of the State, or upon any such person being turned over after capture, by the military authorities of the Confederate States to the civil authorities of the State, it shall be the duty of the State authority, having said person in custody, to forthwith notify the Judge of the District Court of his Judicial District of the fact, who shall there<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />upon designate a day, not less than ten nor more than twenty days after receiving such notification, when he will examine into the truth of the accusation made; said examination to be had after due notice thereof to the prisoner, in the county where said prisoner is detained in custody, and if upon said examination it shall appear that the prisoner comes under the provisions of the 1st section of this act, he shall be deemed to have forfeited his freedom, if he be free, and shall be ordered to be confined in the State Penitentiary at labor until the expiration <pb n="609" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="21" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw> of twelve months after the ratification of a treaty of peace between the Confederate States and the United States, and at the expiration of said period to be dealt with as hereinafter further provided.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. It shall be the duty of the Secretary of State, within sixty days after the ratification of the treaty of peace aforesaid, to procure a complete list of all persons then remaining confined in the Penitentiary under the provisions of this act, with a full description thereof, including the name, age, complexion, height and weight of every such person, and any Other peculiar mark by which they may be identified, together with the name, and residence, if known, of the alleged owner of such, if any, as claim to be slaves; which said list he shall cause to be published eight successive weeks in newspapers, published in three different portions of the State, one of which shall be at the Capital of the State, and no two of which shall be published in the same congressional district.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. At the expiration of twelve months after the ratification of the treaty of peace aforesaid, a list of all persons remaining in the Penitentiary under the pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />visions of this act, and not before then reclaimed as runaway slaves, shall be fur<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />nished by the Superintendent of the Penitentiary to the Secretary of State, and each person thus remaining shall be remanded to the custody of the Sheriff of the county wherein said Penitentiary is situated, who shall, within sixty days thereafter, expose said person to sale at public auction, before the court-house door of said county, to the highest bidder for cash, due notice of the person to be sold and the time, place, and terms of said sale having been first given, by advertisement published eight successive weeks next proceeding said sale, in newspapers published&#8212;one at the Capital of the State, and one in the county where said sale is to be made&#8212;or where no newspaper is published in said county, then in some newspaper published else where in the State, and not at the Capital, having the largest circulation in the county wherein said sale is to be made.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. The purchase money for each and every person thus sold shall be paid by the purchaser to the Financial Agent of the Penitentiary, and out of the proceeds of said sale the Sheriff shall be entitled to receive the same commissions and fees as are by lav allowed in cases of execution, and the balance, if any, after paying all costs, fees and expenses arising out of the custody, maintenance, advertisement and sale of the persons, after leaving the Penitentiary, shall be by said Financial Agent, paid into the State Treasury.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. The Sheriff making a sale of any person under the provisions of this act, shall forthwith thereafter make out in duplicate a full and clear account and state<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment of such sale under his hand, and return one to the Secretary of State and one to the Clerk of the County Court of the county wherein such sale was made, who shall record the same among the proper records of evidences of ownership of slaves.</p>
<p>Sec. 7. The provisions of the laws of the State authorizing free persons of color to choose their masters, or to leave the State, are hereby repealed as to all such persons now in the State, who have invaded the State since the beginning of the present war under the circumstances, or for the purpose specified in Section 1st, of this act, and such persons shall be dealt with in all respiects according to the pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />visions of this act: Provided, That it shall not be necessary to have any judicial examination of any such persons as are already confined in the Penitentiary, but such person shall be retained in such confinement for the term prescribed for other cases arising under this act as though they had been originally committed for that period.</p>
<p>Sec. 8. The owner of any slave held in custody under the provisions of this act may reclaim his property as a runaway slave at any time after said <pb n="610" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="22" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw> slave has passed, into the custody of the State authorities, and before he has been sold: Provided, That the proceedings for the reclamation of such slave shall be had at the cost of the claimant, and before the Chief Justice of the county where said slave may be held, in custody at the time said claim is made and be made a matter of record in said County Court, but the right to any person, either slave or free, actually sold as aforesaid, shall be and remain vested in the purchaser under said sale, and the owner of any slave thus sold, shall only, upon proving his property in said slave within three years after said sale, be entitled to receive from the State Treasury the amount paid into said Treasury on account of the sale of said slave.</p>
<p>Sec. 9. The District Attorney, Sheriff, Clerk, and any other officer whose ser<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vices may be required in any proceeding arising under the provisions of the 2d sec<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion of this act, or who may have already rendered service in any proceeding result<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing in the commitment of any person to the Penitentiary as contemplated in the provisions to the 7th Section of this act, shall be allowed the same fees and expenses as are allowed in cases of felony.</p>
<p>Sec. 10. That this act take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>March 6th, 1863</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXVIII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to punish any person or persons who may obtain goods from the State Penitentiary, under false pretences.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the legislature of the State of Texas. That if any person or persons, representing themselves as agents for the State of Texas, Confederate Government, widows, soldiers&#8217; families, or otherwise, and as such shall obtain goods from the acting agent of the penitentiary, and dispose of the same in any other way than as intimated by them to the said agent at the time of ob<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />taining the same, shall, on conviction thereof, in any Court of proper jurisdiction, be condemned to serve, at hard labor, in the State Penitentiary, not less than two nor more than three years for each and every such offence.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>March 6th, 1863</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXIX.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to amend An Act entitled An Act to amend the Sixteenth Section of &#8220;An Act to provide for the Assessment and Collection of Taxes, approved Feb. 11th, 1850, approved January 11th, 1862.&#8221;</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas. That section sixteen of &#8220;An Act to provide for the Assessment and Collection of taxes, &#8220;approved February 11th, 1850, be so amended as hereafter to read as follows: That if any person shall fail or infuse to pay the taxes imposed upon him and his prop<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />erty by law, until the first day of March next, succeeding the return of the assess<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment roll of his county, to the Comptroller, the Assessor and Collector, shall, by vir<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tue of his tax list, levy upon so much property liable to taxation, belonging to such person, if to be found in his county, as may be sufficient te pay his or her taxes. Pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vided, however, That if such person, his agent or attorney, shall point out to the As<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sessor and Collector sufficient property belonging to the party assessed in said county to pay said taxes, then the Assessor and Collector shall levy upon the prop<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />erty as pointed out, and in case the property levied on is about to be removed out of the county, the Assessor and Collector shall proceed to take possession of so <pb n="611" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="23" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw> much, thereof as will pay the taxes assessed, and costs of collection: Provided, fur<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ther, That any person having no real estate, or not a sufficiency thereof in the county where such assessment is made to pay his or taxes, and who is about to re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />move his or her property out of the county, after the return of the assessment roll, as aforesaid, and before the time specified by law for payment of taxes, then, and in that case, it shall be the duty of the Assessor and Collector, by virtue of his tax list, to levy upon and take into his possession so much of the property of such per<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />son liable to taxation, as may be sufficient to pay his or her taxes and costs, and the Assessor and Collector shall be entitled to the same fees as is by law allowed to Sheriffs for similar services.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That &#8220;An Act to amend the Sixteenth Section of An Act to provide for the assessment and collection of taxes, approved February 11th, 1850, approved January 11th, 1862&#8221; be and the same is hereby repealed, and this act take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>March 6th, 1863</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXX.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to authorize the Treasurer to pay out Confederate Treasury Notes for Civil and Military purposes.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Treasurer of the State is hereby authorized to pay out, for civil and military purposes, Confederate Treasury Notes, received and paid into the Treasury from the current revenue of the State, or from other sources.</p>
<p>Sc. 2. That any law, so far as it conflicts with the provisions of this act, is hereby repealed; and this act take effect from its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>March 6th, 1863</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXXI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>All Act to authorize the Commissioner of the General Land Office to issue to all persons and Corporations, such Land Certificates as they may be entitled to re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ceive under any General or Special Law of the State.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Commissioner of the General Land Office be, and he is hereby authorized to issue to all persons and corporations, such land certificates as they may be entitled to under any general or special law of the State.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>March 6th, 1863</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXXII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to amend an Act to amend an Act amendatory of the Laws to raise revenue by taxation, approved February 16th 1858, and to amend an Act entitled an Act to amend an Act amendatory of the Laws to raise revenue by taxation, ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />proved February 16th, 1858, approved April 8th, 1861, approved January 13th, 1862.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the first section of the above entitled act, approved January 13th, 1862, be so amended as to hereafter read as follows: There shall be levied and col<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lected for the use of the State an annual direct ad valorem tax of fifty cents upon each hundred dollars value of property, real and personal, including all cotton, <pb n="612" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="24" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw> wheat, flour, corn, and all other products of the soil, not in the hands of the pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dueer, in this State, except such property as may be exempt by law from taxation, which tax shall include the specific tax of four cents on the one hundred dollars pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vided by law, for the payment of the interest and principal of loan; and this tax shall be levied and collected on the assessment of the extas for 1863.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That the fourth section of said act shall hereafter read as follows: Sec<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion 4. That the first section of said act, approved April 8th, 1861, recited in the caption hereof, read as follows: There shall be assessed and collected of each person, firm, or public corporation, having money, or paper currency circulating as money, loaned at interest, buying or selling exchange, or buying or selling notes of hand, on all money, or paper currency circulating as money, hoarded or kept on hand, be<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />yond the som of two hundred dollars, a tax at the rate of fifty cents on each hun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dred dollars loaned, hoarded, or kept on hand, and on the amount of capital used for the purchasing of notes or exchange; and any person, firm, or public corpora<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion, having money, or paper currency circulating as money, or hoarded, loaned at interest, or money, or paper currency circulating as money, used in purchasing notes or exchange, or hoarded, or kept on hand, beyond the sum of two Hundred dol<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lars, who shall fail or refuse to give in the same for taxation, shall, upon conviction before any court having competent jurisdiction, forfeit ten per centum upon the amount of money, or paper currency circulating as money, thus loaned or kept on hand beyond two hundred dollars, or used in purchasing notes or exchange, and not given in for taxation, to the use of the informant and of the State, each one-half. That each and every person or firm enaged in the sale of goods, wares and mer<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />chandize, vinous or spirituous liquors, when sold in quantities of a quart or more, shall pay a tax of fifty cents on each hundred dollars value of such articles pur<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />chased for sale, or received for sale as agent or auctioneer by such person or firm; and it shall be the duty-of each Assessor and Collector in this State, once in every three months, or oftener, to call upon such person or firm so occupied or engaged in his county for an account of such purchase or consignments, to be made under oath; and every person or firm, when so called upon, who shall fail or refuse to furnish such Assessor and Collector with an account of such purchase or consignment, dur<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing the term for which the assessment is to be made, shall be liable to a penalty of fifty dollars for each failure or neglect, to be recovered on information of the As<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sessor and Collector, before any Justice of the Peace of the proper county, by a suit in the name of the State; and this specific tax levied shall exempt the goods, wares and merchandize of such person or firm from the ad valorem tax levied by this act.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. This act shall be in force and take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>March 6th, 1863</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<pb n="613" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="25" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXXIII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act supplemental to An Act to amend An Act to amend An Act to amend An Act amendatory of the Laws to Raise Revenue by Taxation, approved Feb. 16th, 1858; and to amend An Act entitled An Act to amend An Act amendatory of the Laws to Raise Revenue by Taxation, approved Feb. 16th, 1858, approved April 8th, 1861, approved the 6th day of March 1863.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the third section of the above recited act, approved April 8th, 1861, shall hereafter read as follows:</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That the 6th section of said act shall hereafter read as follows: &#8220;There shall be assessed and collected of each and every person pursuing the occupation of hawker, peddler of goods, or other articles not manufactured in the State, an annual direct tax of fifty dollars in each county in which he may pursue such occupation; and each and every person or firm keeping a billiard table, an annual direct tax of fifty dollars for each table so kept; of each and every person or firm keeping a nine or ten pin alley, an annual direct tax of forty dollars for each alley so kept; and of each and every person or firm keeping a hotel in towns of five hundred in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />habitants or less, ten dollars; in any town with over five hundred or under two thousand inhabitants, fifteen dollars; in any town with over two thousand and under five thousand inhabitants, twenty dollars; in every town with five thousand or over inhabitants, thirty dollars; on each and every person or firm keeping any restaurant, cook shop, or eating house, for pay or emolument, fifteen dollars; on each and every person or firm keeping any brewery, twenty dollars; on each and every person or firm keeping any beer shop, in which no vinous or spirituous liquors are vended, twenty-five dollars; on each and every person or firm keeping any dis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tillery of spirituous liquors, one thousand dollars on each and every still used by them in the distillation of any spirituous liquors from any kind of grain; on each and every person or firm keeping any storage warehouse, ten dollars; on each and every person or firm engaged in re-pressing cotton, twenty-five dollars; on each in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />surance company, fifty dollars; on each and every person or firm keeping a livery stable, fifteen dollars; on each and every toll bridge or ferry kept and used for pay as much as six months in the year, ten dollars; on each and every person en<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />gaged in the practice of dentistry, for pay or emolument, ten dollars; on each and every person having a fixed annual salary, whether as a public officer, or by private contract, twenty-five cents on each hundred dollars of such salary over and above five hundred dollars; upon each and every firm or person keeping a race track, forty dollars; on each and every person or firm pursuing the occupation of real estate broker, ship broker, cotton broker, or any commission business, for each and every such establishment, twenty dollars; on each person or firm engaged in the business of underwriting, or selling dry goods, groceries, or drugs and medicines, ten dollars; on each and every pawn-broker, forty dollars; on each and every person engaged in negro trading, for each negro sold, five dollars. It shall be the duty of every person or firm engaged in the occupation of hawker or peddler, billiard-table keeper, keeper of nine or ten pin alleys, cook shop, eating house or restaurant, race track, auctioneer, hotel keeper, pawn broker, or distillery, before en<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tering upon any such occupation, to first call upon the Assessor and Collector of the county in which he may intend to follow such occupation, and pay the tax required, and take a receipt for the same, setting forth the occupation, and the amount of tax paid, which receipt he shall file with the Clerk of the County Court, who shall thereupon issue to him a license to follow such occu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pation for the term for which the license tax has been paid, and any person <pb n="614" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="26" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw> failing to do so shall be required to pay a double tax. It shall be further the duty of the Clerk to keep a book, in which he shall enter the names of all persons ob<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />taining a license, with the amount of tax paid, and the date of the license, which book shall at all times be open to the inspection of the County Court, and to all officers, executive and judicial, of his county, a transcript of which book, certified by the Chief Justice; and under the seal of the court, he shall transmit to the Comp<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />troller, on the 1st day of June, in each and every year; for which service the Clerk shall be entitled to a fee of one dollar in each case, to be paid by the party obtain<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing the license.&#8221;</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this act take effect from and after its passage, and apply to the assessment of taxes for 1863.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>March 6th, 1863</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXXIV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to amend the ninth section of an Act entitled &#8220;An Act to provide for the registration of, deeds and other instruments of writing,&#8221; approved May 12th. 1846.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the ninth section of the above recited act shall hereafter read as follows: That when the subscribing witnesses to any instrument of writing may be dead, or their place of residence unknown or when they reside out of the State, an affidavit thereof may be made and attached to such instrument; after which it may be proved, for the purpose of being recorded, by the evidence of the hand-writing of the grantor or person who executed such instrument, and at least one of the subscribing wit<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />nesses; or when the grantor or person who executed such instrument signed by making his mark, by proof of the handwriting of both of the subscribing witnesses; which evidence shall consist of the deposition or affidavit of two or more disinter<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ested persons, in writing attached to such instrument; and the officer taking such proof shall make a certificate thereof, sign, and seal the same with his official seal.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>March 6th, 1863</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXXV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to punish persons who evade or assist in evading the Conscript Laws of the Confederate States of America.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That any person or persons within this State who shall wilfully discourage any other per<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />son or persons who are subject to the Conscript Laws of the Confederate States of America from enlisting in the military service of the Confederate States, with intent to evade the Conscript Laws, or who being subject thereto shall himself evade, or aid or assist any other person being subject thereto to evade the operations of said Conscript Laws, shall be guilty of a felony, and on conviction thereof shall be punished by imprisonment in the Penitentiary for a term not less than two nor more than five years, at the discretion of the jury.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That any person or persons who shall harbor, aid or assist any other person or persons who have been enrolled under the Conscript haws of the Confed<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />erate States, in evading or resisting the operation of said laws, shall foe punished by imprisonment in the Penitentiary for a term not less than one nor more than four years.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That if any person or persons who, being liable to be enrolled and <pb n="615" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="27" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw> conscripted under, the said Conscript Laws, shall by misrepresentation, falsehood or fraud, obtain a certificate of exemption therefrom, he shall be deemed guilty of an offence, and upon conviction thereof shall be punished by confinement in the Peni<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tentiary for a term of not less than one nor more than three years.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>March 6th, 1863</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXXVI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act authorizing the release of securities on the bonds of Assessors and Collectors.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the securities upon the bond of any Assessor and Collector of Taxes in this State, or any one of them, may at any time present a petition to the Chief Justice of the county, praying that such Assessor and Collector may be required to give a new bond, and that he or they may be discharged from all liability for the future acts of such Assessor and Collector: whereupon it shall be the duty of said Chief Justice, whether in term-time or vacation, to cause a citation to be issued and served upon such Assessor and Collector, requiring him to appear on a day named in the cita<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion, which may be in term time or vacation, and give a new bond. When such new bond has been required, an order to that effect shall be entered upon the min<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />utes of the County Court, requiring such Assessor and Collector to give the bond in ten days from the date thereof; and until the new bond is given, the powers of the Assessor and Collector shall be suspended: and when the new bond is given, the securities on the former bond shall be discharged from further liability thereon.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That if such Assessor and Collector shall fail to give the new bond re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />quired in ten days after the order requiring the same, his office shall be vacated, and the vacancy shall be filled as other vacancies in that office.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That this act shall be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>March 6th, 1863</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXXVII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act supplementary to An Act, entitled An Act to punish speculations in certain cases.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That if any person as agent for the family or families of Soldiers of the Confederate States, or of this State, or any other person, shall procure from the State Penitentiary any articles manufactured therein, and shall claim for and appropriate any portion thereof to his individual benefit, upon any pretext whatever, he shall be deemed guilty of a misdemeanor, and, upon conviction thereof, shall be fined in any sum not less than ten nor more than five hundred dollars for each offence. If any Quartermaster or Commissary, or person of the army of this State, or of the Con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />federate States of America, who is authorized or empowered to purchase supplies of any and every kind, for said army, shall be directly or indirectly interested in the purchase of such articles by himself or through an agent or agents, for his or their profits, or shall make profit or gain by such purchase beyond the fees or salaries allowed by law to them, he or they so offending shall be guilty of a felony, and shall be punished by confinement in the Penitentiary, at hard labor, for not less than two, nor more than ten years.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>March 6th, 1863</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<pb n="616" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="28" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXXVIII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act appropriating twenty thousand dollars, or so much thereof as may be necessary for the re-covering or repairing the roofs on the Capitol, the General Land Office, the old Land Office and Treasury buildings.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the sum of twenty thousand dollars, or so much thereof as may be necessary, be and the same is hereby appropriated to pay for re-covering or repairing the roofs of the Capitol, the General Land Office, the old Land Office, and the Treasury Buildings.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That the Board of Commissioners of Public Grounds and Buildings, be, and they are hereby authorized to contract for the re-covering or repairing the roofs of said buildings, with such persons and on such terms as they may think most advantageous to the State.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That the contracts entered into with said Commissioners for the re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />covering of any of such buildings, shall require such building to be covered with good, sound heart cedar or red cypress shingles; said shingles to be at least eighteen inches long, not less than five-eighths of an inch thick and when put upon such roof shall not show more than four inches at the lower end. Said shingles shall not average more than four inches in width.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. Such work may be let out in one or more contracts; and by such con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tract or contracts said Commissioners shall not agree to pay more than three-fourths of the price agreed to be paid for the work specified in the same at the time of the completion of said work, and on the completion of every job of such work so contracted for, said Commissioners shall examine the same, and if they find such work well done, they shall receive the same and pay to the contractor doing the same three-fourths of the price agreed to be given for the same; the remainder of the price agreed to be paid for such work not to be due until the expiration of twelve months from the completion of such work; at the expiration of which time it shall be the duty of said Commissioners to re-examine said work, and if they then find the same to be water-tight and the work done in a good and workmanlike manner, they shall, pay to such contractor the full amount agreed to be paid for such work.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. On entering into contract with any person or persons for the performance of such work, or any part of the same, it shall be the duty of such Commissioners to require of the person or persons agreeing to do such work, a bond, with two or more good and sufficient sureties, which bond shall be taken for double the amount agreed to be paid for the work contracted to be done; said bond shall be payable to the State of Texas, and shall be conditioned, that if said work be not done in accordance with the contract entered into between said Commissioners and such contractor or contractors, and in compliance with the provisions of this act, then such contractor or contractors, and his or their sureties, to be liable upon such bond for all the damages, the State may sustain by such failure; said contract and bond both to be filed in the office of the Secretary of State.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. That neither the receiving of any job of such work by said Com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />missioners nor the payment by them of a part or the entire amount to be paid to the contractors mentioned in this act, shall operate as a discharge of the obligations contained in the bond required to be given; but said bond shall remain in full force and virtue until the expiration of three years from the time of the completion of the job of worn mentioned in said bond. And, if at any time during said period of three years said Commissioners shall ascertain that the job of work mentioned in said bond has not been done in a good and workmanlike manner, and according to contract, they shall <pb n="617" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="29" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw> deliver the bond of such contractor to the Attorney General and direct him to bring suit upon the same.</p>
<p>Sec. 7. That this act take effect from its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>March 6th, 1863</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXXIX.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to provide for electing Senators and Representatives to the 10th Legis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lature, for the year 1863, in counties occupied by a public enemy.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That in all cases where Senatorial or Representative Districts are, in whole or in part, occupied by a public enemy so that elections can not be held in such districts for members of the 10th Legislature, as required by law, the legally qualified electors of such district or districts may east their votes at any precinct or precincts in the State for a citizen or citizens of their respective districts for Senators and Repre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sentatives to represent them in the 10th Legislature, and the several Chief Justices of the Counties where such votes shall be east are hereby required to certify such votes so cast, and return the same to the Secretary of State, specifically stating the district for which such votes were given, and whether for Senator or Representative, under the same regulations as are prescribed in other cases; and the person or persons having the highest number of votes for the respective offices shall, on production, of a certificate of the fact from the Secretary of State, be entitled to repre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sent the district for which they were elected in the Senate or House of Representa<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tives of the 10th Legislature, as the case may be.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>March 6th, 1863</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XL.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to provide necessary assistance for Families and other dependents of Officers and Soldiers.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas. That each County Court for administrative police in the respective county, is charged with the duty of providing necessary assistance for families and other dependents of officers and soldiers, who have been or may be in the military service of the Con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />federate States of America, or of this State, during the pending war with the United States of America; and the court shall conduct this business with appropriate regularity, keeping full minutes of its proceedings in a book, not containing any other matter; and such book shall be always subject to the inspection of any orderly citizen.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Such business as may be transacted at any regular term of the court, or at any special term which may be ordered by the Chief Justice, he causing written notice thereof to be given to each County Commissioner, or left for him at his resi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dence with some member of the family, or posted on his door, at least five days in advance of the time appointed for such special term.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. In such business the Court may obtain money, or other means, either by public appropriation or by private donation; and the court may so use any funds which it may now have, or may bereafter acquire, derived from taxation or other ordinary source; and the court shall raise funds therefor by extraordinary taxation, as may be proper to supply necessary assist<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ance for the families or individuals to be provided for, so that their persons shall have suitable subsistence and comfort, and property in their charge <pb n="618" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="30" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw> shall have prudent management- to prevent loss or waste, and to promote appro$$priate income; provided such extraordinary taxes shall be collected, as needed, ac<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cording to the State assessment as it may be from time to time; and further pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vided the amount of tax collected shall not exceed the sum of seventy-five cents on the one hundred dollars. Within ten days after the levy of the tax it shall be the duty of the County Court to report to the Comptroller of Public Accounts, by cer<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tificate under seal of the county, the rate of taxation so levied by such court; and on the receipt of such report, by the Comptroller, it shall be his duty to notify the Assessor and Collector of each county in the State of the rate of taxation so levied by each of the several counties so reported to him.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. In such business the court may administer the means under its control, not only in any mode which may be prescribed by law, but consistently therewith, by any other suitable instrumentalities.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. Should the court fail to perform its duty, and so leave without adequate care any of the foregoing subjects, the District Court and Judge of the respective locality shall have jurisdiction to compel the County Court to perform its duty; and such jurisdiction may be exercised on the complaint of any person who may present such grievance, whether it be to himself or to any other person or persons from whom the complaint may be made; provided such control shall not be exercised un<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />til at least a majority of the members of the County Court shall have been cited to appear and answer the complaint; and the citation shall be executed at least ten days before the time for answering; and the mode of service shall be by giving a copy to the person or by leaving it at his residence with some member of his family, or posted on this door.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. This Act shall be cumulative of, and not a repeal of an &#8220;Act authorizing the County Courts of the several Counties in this State to levy and collect a special tax for war purposes on all property subject to taxation by the State,&#8221; approved January 1st, 1862, but said Act shall be and remain in force.</p>
<p>Sec. 7. This Act shall be in force from its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>March 6th, 1863</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XLI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to supply a deficiency in a certain appropriation for paying Officers and Soldiers of State Troops.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That, in addition to the former appropriation of three hundred thousand dollars, the further sum of two hundred thousand dollars, or so much thereof as may be neces<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sary, is appropriated out of any money in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated, to carry out the provisions of &#8220;An Act to provide for auditing and settling all claims against the State on account of volunteer companies, called out by the Gov<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ernor or Committee of Safety, and for the defense of the State, and providing pay<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment for the officers and men thereof,&#8221; approved January 4th, 1862.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. This act shall be in force from its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>March 6th, 1863</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<pb n="619" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="31" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XLII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to provide for the sale of Lots in the City of Austin.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Comptroller is authorized and required to sell all of the lots in the city of Austin not heretofore sold by the State, except such as have been reserved for public pur<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />poses, not embracing in this exception the lots ground the Capitol grounds that remain unimproved, which are hereby subjected to sales.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. After six weeks notice by publication in one newspaper in each of the cities of Austin, San Antonio and Houston, the sale shall be made at the Comp<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />troller&#39;s office, by public auction, to the highest bidder, for each lot, to be separately sold for prompt payment in Treasury warrants of this State.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. In tie discretion of the Comptroller sale may be made, either of all the lots under one notice, or of portions under different notices.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. This act shall be in force from its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>March 6th, 1863</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XLIII</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act making further appropriation for the use and support of the State Gov<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ernment, for the years 1862 and 1863.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted, by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the fol<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lowing sums be, and they are hereby appropriated for the use and support of the State Government for the years 1862 and 1863, in addition to the sums appropri<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ated by the act approved January 13th, 1862:</p>
<p>For the support of the Lunatic Asylum........................... $10,000 00</p>
<p>Expenses incurred, under the provisions of an act providing for disposi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion of runaway slaves, approved April 8, &#8217;61....................... 2,000 00</p>
<p>For purchase of fire-wood and stationery, and for fitting up the Capitol for the next Legislature, and for taking care of the Capitol, and for repairing and taking care of the furniture........................ 3,000,00</p>
<p>For extra clerk hire in State Department, in addition to former appro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />priation...................................................... 500 00</p>
<p>For wood and porter hire in State Department......................... 200 00</p>
<p>For additional appropriation to Secretary of State, for postage................... 100 00</p>
<p>For stationery to Secretary of State, additional...................... 300 00</p>
<p>For additional appropriation for Adjutant General&#39;s Office for wood and porters.............. 100 00</p>
<p>For additional appropriation for same, for postage....................... 150 00</p>
<p>For additional appropriation for same, for stationery.......................... 300 00</p>
<p>To pay the salaries of Librarians of the Supreme Court at Galveston, Ty<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ler and Austin................................................ 900 00</p>
<p>For postage for Executive Department 300 00 For stationery............ 300 00</p>
<p>For postage, for Comptroller&#8217;s office........... 800 00</p>
<p>For stationery.................................... 1,000 00</p>
<p>For supplying the deficiency in the appropriation for taking scholastic census of 1862 and 1863....................................... 800 00</p>
<p>Audited claim of J. W. Magoffin, as allowed by S. A. Maverick, Thos. J. Devine and P. W. Luckett, to the au<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dited and allowed by the Comptroller, on the certificate <pb n="620" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="32" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw> signed by them on the 3d December 1862......................... 6,345 60</p>
<p>Pension of Cynthia Ann Parker, for the years 1862&#8212;&#39;63................. 200 00</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this act take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>March 6th, 1863</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER LXIV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to amend the 2d section of and supplementary to an Act to perfect or<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ganization of the State Troops, and place the same on a war footing,&#8221; approved Dec. 25th, 1861.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the second section of the act recited above shall hereafter read as follows, viz:</p>
<p>All officers, State and County, of the State of Texas, except Coroners, Justices of the Peace, Constables and Notaries Public, and all officers of the Confederate States, including such clerks and employees as they by law are entitled to; officers, clerks, directory and guards of the Penitentiary; superintendents and teachers in the deaf and dumb, blind and lunatic asylums; professors and teachers of schools and academies having as many as twenty or more scholars; one captain, two pilots and two engineers to each steamboat actually in the service of the State or of the Confederate States; telegraphic operators, actually engaged as such; one apothe<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cary for each apothecary store actually engaged in business; presidents, secretaries, superintendents, engineers, conductors and road masters of railroads; mail con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tractors and carriers; ferrymen on public roads, mechanics actually engaged in the manufacture of spinning jennies or cotton cards; persons having substitutes in the army of the Confederate States who were exempt from military service to the State of Texas; licensed ministers of the Gospel, and such millers as may be necessary to each steam or water mill that grinds for the public, and as many engineers as may be necessary for such steam mill in actual operation, shall be exempt from military service to the State of Texas as prescribed by this act.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That during any invasion, insurrection or rebellion, whenever in the opinion of the Governor the interest of the State demands that the State Troops, or any portion of them, should be called into service, or whenever the President of the Confederate States shall call upon the Governor of this State to furnish an addi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tional quota of soldiers for the prosecution of the present war, or upon a call upon the Governor by the General Commanding this department, the Governor shall, by proclamation, order into camp, from any one or more brigades, a sufficient number of troops to fill such requisition, or to quiet such rebellion, or insurrection, in the following manner, to-wit: He shall order the Brig. Generals of such brigades as to him may seem proper, to cause each Captain within his brigade to muster his company on any designated day, and cause the names of each and evqry commissioned, non-commissioned officer and private to be placed in a hat or box, and the proportion of said companies as may be ordered by the BrigaTdier General shall be drawn by the Captain, or any person whom he may designate, from the hat or box, and such persons as are drawn, shall immediately repair to the camp designated by the Governor, or Brigadier General. And it shall be the duty of the Brigadier General to proceed, immediately, to organize the troops drawn into service, within his brigade, into companies of not less than sixty-four, rank and file, and officered as is required by the laws of the Con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />federate States; and when so officered, may be transferred, by the Governor, into the service of the Confederate States, for a period of not more than twelve months, and shall not, by any comnionder, he carried beyond the lim<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" /><pb n="621" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="33" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw> its of the State of Texas. And the Brigadier General shall, upon the organization of such companies, forward a muster roll of each company to the Adjutant and In<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />spector General for preservation&#8212;provided, any citizen may have the privilege of volunteering if he desires.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That Company, battalion and regimental drill as suspended during the continuance of the present war.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. That Enrolling officers, whilst engaged as such, shall be entitled to the pay of 2d Lieut, of Cavalry, to be paid out of the Treasury of the State, the same to be approved by the Brigadier General Commanding the brigade; and that this act be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Passed <date>March 7th, 1863</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
</div2>
<pb n="622" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="34" />
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">JOINT RESOLUTIONS.</head>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER I.</head>
<opener>
<salute>Joint Resolution, in relation to an Express between the Mississippi and Rio Grande Rivers.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Whereas, The occupation of the Lower Mississippi by the enemy, and the peculiar condition of Texas, in consequence of the war, make it impossible, by the ordinary mails, to obtain the needful, early and reliable information from Richmond and the States East of the Mississipi River: And, Whereas, it is of the greatest importance, that during the war, rapid and correct information should be had between our posts on the Rio Grande and Richmond, through some point on the Mississippi&#8212;There<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fore,</p>
<p>Be it Resolved by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Hon. Postmaster General be, and he is hereby requested, under authority of the Confederate States, to contract with some suitable person or persons to run a Pony Express, during the war, between Brownsville, on the Rio Grande, via San Antonio and Houston, to some safe point on the Mississippi, and back again, twice a week, the trips to be made, each way, in five days, if practicable, to carry letters only, and at such rates of postage as may be deemed right and proper by the Post Master General.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>February 9th, 1863</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER II.</head>
<opener>
<salute>Joint Resolution.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it resolved by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the people of Texas, acknowledging with heartfelt gratitude the fovar of God in the brilliant achievements of our Confederate armies, do hereby, formally and sincerely, tender to the Officers and Privates of the Military Service of the country, from the State of Texas, the thanks and praises they have so justly merited, by their self<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sacrificing devotion to their country, and their many deeds of valor upon every battle-field of the Confederacy.</p>
<p>In the name of a gallant State and a gallant people we thank you. In the name of your mothers, your wives, and your sisters, we thank you for your gallant deeds.</p>
<p>You have won for yourselves imperishable renown. You have won for your State the highest honors..</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Resolved, That while our brave troops are battling so gloriously for the dearest interests of our people, we recognize it as a sacred obligation to provide for their comfort, and to support and cherish their families at home.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. Resolved, That the faith of the State of Texas is hereby pledged to our soldiers in the field, that their families shall be nourished and Supported during the war.</p>
<pb n="623" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="35" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<p>Sec. 4. Resolved, That the Governor be instructed to have a copy of this reso<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lution transmited to every Texas regiment now in the service, with the request that it may be read out to every company.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>April 21st, 1863</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER III.</head>
<opener>
<salute>Joint Resolution, in relation to the Indebtedness of the Confederate States.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Whereas, the Legislature of the State of Texas considers the faith of the Con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />federate States fully and sacredly pledged to the payment of all indebtedness which has been or may be incurred by the Confederate States, during the war between said Confederacy and the United States of America, and that should any State com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />posing said Confederacy withdraw therefrom, from any cause, before the payment of such indebtedness shall have been fully completed, such withdrawing State shall be bound to the payment of her pro rata portion of such remaining indebtedness&#8212; Therefore,</p>
<p>Section 1. Be it Resolved by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That should the State of Texas, from any cause, withdraw her association as a member of the Confederate States, before the indebtedness of said Confederate States is fully paid, the faith of the State is hereby pledged to the payment of her pro rata portion of such remaining indebtedness, to whoever the same may be due.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That the Governor of the State transmit to the President of the Con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />federate States, and to the Governor of each of said States, a certified copy of this resolution.</p>
<p>Approved February 27th, 1863.</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER IV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>Joint Resolution, in relation to Public Printing.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it Resolved by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That during the continuance of the war between the Confederate States and the United States, the Secretary of State, Comptroller and Treasurer, or a majority of them, are required to procure to be done, all such printing as may be necessary for the use of the State, under existing laws; and, in so doing, they shall be governed as nearly as may be by the existing laws regulating the public printing, but may de<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />part therefrom as to prices to be paid, and other matters, so far as may be necessary, in order to accomplish said object.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. This Joint Resolution shall be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>March 6th, 1863</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER V.</head>
<opener>
<salute>Joint Resolution, concerning certain Salines.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Resolved, That the Military Board be instructed to inquire into the expediency of working certain Salines and salt works near Double Mountain, on the North<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />western frontier of this State; and, that should they deem the enterprise ex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pedient, they will immediately take such measures as may be necessary for work<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing the same, under the supervision of State authority: and that the sum of five thousand dollars, or so much thereof as may be necessary, be appropriated out of any funds in the Treasury, not otherwise appropirated, for the purpose of putting the same in successful operation.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>March 6th, 1863</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<pb n="624" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="36" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER VI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>Joint Resolution, in response to Joint Resolution of the General Assembly of the State of Florida, approved December 11th, 1862.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Whereas, With nations as with individuals, the consciousness of sympathy and support strengthens and encourages them in the struggle, in the onward path of duty, against difficulty and danger, and operates as an incentive to renewed ex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ertion&#8212;Therefore,</p>
<p>Resolved, 1. That the people of Texas fully appreciate the pledge of sympathy and assistance tendered by the General Assembly of the State of Florida to her sis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ter States of the Confederacy, by joint resolution, approved December 11th, 1862. That from the acknowledged gallantry of the people of that State, nothing less could have been expected&#8212;more it would not be possible for them to offer.</p>
<p>Resolved 2. That while the people of Texas cannot hope to surpass the devotion to a common cause manifested by their gallant compatriots of Florida, they trust that when the history of the present war has been written, it will show that Texans have stood shoulder to shoulder with the people of any State of this Confederacy, in battling for their rights, to sustain which they mutually stand pledged.</p>
<p>Resolved 3. That we reiterate the sentiments contained in joint resolution of this body, approved January 13th, 1862, pledging Texas to the devotion of her every energy to the prosecution of the present war until its sucessful termination in a peace, concluded upon the basis of the unqualified recognition of the independence of the Confederate States.</p>
<p>Resolved 4. That the Governor of this State be requested to forward a copy of these resolutions to the Governor of the State of Florida.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>March 6th, 1863</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER VII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>Joint Resolution, concerning Retaliation.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Resolved by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That we heartily approve of the proclamation of the President of the Confederate States, to retaliate for the iniquities of Gen. Ben Butler, (better known as Butler the Beast,) in the State of Louisiana, as well as his retaliation proclamation against General McNeill, for the murder of citizens in the State of Missouri, and we trust that retaliation will be strictly and rigidly practiced by our government in all such cases of outrage, and we pledge the people of this State to sustain the President of the Confederate States in all his measures of retaliation against those who outrage humanity by such an utter disregard of the rules of civilized warfare.</p>
<p>Resolved, That the Governor of this State transmit a copy of this resolution to our members in Congress, and that they lay it before the President.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>March 6th, 1863</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER VIII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>Joint Resolution providing for the payment of the expenses of the investi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />gation, by the Joint Committee of both Houses, of the condition of the Peni<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tentiary.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Be it Resolved by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the members of the Joint Committee raised at this Session of the Legislature to examine the condition of the Penitentiary shall be entitled to the same mileage in travel<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" /><pb n="625" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="37" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw> ing to and from Huntsville as members of the Legislature in traveling to and from the Legislature, and the same per diem pay while there discharging their duties as members of the Legislature: and the Chairman of the Committee shall be authorized to give certificates of milage and per diem to the members of the Committee, and for all other expenses necessarily incurred in the progress of their investiga<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tions, and the Comptroller shall draw his warrant upon the Treasurer for such amounts as shall appear to be due on such certificates, to be paid out of the con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tingent fund of this Legislature, and the Committee shall have authority to adjourn at the close of the present Session to meet for the discharge of their duties at Huntsville on the 6th of April next.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>March 6, 1863</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER IX.</head>
<opener>
<salute>Joint Resolution, requesting His Excellency, the Governor, to disband all military organizations known as the Coast Guards or Spy Companies.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it Resolved by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That it is the opinion of this body that the necessities which may have justified such military organizations, as above indicated, have ceased to exist, having been fully covered by a prudent and competent Confederate force, which can perform all the services which was contemplated to be performed by said companies.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. It is further Resolved, That in the opinion of this body, his Excellency would be acting in compliance with the wishes of a large majority of the citizens, living within the counties in which those organizatons have been made, that they be forthwith disbanded and ordered to be enrolled among the militia, within then<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />respective brigades.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Passed <date>March 7th, 1863</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER X.</head>
<opener>
<salute>Joint Resolution, in regard to Trade.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Sec. 1. Resolved, That the power to regulate commerce is, by the Constitution of the Confederate States, vested in Congress: and that the power assumed by the military authorities of this department, to allow, control and prohibit the exporta<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion and transportation of cotton, is unwarranted in law, is an encroachment upon the rights of the people and upon the power of Congress, and is an exercise of power which Congress itself has refused to exercise by act approved 21st May, 1861, and which tends to the impoverishment of one portion of the people, and to the aggrandizement and corruption of another, and to expel the planter and lawful trader from the market, to create monopolies, and to cause scarcity of supplies and. consequent high prices.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That our Senators in Congress be instructed and our Representatives re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />quested to see that the Rio Grande trade is not unlawfully closed or obstructed and that such regulations be prescribed to the officers of customs as may be necessary to secure to the people the benefits of said trade and a return of supplies and that the Governor forward a copy of these Resolutions to our Senators and Representa<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tives in Congress.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Passed <date>March 7th, 1863</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
</div2>
<pb n="626" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="38" />
<pb n="627" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="39" />
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">INDEX TO THE GENERAL LAWS.</head>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">A</head>
<p>Appropriations. Page</p>
<p>contingent expenses extra session, IX Legislature.......................... <ref>7</ref></p>
<p>per diem and mileage, extra session, IX Legislature.................... <ref>7</ref></p>
<p>for the relief of sick and wounded Texan soldiers................................ <ref>11</ref></p>
<p>to defray the expenses of the State troops, called out by Gen. Hudson. <ref>15</ref></p>
<p>to re-cover certain public buildings................................. <ref>28</ref></p>
<p>to supply a deficiency, for the pay of officers and soldiers, Texas State troops............................................ <ref>30</ref></p>
<p>for support of State government, for 2 years, 1862 and 1863............... <ref>31</ref></p>
<p>Administrator&#8217;s and Executor&#8217;s,</p>
<p>see &#8220;estates of deceased persons.&#8221;</p>
<p>Assessor and Collector. securities on bonds of to be released........................... <ref>27</ref></p>
<p>Austin City. providing for the sale of public lots therein............................ <ref>21</ref></p>
<p>Alien Oath. persons taking it excluded from office, serving on juries, &#38;c........... <ref>12</ref></p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">B</head>
<p>Bail. in oases of felony, to be given in open court............................. <ref>18</ref></p>
<p>if court is not in session, to be taken by the sheriff....................... <ref>18</ref></p>
<p>Blaneo County.</p>
<p>see &#8220;counties.&#8221;</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">C</head>
<p>Counties. regulating judicial proceedings in counties in possession of, or en<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dangered by the enemy................. <ref>3</ref></p>
<p>Blanca county attached to 4th Judicial District.................. <ref>7</ref></p>
<p>Kendall county attached to 4th Judicial District.................. <ref>7</ref></p>
<p>providing for the election of members of the X Legislature, from counties possessed by the enemy.......................... <ref>29</ref></p>
<p>County Clerk. duties concerning Notaries Public....................... <ref>14</ref></p>
<p>Chief Justices. duties further defined soncernine elections.................. <ref>16</ref></p>
<p>County Courts. regulating proceedings therein, relative to the estates of deceased persons.............................................. <ref>5</ref></p>
<p>may levy a specific tax..................................................... <ref>29</ref></p>
<p>records of when a county is in possession of the enemy, to he <pb n="628" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="40" /><fw type="header" place="top">Index.</fw> removed and proceedings to be bad in an adjoining county.................. <ref>3</ref></p>
<p>Counterfeiting. parties may be prosecuted where the offence was committed, or the coin passed.................................. <ref>18</ref></p>
<p>Cattle. to regulate the sale of beef cattle.................. <ref>10</ref></p>
<p>Code. penal, inciting insurrection among slaves, by public enemy.............. <ref>13</ref></p>
<p>articles 34, 349 and 745 A, amended, and article 669 A, added............ <ref>12</ref></p>
<p>of criminal procedure, articles 156, 190 A, 280, 644 and 960 amended.. <ref>18</ref></p>
<p>district attorney to attend the trial ot habeas corpus cases.......<ref>8</ref></p>
<p>fee for such attendance............................................ <ref>18</ref></p>
<p>when absent the judge shall appoint a person to represent the State.. <ref>18</ref></p>
<p>Color, Free Persons of. to provide against a hostile invasion of the State, by.................. <ref>20</ref></p>
<p>Conscript Acts. punishing persons evading, or assisting in evading.................. <ref>26</ref></p>
<p>Confederate States. joint resolution in relation to the indebtedness of.................. <ref>35</ref></p>
<p>Confederate Treasury Notes, see &#8220;Treasurer.&#8221;</p>
<p>Coast Guards. joint resolution recommending the disbanding of.................. <ref>37</ref></p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">D</head>
<p>District Court. proceedings of, in counties possessed by the enemy.................. <ref>3</ref></p>
<p>time of holding, in the 4th District changed.................. <ref>7</ref></p>
<p>records of, where a county is in possession of the enemy, to be re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />moved to an adjoining county......................... <ref>3</ref></p>
<p>District Attorney see &#8220;code of criminal procedure.&#8221;</p>
<p>Domain Public. price of, fixed....................................... <ref>11</ref></p>
<p>Deeds, &#38;c. of trust, property sold under, to bring 9-10th of its appraised value.. <ref>9</ref></p>
<p>registration of............................................ <ref>26</ref></p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">E</head>
<p>Elections. laws amended.............................................. <ref>16</ref></p>
<p>Estates of Deceased Persons. laws concerning, amended........................... <ref>5</ref></p>
<p>executors and administrators may qualify before the clerk, or any county officer............................. <ref>5</ref></p>
<p>claims against the estate to be presented within 12 months, excluding the time of the executor&#8217;s or administrator&#8217;s absence from the State. <ref>5</ref></p>
<p>Evidence. lav of, in criminal cases amended......................................... <ref>19</ref></p>
<p>Enrolling Officers. see State troops.</p>
<p>Execution. property sold under, to bring 9-10ths of its appraised value........... <ref>9</ref></p>
<pb n="629" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="41" /><fw type="header" place="top">Index.</fw>
<p>Express. Page joint resolution recommending, between the Rio Grande and the Mis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sissippi rivers.................................... <ref>34</ref></p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">F</head>
<p>Frontier Regiment. law creating it, amended................................. <ref>19</ref></p>
<p>Forgery. party may be prosecuted where the offense was committed, or the paper altered......................................... <ref>18</ref></p>
<p>Florida. joint resolution in response to the general assembly of.................. <ref>36</ref></p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">H</head>
<p>Hospital Fund. appropriation for....................................... <ref>11</ref></p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">I</head>
<p>Invasion by &#8220;Persons of Color.&#8221; provided against................................... <ref>20</ref></p>
<p>Insurrection. see &#8220;slaves.&#8221;</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">T</head>
<p>Judgment. to be rendered in certain cases.......................................... <ref>9</ref></p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">K</head>
<p>Kendall County. see &#8220;counties.&#8221;</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">L</head>
<p>Legislature, the 10th. providing for the election of members, from counties possessed by the enemy............................................ <ref>29</ref></p>
<p>Limitation, Statutes of. suspended during the war, except in cases of assault and battery, &#38;c... <ref>6</ref></p>
<p>Land Office. price of domain regulated.......................................... <ref>11</ref></p>
<p>commissioner to issue certificates to certain persons.................. <ref>23</ref></p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">N</head>
<p>Notaries Public. laws defining the office, and duties of, amended.................. <ref>14</ref></p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">O</head>
<p>Officers. death or resignation of to be certified to Secretary of State by chief justice................................. <ref>16</ref></p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">P</head>
<p>Public Domain. regulating the price of............................................ <ref>11</ref></p>
<p>Penal Code. see &#8220;code&#8221;......................................... <ref>12</ref></p>
<p>Public Enemy. inciting insurrection among slaves, penalty.................. <ref>13</ref></p>
<p>persons giving aid and comfort to, excluded from serving on juries, etc., <ref>12</ref></p>
<p>sales made by to be void..................................... <ref>15</ref></p>
<pb n="630" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="42" /><fw type="header" place="top">Index.</fw>
<p>Perjury on False Swearing. Page. parties may be prosecuted where the offence was committed or the false statement used..................................... <ref>18</ref></p>
<p>Penitentiary. punishing those obtaining goods therefrom under false pretences..... <ref>22</ref></p>
<p>financial agent permitted, to purchase machinery.................. <ref>18</ref></p>
<p>regulating the distribution of cloth manufactured.................. <ref>20</ref></p>
<p>joint resolution providing for the payment of the investigating com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mittee................................................. <ref>36</ref></p>
<p>Public Buildings. certain ones to be recovered............................... <ref>28</ref></p>
<p>Public Printing. joint resolution concerning.................................. <ref>35</ref></p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">Q</head>
<p>Quartermasters and Commissaries. see &#8220;speculation&#8221;.................................. <ref>2</ref></p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">R</head>
<p>Retaliation. joint resolution concerning.................. <ref>36</ref></p>
<p>Records. see &#8220;district&#8221; and &#8220;county court.&#8221;</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">S</head>
<p>Sheriff. may take bail in certain cases of felony.......................... <ref>18</ref></p>
<p>compensation for employing guard and supporting prisoners.................. <ref>19</ref></p>
<p>Securities of Assessors Bonds. securities on assessors bonds, providing for their release.................. <ref>27</ref></p>
<p>Supreme Court. Galveston spring term to be held in Austin.................. <ref>3</ref></p>
<p>Surveyors County. to prescribe the residence of................................. <ref>3</ref></p>
<p>Slaves. defining the offence of inciting insurrection among.................. <ref>13</ref></p>
<p>persons prohibited from giving or selling weapons to.................. <ref>12</ref></p>
<p>punishment of those aiding and assisting the public enemy.................. <ref>20</ref></p>
<p>Stray Laws. operations suspended during the present war................................... <ref>6</ref></p>
<p>vicious animals may be strayed.................. <ref>6</ref></p>
<p>Speculation. to provide for the punishment of, in certain cases.................. <ref>27</ref></p>
<p>Specie. to be provided to pay the specie tax.......................................... <ref>8</ref></p>
<p>Soldiers. for the relief of sick and wounded..................................... <ref>11</ref></p>
<p>to support the families of.......................................................... <ref>13</ref></p>
<p>families and dependents of, further provided for and assisted.................. <ref>29</ref></p>
<p>joint resolution of thanks to State Troops................................... <ref>34</ref></p>
<p>to defray the expenses of those called out by Gen. Hudson.................. <ref>15</ref></p>
<p>act to perfect the organization of, amended.......................... <ref>32</ref></p>
<p>who exempt from military duty, Governor may order a draft and how, <ref>32</ref></p>
<p>regimentai battalion and company drill suspended.................. <ref>32</ref></p>
<p>enrolling officers to receive the pay of a Lieutenant of cavalry......... <ref>32</ref></p>
<p>Salines.</p>
<p>joint resolution concerning............................ <ref>35</ref></p>
<pb n="631" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="43" /><fw type="header" place="top">Index.</fw>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">T</head>
<p>Taxes. Page. assessment and collection of............................ <ref>22</ref></p>
<p>law relative to specie tax amended.......................... <ref>8</ref></p>
<p>Taxation. law to raise revenue by, amended........................... <ref>23</ref>-<ref>25</ref></p>
<p>Treasurer. authorized to pay out C. S. treasury notes for civil and military pur<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />poses................................... <ref>23</ref></p>
<p>Trade. joint resolution in regard to............................................... <ref>37</ref></p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">W</head>
<p>Witnesses. who incompetent.................................. <ref>18</ref></p>
</div3>
</div2>
<pb n="632" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="44" /><fw type="header" place="top">Index.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">THE STATE OF TEXAS, DEPARTMENT OF STATE.</head>
<p>I, R. J. Townes, Secretary of State of the State of Texas, do certify that the Extra Session of the Ninth Legislature of said State, convened, in accordance with the Proclamation of the Governor, at Austin, on Monday, the second day of Feb<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ruary one thousand eight hundred and sixty-three, and adjourned on Friday, the 6th day of March the same year.</p>
<p>And, I further certify that, the acts and resolutions contained in this volume, are true copies, taken from the original rolls deposited in this Department, which have been carefully compared.</p>
<p>Given under my hand, and the Seal of the Department of State affixed, at the the City of Austin on the seventh day of June one thousand eight hun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" /> <floatingText rend="left"><body><p>[L. S.]</p></body></floatingText>dred and sixty three.</p>
<closer>
<signed>R. J. TOWNES, Secretary of State.</signed>
</closer>
</div2>
</div1>
</body>
</text>