<text xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 UNTtite%20(1.3).xsd" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="TEI">
<body>
<pb n="633" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="1" />
<div1 type="article">
<head type="main">SPECIAL LAWS <lb/>OF THE <lb/>EXTEA SESSION <lb/>THE NINTH LEGISLATURE <lb/>OF <lb/>THE STATE OF TEXAS</head>
<byline>PUBLISHED BY AUTHORITY</byline>
<byline>AUSTIN 1863</byline>
<pb n="634" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="2" />
<pb n="635" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="3" />
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">SPECIAL LAWS</head>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER I.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to release to the heirs of Colonel Benjamin F. Terry, all the right, title and interest, of the State of Texas, in and to the property owned by said Terry, at the time of his death, and devised by his last will.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Whereas, Colonel Benjamin F. Terry, of the County of Fort Bend, and State of Texas, commanding the Regiment of Texas Rangers, died heroically fighting in the cause of Southern Independence, at Woodsonville, Kentucky, on the 17th day of December, 1861, and doubts have arisen as to the effect of a devise contained in his last will, duly admitted to Probate in the County Court of Fort Bend County&#8212; Therefore,</p>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That all right, title, and interest, legal or equitable, existing, or which by legal proceedings, might be established in behalf of the State of Texas, in and to all the property belonging to Col. Terry at his death, and devised in his last will, be and the same is hereby relinquished, released, surrendered and conveyed to the heirs of said Col. Benjamin F. Terry; and the same, so far as the State of Texas is concerned or has interest, shall descend and pass to them in the same manner as if said Terry had died in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />testate as to the same.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. This act shall be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>February 25th, 1863</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER II.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to revive and continue in force, &#8220;An act entitle &#8216;An act to incorporate the Galveston and Houston Junction Railroad Company,&#39;&#8221; approved, April 8th, 1861, and to amend said act.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted, by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Act, entitled &#8220;An act to incorporate the Galveston and Houston Junction Railroad Company,&#8221; approved April 8th, 1861, be and the same is hereby revived and con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tinued in force as fully and with the same effect as though the Railroad contem<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />plated to be built, and connection made, under and by the provisions of said act of incorporation, had been fully completed before the first day of January, A. D., 1863.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. The fourth section of said act is hereby amended, so that the same shall hereafter read as follows, to-wit: &#8220;The capital stock of said company shall not exceed the sum of five hundred thousand dollars, divided into shares of one hundred dollars each, and the persons who were acting as President and Directors of said Company, on the thirty-first day of December, A. D., 1862, together with J. S. Sydnor, shall be considered, and act as such Presi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" /><pb n="636" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="4" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw> dent and Directors of said Company until the regular time fixed by the By-Laws of said Company in force previous to January 1st, 1863, shall have&#8221; arrived, when the stockholders may elect a new Board of Directors, and other officers, as provided by the by-laws of the Company. Said Company may make all By-Laws and regu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lations for the Government of the same and its affairs, not in contravention of the laws of the State, and may alter the same at pleasure; and the rights of all persons who were stockholders in said Company, on the 21st day of December, 1862, are hereby fully preserved as Stockholders therein, under this act, and the said original charter. The principal office of said Company shall be kept at the City of Gal<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />veston, but the Company may, at their option, keep such office at the City of Houston, during the continuance of the war between the Confederate States and the United States. Said Company may acquire and hold such Railroad locomotives, and rolling stock, and fixtures, as they may think proper, and may, at their option, rent or hire the same to any other Railroad Company; and the right of way for their Railroad, and all rights of property, and action acquired by said Company, previous to December 31st, 1862, are hereby fully vested in said Company, under this act and said original charter.&#8221;</p>
<p>Sec. 3. The fifth section of said act is hereby amended, so that the same shall hereafter read as follows, to-wit: &#8220;Said Company shall complete said road, and make said connection between the Galveston, Houston and Henderson, and Texas Central Railroads, of the same gauge as those roads, oh or before the 1st day of January, A. D., 1864, unless prevented by the public enemy, in which event they shall complete the same, within six months after the close of the war between the Confederate States and the United States.&#8221;</p>
<p>Sec. 4. This act shall be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>February 25th, 1863</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER III.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act for the relief of the parties holding lands under Daniel Monroe.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That all that portion of land sold by Daniel Monroe, as his head-right league, on Little River, in Milam County, between what is known as the Robertson Block and the grant to said Monroe, and which has been declared by the Supreme Court of the State of Texas, to be vacant land, is hereby ceeded to parties holding under Monroe, and all right of the State of Texas to said land is relinquished to the purchasers of Monroe, and those holding under him.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this act be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>February 27th, 1863</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER IV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to incorporate the Comal Manufacturing Company.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That John F. Torrey, Henry Bunge, Hermon A. H. Bunge, and their associates and suc<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cessors, be and they are hereby constituted and declared, to be a body politic and corporate, under the name and style of &#8220;The Comal Manufacturing Com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pany,&#8221; with capacity to make contracts, to have succession, and a common seal, to make by-laws for the government and regulation of its affairs, and in said corporate name, to sue and be sued, to buy, receive, and possess, movable and immovable property, and to sell, alienate and dispose of the same, and generally to do and perform all such acts and things as may be necessary <pb n="637" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="5" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw> and proper for, or incident to the fulfillment of its objects, or maintenance of its rights under this act, and consistent with the Constitution of this State.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. The said Company shall have the right, power, and authority to own, erect, establish, maintain, and operate machinery, and buildings with all necessary fixtures, in Comal County, for the manufacture of cotton or woolen goods, or such other articles as said Company may at any time choose to manufacture.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. The capital stock of said Company shall not at any time exceed five hundred thousand dollars, to be divided into shares of one hundred dollars each, and the holders of such shares shall constitute said Company, and each member shall be entitled to one vote, in person or by written proxy, for each and every share, he or she may own upon the books of the Company, and under such rules and regulations as may be, from time to time, prescribed by the by-laws of said Company.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. The capital stock of said Company shall be transferable, only upon the books of said Company, in such manner, and subject to such rules and regula<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tions, as the majority of the stockholders may, from time to time, prescribe.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. All the corporate powers of the Company shall be exercised by a Board of Directors, composed of not less than three nor more than nine stockholders, to be elected on the first Tuesday in January, of each year, at the office of said Com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pany, which shall be kept at the town of New Braunfels, in Comal county, State of Texas&#8212;Provided, that the first election may be held immediately after the organization of the Company, and the Board so elected shall continue in office until the first annual election thereafter, and until their successors are elected. In all elections, those persons receiving a plurality of votes shall be considered duly elected, and, in the event of no election taking place on the day herein appointed, the President shall cause another election to be held within thirty days thereafter, and give public notice of the same. No person shall be eligible to fill the office of Director unless he be the owner of, at least, ten shares of the capital stock of said Company, standing on the books of the Company, in his name, for at least thirty days, next preceding the day of election; and, in case of failure no elect at the stated time, the Board of Directors, then in office, shall continue in office until there be an election.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. The Board of Directors shall elect a President from their number, fill vacancies, and appoint such other officers and agents as they may deem necessary, and remove the same at pleasure, and require security for the faithful performance of their duties. Said Board shall also prescribe the time for the payment of in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />stallments, or assessments upon stock, and the amount of such installments or assessments; shall have the right to declare the forfeiture of such stock for non<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />payment, and do, or cause to be done, all other acts and things which they deem necessary or proper, in conducting the affairs of said Company. A majority of said Board of Directors shall constitute a quorum for doing business, and the Board shall have the right to appoint a Vice-President from their number, to act in case of the absence of the President.</p>
<p>Sec. 7. All the instruments of writing executed by the President, or in his ab<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sence, by the Vice-President, and by the Secretary, under the seal of the Com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pany, with the consent of the Board of Directors, shall be valid and binding on the Company.</p>
<p>Sec. 8. After said Company shall be organized and commence business, its cap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ital stock and property shall be exempt from all taxes for the term of five years.</p>
<pb n="638" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="6" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<p>Sec. 9. This act shall take effect and be in force from and after its passage, and continue for twenty-five years.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>March 2nd, 1863</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER V.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to incorporate the &#8220;Jackson Manufacturing Company.&#8221;</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted, by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That S. P. &#38; B. P. Hollingsworth, of the State of Texas, and James Crow, of the State of Ala<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />bama, their associates and successors be, and are hereby constituted and declared to be a body politic and corporate, under the name and style of the &#8220;Jackson Manufacturing Company,&#8221; with capacity to own property, real and personal, make contracts, to have succession, a common seal, to make by-laws for its government, and in its corporate name, sue and be sued, to grant and receive, and, generally, to do and perform such acts and things as may be necessary and proper for, or incident to the fulfillment of its objects, or maintenance of its rights, under this act, and consistent with the provisions of the State Constitution.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That the said Company be, and is hereby established, with the right to erect, own, maintain and operate a woolen and cotton manufactory, and other articles, separately or conjointly, at such place or places as said Company may select.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That the capital stock of said Company shall be divided into shares of one hundred dollars each, and the holders of said shares shall constitute said Company, and said capital stock shall not exceed two hundred thousand dollars.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. That the affairs and business of said Company shall be conducted by a Board of Directors, not less than three nor more than five, who shall be elected by the stockholders, at such time as may be appointed, and annually thereafter,&#8212; Provided, that in case of failure to elect at the stated time, the Board of Directors, incumbent, shall continue in office until there be an election, the time for which may be fixed by said Board, whereof, reasonable notice shall be given.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. That no person shall be eligible as a Director unless he is a member of the Company. The said Board shall elect a President from their number, fill vacan<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cies, and appoint such officers as they may deem necessary, and require security for the faithful performance of the duties, also, prescribe the time for the payment of installments or assessments, to declare the forfeiture of such stock for non<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />payment, and to do, or cause to be done, all other acts or things, which they may deem necessary, or proper, in the conducting the business of said company. A majority of said Board of Directors shall constitute a quorum to do business.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. That the parties named in this act are hereby appointed Commissioners, and invested with the right of organizing said Company, and, that this charter shall expire at the end of twenty-five years from the passage of this act.</p>
<p>Sec. 7. That this act shall take effect from its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>March 2nd, 1863</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<pb n="639" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="7" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER VI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to authorize the County Courts of Smith and Walker Counties to order, and cause to have collected immediately, the Special Tax, known as the War Tax.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the County Courts of Smith and Walker Counties be, and they are hereby author<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ized to order, and cause to be collected immediately, the Special Tax, known as the War Tax; and levied under the provisions of &#8220;An Act authorizing the County Courts of the several Counties in this State, to levy and collect a special tax, for war purposes, on all property subject to taxation by the State:&#8221; approved January 1st, 1862.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>March 2nd, 1863</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER VII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to authorize the establishment of Ferries, at the crossings of the Waco and Austin road, on the Lampasas and Leon Livers, in the County of Bell, without obtaining license.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That any person or persons are hereby authorized and empowered to establish and keep ferries, without obtaining license therefor, paying tax on entering into bond, at the crossings of the Austin and Waco, roads, on the Lampasas and Leon Rivers, in the County of Bell, being liable, only, as common carriers.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That the Comity Court of Bell County shall establish the rates of ferriage across said streams, and the ferrymen shall keep posted up at their ferries, a list of said rates, and if any such ferryman shall charge, and receive from any person, a higher rate of ferriage than has been established for his ferry by the said Court, he shall forfeit and pay to such person, five dollars for each and every such offence, to be recovered by action before any Justice of the Peace of said Bell County, with costs of suit, and the oath of the complainant shall be received in evidence.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>March 2nd, 1863</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER VIII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to incorporate the Dallas Male and Female College.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That J. M. Patterson, W. H. Thomas, M. T. Johnson, R. M. Gano, A. M. Moore, J. W. Throckmorton. P. Taylor, T. G. Hawpe, B. W. Stone. J. J. Good, S. B. Pryor, J. J. Eakins, A. C. Halleck, R. B. Scott and John N. Bryan, and their sucessors in office, be and they are hereby constituted a Board of Trustees, of the Dallas Male and Fe<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />male College, established in the town of Dallas, in Dallas County, and State of Texas, and which by this act, is incorporated by the name of the &#8220;Dallas Male and Female College,&#8221; with perpetual succession for the term of fifty years; and, by which name, may sue and be sued, plead and be impleaded, buy and sell property real, personal and mixed&#8212;may have a common seal, and do and perform any and all act or acts that may be necessary to carry out the provisions of this act, for the benefit of said College; and may establish such rules and laws for the government of the same as may be deemed necessary, and which may not be inconsistent with <pb n="640" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="8" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw> the Constitution and laws of the State of Texas, or of the Confederate States, and in short may do and perform all other acts incident to similar institutions, for the benefit of the same.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That said College shall have a made and female department, in which shall be taught all branches of education usually taught in institutions of a similar character, to which maybe added the science of war, and shall be open to pupils of any religious denomination, but shall never become sectarian in its character, nor shall the peculiar doctrines of any religious denomination ever be taught, therein.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That said Board, and their successors in office, shall have power to re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ceive as donations, or otherwise, any lands, tenements, moneys, rents, goods, chattels and effects that may be given, granted, donated or devised to said College, for the purpose of education, not to exceed, in value, exclusive of the College buildings and College grounds, two hundred thousand dollars.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. That the persons hereinbefore named shall constitute the first Board of Trustees, and shall hold their office as hereinafter provided. Said Board shall be divided into three classes, and numbered first, second and third classes; the classes to be determined by lot, and the said Board shall be self-created. The first class shall hold their office one year from the fourth Wednesday in June, 1863, at the expiration of which time an election shall be held to fill their vacancy. The second class shall hold their office for two years from the fourth Wednesday in June, 1863, at the expiration of which time an election shall be held to fill their vacancy. The third class shall hold their office for three years from said fourth Wednesday in June, 1863, at the expiration of which term an election shall be held to fill their vacancy; and thus an election of one of said classes shall be held an<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />nually thereafter, on the fourth Wednesday in June in each and every year to fill vacancies. The members of said Board shall be the electors in effecting their own succession, the President only having a vote in case of a tie. All elections by said Board shall be by ballot, under such rules as said Board may prescribe. The Presi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dent, Secretary and Treasurer to be elected by said Board, and to hold their offices for such term and time as their by-laws may direct, and may be dismissed from office for any cause upon a vote of two-thirds of said Board.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. That said Board shall have the power to employ a President and all necessary Professors and teachers for said College, and may dismiss them at pleas<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ure. The President and Professors of said College shall have power to confer all the literary scientific and other degrees usually conferred in similar institutions.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. That said Board shall be organized by the first day of June, 1863, and as early as practicable thereafter, and within three years therefrom shall procure and employ a teacher in military science, who shall instruct such male pupils as may desire the same, over the age of ten years, and who may be physically able to per<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />form military duty in the science of arms.</p>
<p>Sec. 7. That said Board shall have a regular semi-annual meeting on the 4th Wednesday in January and June in each year, and at any other time when five of its members may so require, and give five days previous notice of the time to a full quorum of the other members. Any seven of said Board shall constitute a quorum to do business.</p>
<p>Sec. 8. That all conveyances of property of said College, made by said Board may be acknowledged by the President of said Board, as required by law of private persons, and every diploma awarded to any student of said College shall be signed by the President and Professors of said College, and may be countersigned by the President of said Board of Trustees in his official capacity.</p>
<pb n="641" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="9" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<p>Sec. 9. That said Board of Trustees shall attend the regular commencement, at the close of each session of ten months, at which time a full report in regard to said institution shall be prepared and signed by the President and Faculty of the institution and endorsed by the President and Secretary of said Board of Trustees.</p>
<p>Sec. 10. That this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>March 3, 1863</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER IX.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to authorize the County Courts of Bastrop and other counties herein named, to regulate the pay of Sheriffs of said counties, in certain cases.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the County Courts of Bastrop, Kaufman, Van Zandt, Henderson, Red River, Titus, Tarrant, Collin, Grayson, DeWitt, Denton, Wilson, Rayette, Lavaca, Davis, Bowie, Gonzales, Ellis, Anderson, Rusk, Panola, Falls, Freestone, Wood, Lamar, Hidalgo, Guadulupe, Hill, Upshur, Trinity, Cameron and Starr counties be, and they are hereby authorized to allow the Sheriffs thereof, for summoning jurors in the Dis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />trict Court, serving election notices, notice on overseers of roads, attending on the District and County Courts, and doing all other business not provided for, such sum or sums of money as said Court may deem sufficient for said service, not to exceed two hundred dollars, to be paid out of the Treasury of said county.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>March 4, 1863</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER X.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to incorporate the Texas Paper Manufacturing Company.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That David Richardson, of the County of Travis, Samuel Mather, of the County of Williamson, and Dr. Theodoer Koester, of the County of Comal, are hereby created a body cor<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />porate, by the name of the &#8220;Texas Paper Manufacturing Company,&#8221; and by that name to make contracts, to have a common seal, to make by-laws for its govern<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment, and the regulations of its affairs, to sue and be sued, to plead and be impleaded; may transfer their rights by succession or assignment, and also by that name and style they and their successors may purchase, hold and convey such real and personal estate as may be necessary for the purpose of carrying out the objects of this charter.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That said Company shall have the right to erect and establish, in the County of Comal, machinery and establishments for the manufacture of paper, and operate the same.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That the capital stock of said Company shall be Fifty Thousand Dollars, to be divided into Fifty Shares of One Thousand Dollars each, and said company shall have authority to increase said capital to One Hundred Thousand Dollars.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. That the affairs of said Company shall be managed by a Board of five Directors, each of whom shall own at least five Shores of the Capital stock of said Company. A majority of said Directors shall constitute a quorum to do business, and shall have power to appoint a President from <pb n="642" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="10" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw> their own number, and to fill all vacancies that may occur in the Board of directors, from death, resignation, or otherwise. After the first election of directors, by virtue of this Act, all subsequent elections shall be held at such time and place as they shall appoint. In case of failure to elect said directors at such time and place, the Corporation shall not be dissolved for that cause, but the President and Directors previously elected shall continue to perform their duties until successors are chosen.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. That the Directors shall be chosen by the Stockholders of said Company, and that each Stockholder shall have one vote for each Share that he may own, and vote in person or by proxy.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. That the President and Directors of said Company shall have full authority to adopt all such Rules, Regulations and By-Laws as they may consider necessary to effect the object of this Act of Incorporation, not inconsistent with this Act or the Laws of the State, and may appoint or remove at pleasure all agents or other employees necessary to transact the business of said Corporation.</p>
<p>Sec. 7. That every person subscribing for any of the Capital Stock of said Com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pany, shall pay such proportion thereof at the time of subscribing as may be directed by the terms of original subscription lists, and after the election of the first Board of Directors, the balance shall be paid at such times and upon such terms as said Directors may designate. That in all cases where further payment may be required, notice thereof shall be duly given at least thirty days before said payment.</p>
<p>Sec. 8. That if any Stockholder shall fail or refuse to pay the balance of his sub<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />scription at the time required by said Directors, it shall be lawful at any time after due notice has been given, in accordance with the preceding section of this Act, for said Directors to sell the Shares of said Stockholders at public auction, after ten days previous notice of said sale has been given by public advertisement, and the purchaser of said Shares shall be subject to all the liabilities, and entitled to all the benefits of the defaulting Stockholder. Provided said Manufactory goes into opera<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion during the present war it shall be exempt from taxation for five years.</p>
<p>Sec. 9. That this Act shall be in force and take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>March 5, 1863</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to incorporate the Houston Mutual Aid Association.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted, by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That Charles S. Longcope, Thomas M. Bagby, Alexander McGowen, Thomas W. House, William J. Hutchins, James Sorley and Jathem L. Briggs, and such other persons as they may bereafter associate with under the provisions of this act be, land they are hereby constituted a body politic and corporate under the name and style of &#8220;The Houston Mutual Aid Association,&#8221; by which name they and their successors or assigns are declared capable in law of suing and being sued in any of the courts of this State; of holding property, real, personal and mixed; of selling and conveying the same at will; of having a common seal, and of doing and performing whatever may be proper and necessary to be done for the conducting and management of a general mercantile business, not contrary to the Constitution and laws of the State.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That said Association may organize witn such officers, and may nact such by-laws for its government as may, from time to time, be deemed <pb n="643" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="11" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw> necessary and proper, and shall have all such rights and privileges as are by law incident to or necessary for corporations of a similar character.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That this act shall take effect from and after its passage and remain in force during the continuance of the present war between the Confederate States and the United States, and for the term of twelve months thereafter.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>March 5, 1863</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to incorporate the Texas Iron Company.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted, by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That J. S. Nash, Wm. Nash, James Alley, H. P. Perry, Josiah D. Perry, Jonathan Adams, R. R. Haynes and Thomas D. Powell, citizens of the State of Texas, their associates and successors be, and are hereby created a body corporate and politic under the name and style of the &#8220;Texas Iron Company,&#8221; with capacity to own property, real and personal, in such quantities as may be necessary for the legitimate objects of this corporation, make contracts, have succession and a common seal, to make by-laws for its government, and in their corporate name to sue and be sued, to grant and receive, and generally to do and perform such things and acts as may be necessary and proper for or incident to the fulfilment of their objects or maintenance of their rights under this act, not inconsistent with the Constitution of the State.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That said Company is hereby created with the right to erect, own, main<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tain and operate a manufactory of iron and steel of every description whatever, and all other articles of which iron or steel may form a part, at such place or places as said Company may select, within the counties of Marion and Davis.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. The capital stock of said Company shall be divided into shares of one hundred dollars each, and the holders of said shares shall constitute said Company, and said capital stock shall not exceed one million dollars.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. The corporators mentioned in section 1st of this act shall, within ninety days from its passage, cause an election to be held for a Board of Directors, of not less than three nor more than seven in number, who shall be elected by the stock<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />holders at such time and place as may be appointed, and annually thereafter; pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vided that in case of failure to elect at the stated time, the Board of Directors in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cumbent shall continue in office until there be an election, the time for which shall be fixed by said Board, whereof notice shall be given, as required by law governing other corporations. The corporators under this act shall be considered a Board of Directors until the first election of Directors has taken place.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. No person shall be eligible as a Director unless he is the owner of at least ten shares of stock of the Company. The said Board shall elect a President from their number, fill vacancies until the next succeeding stockholders&#8217; meeting, and appoint such officers as they may deem necessary, and require security for the faithful performance of their respective duties; also, they shall have power to pre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />scribe the time and place for the payment of installments or assessments on stock, declare the forfeiture of stock for non-payment, and to do or cause to be done all other acts and things which they may deem necessary and proper in conducting the business of said Company. A majority of the Board of Directors shall constitute a quorum for the transaction of business, but in no case shall a Director vote by proxy.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. This act shall take effect from its passage, and be in force for the period of twenty-five years.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>March 5, 1863</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<pb n="644" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="12" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XIII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to incorporate the Texas Lead and Copper Mine Company.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted, by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That Louis Wells, Josephus M. Steiner and Geo. W. White, and their associates and successors, are hereby declared a body corporate and politic by the name and style of the &#8220;Texas Lead and Copper Mine Company, &#8220;and by that name they, their associates and successors shall be capable of sueing and being sued, plead and be impleaded in all the courts of this State, and shall be capable in law of contracting and being contracted with, and acquiring, by purchase, donation or otherwise, property, real, personal and mixed, holding and conveying the same as said corporation may think proper.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That the State of Texas doth hereby relinquish to said corporation all the right, title and claim which the said State of Texas has in and to all minerals that may be found on any patented land or located lands which said Company may select and purchase for the manufacture of lead or working of copper, provided the amount does not exceed twelve hundred and eighty acres; and, provided further, that the manufacture of lead and copper by said Company shall be commenced within twelve months from the passage of this act.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That the charter of said Company shall be in force for twenty years, and that this act be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>March 5, 1863</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XIV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to repeal an act entitled &#8220;An Act concerning the Alamo Ditch in the city of San Antonio, and to regulate irrigation therefrom,&#8221; approved April 8th, 1861.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That an act entitled &#8220;An Act concerning the Alamo Ditch, in the city of San Antonio, and to regulate irrigation therefrom,&#8221; approved April 8, 1861, be, and the same is hereby repealed, and. that the Alamo Ditch, in the city of San Antonio, be and remain under the control of the city authorities of San Antonio, as it was before the passage of the above recited act.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>March 6, 1863</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to suspend the corporate authority of the town of San Patricio.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Cor<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />porate authority of the town of San Patricio shall suspend all action in business affecting the interests of said town or the county of San Patricio, until twelve months after the close of the pending war between the Confederate States of America and the United States of America.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. This act shall be in force from its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>March 6, 1863</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<pb n="645" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="13" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XVI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to incorporate the San Antonio Mutual Aid Association.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the offi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cers and members of the &#8220;San Antonio Mutual Aid Association,&#8221; as now organized, be and they are hereby constituted a body corporate and politic under the name and style of the &#8220;San Antonio Mutual Aid Association,&#8221; and by that name they and their successors are declared capable in law of sueing and being sued in any of the courts of this State, of holding property, real, personal and mixed, or selling and conveying the same at pleasure, of having a common seal, and of doing and per<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />forming whatever may be proper and necessary to be done for the conducting of a general mercantile establishment, not contrary to the Constitution and laws of this State.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That the officers and members of said Association may enact such by-laws for their government as they may, from time to time, deem necessary and proper; and shall have all such rights and privileges as are by law incident to or necessary for corporations of a similar character, and that this act take effect from and after its passage, and shall continue in force until one year after the close of the war be<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tween the Confederate States and the United States.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>March 6, 1863</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XVII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to incorporate the Columbus Mutual Aid Association.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That C. W. Tait, Stephen Harbert, E. P. Whitfield, Isam Took, A. M. Campbell and such other persons as they may bereafter associate with them under the provisions of this act, be, and they are hereby constituted a body politic and corporate, under the name and style of the Columbus Mutual Aid Association, by which name they and their successors or assigns are declared capable in law, of sueing and being sued in any of the courts of this State, of holding property, real, personal and mixed, of selling and conveying the same at will, of having a common seal, and of doing and performing whatever may be proper and necessary to be done for the conducting and manage<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment of a general mercantile business, not contrary to the Constitution and laws of the State; provided that after the persons incorporated shall supply themselves, they shall sell to families of soldiers at cost.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That said Association may organize with such officers and enact such by<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />laws for its government as may, from time to time, be deemed necessary and proper, and shall have all such rights and privileges as are by law incident to or necessary for corporations of a similar character.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. This act shall take effect from and after its passage, and remain in force during the continuance of the present war between the Confederate States and the United States and for the term of twelve months thereafter.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>March 6, 1863</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XVIII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to incorporate the Caldwell County Mutual Aid Society.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That E. Heppenstall, O. O. Searcy, W. A. Clark, W. S. Carpenter, J. S. Proctor, W. R. Cowan and G. W. Shoof, and others whom they may associate with <pb n="646" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="14" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw> them, be, and they are hereby created a body politic and corporate to be known by the name and style of the &#8220;Caldwell County Mutual Aid Society,&#8221; and by that name may sue and be sued in any court of law or equity, and may have a common seal.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. The capital stock of said Company stall not exceed twenty-five thousand dollars, to be divided into shares of fifty dollars each. The Association may organ<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ize by electing a President and five Directors, who shall be stockholders, and when organized the said President and Directors shall have the management of the Asso<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ciation.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. The said Company may purchase and deal in any kind of provisions, fam<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ily supplies and merchandise, and after supplying themselves, they may sell the re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mainder of said provisions, supplies and merchandise, provided that they shall sell to the families of soldiers at cost, carriage and expenses, and to others at a profit not exceeding twenty-five per cent on cost, carriage and expenses; the object of the Association being mutual aid in procuring supplies for the needy and protection against speculators and extortioners.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. This act to be in force from its passage and remain in force for twelve months after the ratification of a treaty of peace between the Confederate States and the United States.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>March 6, 1863</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XIX.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to incorporate the Washington County Mutual Aid Association.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That A. H. Rip<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />petoe, Jno. P. Key, J. D. Giddings. Gilbert Buchanan, N. Kavanaugh and Jno. H. Dawson, and such other persons as they may bereafter associate with them under the provisions of this act, be, and they are hereby constituted a body politic and cor<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />porate under the name and style of the Washington County Mutual Aid Associa<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion, by which name they and their successors or assigns are declared capable in law of sueing and being sued in any of the courts of this State, of holding property, real, personal and mixed, of selling and conveying the same at will, of having a com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mon seal, and of doing and performing whatever may be proper and necessary to be done for the conducting and management of a general mercantile business, not con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />trary to the Constitution and laws of the State, provided that after the persons in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />corporated in this act shall supply themselves, they shall sell to the families of sol<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />diers at cost.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That said Association may organize with such officers and enact such by-laws for its government as may, from time to time, be deemed necessary and proper, and shall have all such rights and privileges as are by law incident to or necessary for incorporations of a similar character.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. This act shall take effect from and after its passage, and remain in force during the continuance of the present war between the Confederate States and the United States and for the term of twelve months thereafter.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>March 6, 1863</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XX.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to incorporate the Goliad Aid Association.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Terns, That D. Hardeman, William Evans, A. H. Biseoe, J. Alison Dill, J. A. Robbins, John A. Clark, J. M. Brown and Pryor Lea, all of Goliad county, or any <pb n="647" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="15" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw> three of them as Commissioners, may organize a Joint Stock Association, to consist of the persons before named, or any of them, and their associates and successors, on such legal terms as they may adopt, for the purposes therein stated; and such asso<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ciation, when organized, shall be a corporate body by the name of the Goliad Aid Association, and in that name shall have, all the ordinary privileges of a corporation.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. The business of the Association will be to furnish necessaries for its mem<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />bers, for families and other dependents of officers and soldiers who have been or may be in the military service of either the Confederate or the State Government, and for general market, all within the area of Goliad and neighboring counties, at prices which shall not exceed the aggregate of cost and twenty-five per centum thereon, allowing for current rates of exchange.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. For accomplishing said objects the Association may trade in any suitable manner.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. The capital stock may be one hundred, thousand dollars or any less amount, in shares of one hundred dollars or any less amount, as the Association may determine.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. This charter shall continue in force until the expiration of one year after the ratification of a treaty of peace between the Confederate States of America and the United States of America.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. This act shall be in force from its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>March 6, 1863</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
</div2>
<pb n="648" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="16" />
<pb n="649" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="17" />
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">JOINT RESOLUTIONS.</head>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER I.</head>
<opener>
<salute>Joint Resolution requesting the Governor to procure the detail and exemption of certain persons therein named, to work in Messrs. Eubanks &#38; Co.&#8217;s Cotton Card Factory.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it resolved by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Gov<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ernor of the State is hereby requested to procure the detail, if it can be done, of John Curtis, a private in Capt. Strawhorn&#8217;s company, and David Armstrong, pri<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vate in Col. A. Smith&#39;s command, and James Shaw in Capt. D. Lively&#8217;s company, of the Confederate States Army, to work in the cotton and wool hand card factory of Messrs. Eubanks &#38; Co., of Williamson county, Texas, and all other hands which they may employ in the business of the factory, to be exempt from military duty so long as they shall be employed in said factory, and so long as said factory shall make a reasonable number of cards per hand.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That said Eubanks &#38; Co. shall make a report every sixty days, to the Governor of the State, of the number of hands employed, liable to military duty, and the number of pairs of cards made monthly.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That this Joint Resolution shall take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>February 19, 1863</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER II.</head>
<opener>
<salute>Joint Resolution in regard to John R. Baylor.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it resolved by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That in view of the patriotic zeal, the known gallantry, and the past efficient and valuable mili<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tary services of our fellow-citizen, Col. John R. Baylor, the President of the Con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />federate States be, and he is hereby respectfully requested to reinstate said Baylor in his command, as heretofore, or place him in some similar position of usefulness, and that His Excellency, the Governor, be requested to transmit a copy of this reso<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lution to His Excellency. President Davis.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>March 6, 1863</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<pb n="650" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="18" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER III.</head>
<opener>
<salute>Joint Resolution of thanks to General J. B. Magruder and others.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Resolution 1. Be it resolved by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the thanks of the Legislature are hereby tendered to Gen. J. B. Magruder, and the of<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ficers and men under his command, for the brilliant victory which they gained over the Federalists at Galveston, on the 1st January last; and to Major O. M. Wat<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />kins, and the officers and men under his command, for their gallant conduct at Sabine Pass, and the recapture of that fort, and capturing the blockading vessels of the enemy; and to Major Dan Shea, and the officers and men under his command, for their firm defence of the town of Lavaca; and to Maj. Hobby, and the officers and soldiers under his command, for the repulse of the enemy&#8217;s attack on Corpus Christi, the commencement of our successes on the Texan coast; and to Captains Ireland and Ware, and the officers and soldiers under their command, for their ex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ploit in the capture of Capt. Kittridge and his men, near Corpus Christi; and to Captains Ireland and Wilkie, and the officers and soldiers under their command, for their good conduct in defeating the enemy&#8217;s attempt to capture one of our vessels, and in capturing his barges in the bay of Corpus Christi; and to Captains Santos Benavides and Refugio Benavides, and officers and men, for the vigilance, energy and gallantry displayed by them in pursuing and chastising the banditti infesting the Rio Grande frontier.</p>
<p>Res. 2. That the Governor be requested to transmit a copy of these Resolutions to Gen. J. B. Magruder and the other officers mentioned, with the request that they make them known to the officers and men under their command.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>March 6, 1863</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER IV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>Joint Resolution in relation to the contract of the Military Board with Sherrard Taylor &#38; Co., for Pistols.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Be it resolved by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Military Board be, and they are hereby instructed and directed to rescind their contract with Sher<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />rard Taylor &#38; Co., of the town of Lancaster, in Dallas county, for making pistols (Colt&#8217;s revolvers) upon their, the said Sherrard Taylor &#38; Co., refunding to said Board the money they have advanced on said contract, together with the legal in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />terest thereon from the time it was advanced.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Passed <date>March 7, 1863</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
</div2>
<pb n="651" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="19" />
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">INDEX TO SPECIAL LAWS.</head>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">EXTRA SESSION NINTH LEGISLATURE.</head>
<p>Page</p>
<div4 type="section">
<head type="main">A</head>
<p>Alamo Ditch. act regulating irrigation therefrom, repealed....................... <ref>12</ref></p>
<p>Anderson County. County Court to regulate the pay of Sheriff in certain cases........... <ref>9</ref></p>
</div4>
<div4 type="section">
<head type="main">B</head>
<p>Bastrop County. County Court of, to regulate the pay of Sheriff in certain cases......... <ref>9</ref></p>
<p>Baylor, Col. John R. joint resolution concerning............................. <ref>16</ref></p>
<p>Bowie County. County Court to regulate the pay of Sheriff in certain cases................. <ref>9</ref></p>
</div4>
<div4 type="section">
<head type="main">C</head>
<p>Caldwell County. Mutual Aid Association incorporated.................. <ref>13</ref></p>
<p>Cameron County. County Court to regulate the pay of Sheriff in certain cases......... <ref>9</ref></p>
<p>Collin County.</p>
<p>County Court to regulate the pay of Sheriff in certain cases............. <ref>9</ref></p>
<p>Columbus Mutual Aid Association.</p>
<p>act of incorporation...................................... <ref>13</ref></p>
<p>Comal Manufacturing Company.</p>
<p>act of incorporation 4 Counties.</p>
<p>Smith and Walker counties to have special war tax collected........... <ref>7</ref></p>
<p>County Courts.</p>
<p>of Bastrop and other counties, to regulate the pay of Sheriff in certain cases............................................ <ref>9</ref></p>
</div4>
<div4 type="section">
<head type="main">D</head>
<p>Dallas Male and Female College. act of incorporation............................................. <ref>7</ref></p>
<p>Davis County. County Court to regulate the pay of Sheriff in certain cases................ <ref>9</ref></p>
<p>Denton County. County Court to regulate the pay of Sheriff in certain cases......... <ref>9</ref></p>
<p>De Witt County. County Court to regulate the pay of Sheriff in certain cases......... <ref>9</ref></p>
</div4>
<div4 type="section">
<head type="main">E</head>
<p>Ellis County. County Court to regulate the pay of Sheriff in certain cases...... <ref>9</ref></p>
<p>Eubanks &#38; Co., Card Factory. joint resolution, requesting the detail of persons to work therein.... <ref>16</ref></p>
</div4>
<pb n="652" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="20" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div4 type="section">
<head type="main">F</head>
<p>Falls County. County Court to regulate the pay of Sheriff in certain cases......... <ref>9</ref></p>
<p>Fayette County. County Court to regulate the pay of Sheriff in certain cases.......... <ref>9</ref></p>
<p>Freestone County. County Court to regulate the pay of Sheriff in certain cases.............. <ref>9</ref></p>
<p>Ferries. authorized to be placed on the Leon and Lampasas rivers without license............................................. <ref>7</ref></p>
</div4>
<div4 type="section">
<head type="main">G</head>
<p>Galveston &#38; Houston Junction R. R. Co. reincorporated and former law amended......................... <ref>3</ref></p>
<p>Goliad Aid Association. act of incorporation............................................. <ref>14</ref></p>
<p>Gonzales County. County Court to regulate the pay of Sheriff in certain cases................... <ref>9</ref></p>
<p>Grayson County. County Court to regulate the pay of Sheriff in certain cases.................. <ref>9</ref></p>
<p>Guadulupe County. County Court to regulate the pay of Sheriff in certain cases.................. <ref>9</ref></p>
</div4>
<div4 type="section">
<head type="main">H</head>
<p>Henderson County. County Court to regulate the pay of Sheriff in certain cases............. <ref>9</ref></p>
<p>Hidalgo County. County Court to retaliate the pay of Sheriff in certain cases............ <ref>9</ref></p>
<p>Hill County. County Court to regulate the pay of Sheriff in certain cases...........</p>
<p>Houston Mutual Aid Association. act of incorporation......................................... <ref>10</ref></p>
</div4>
<div4 type="section">
<head type="main">I</head>
<p>Incorporations.</p>
<p>Comal Manufacturing Company.................. <ref>4</ref></p>
<p>Columbus Mutual Aid Association.................. <ref>13</ref></p>
<p>Caldwell County, Aid Association.................. <ref>13</ref></p>
<p>Dallas Male and Female College.................. <ref>7</ref></p>
<p>Galveston &#38; Houston Junction R. R. Co................... <ref>37</ref></p>
<p>Goliad Aid Association.................. <ref>14</ref></p>
<p>Houston Mutual Aid Association.................. <ref>10</ref></p>
<p>Jackson Manufacturing Company.................. <ref>6</ref></p>
<p>San Antonio Mutual Aid Association.................. <ref>13</ref></p>
<p>Texas Iron Company.................. <ref>11</ref></p>
<p>Texas Lead &#38; Copper Mine Company.................. <ref>12</ref></p>
<p>Texas Paper Manufacturing Company.................. <ref>9</ref></p>
<p>Washington co., Aid Association.................. <ref>14</ref></p>
</div4>
<div4 type="section">
<head type="main">J</head>
<p>Jackson Manufacturing Company. act of incorporation......................................... <ref>6</ref></p>
</div4>
<div4 type="section">
<head type="main">K</head>
<p>Kaufman County. County Court to regulate the pay of Sheriff in certain cases............ <ref>9</ref></p>
</div4>
<div4 type="section">
<head type="main">L</head>
<p>Lampasas River. ferries authorized to be placed thereon without license........... <ref>7</ref></p>
<p>Lamar County. County Court to regulate the pay of Sheriff in certain cases............ <ref>9</ref></p>
<pb n="653" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="21" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<p>LaVaca. County Court to regulate the pay of Sheriff in certain cases............... <ref>9</ref></p>
<p>Leon River. ferry authorized, to be placed thereon without license.................. <ref>7</ref></p>
<p>Lead &#38; Copper Mining Company. act of incorporation...................................... <ref>12</ref></p>
</div4>
<div4 type="section">
<head type="main">M</head>
<p>Magruder, Gen. J. B. and others. joint resolution of thanks to............................... <ref>17</ref></p>
<p>Military Board. joint resolution annulling the contract made by them with Sherrard</p>
<p>Taylor &#38; Co............................................ <ref>17</ref></p>
<p>Monroe Daniel.</p>
<p>an act for the relief of persons holding land under him.................. <ref>1</ref></p>
</div4>
<div4 type="section">
<head type="main">P</head>
<p>Panola County. County Court to regulate the pay of Sheriff in certain cases........... <ref>9</ref></p>
<p>Paper Manufacturing Company. act of incorporation............................................... <ref>9</ref></p>
</div4>
<div4 type="section">
<head type="main">R</head>
<p>Red River County. County Court to regulate the pay of Sheriff in certain cases............. <ref>9</ref></p>
<p>Rusk County. County Court to regulate the pay of Sheriff in certain cases............... <ref>9</ref></p>
</div4>
<div4 type="section">
<head type="main">S</head>
<p>San Antonio Mutual Aid Association. act of incorporation............................................ <ref>13</ref></p>
<p>San Patricio. suspending the corporate authority of the town of................... <ref>12</ref></p>
<p>Sheriff.</p>
<p>act regulating the pay of, in certain cases................ <ref>9</ref></p>
<p>Sherrard Taylor &#38; Co. joint resolution annulling a contract made by them with the State</p>
<p>Military Board............................ <ref>17</ref></p>
<p>Smith County.</p>
<p>an act requiring the collection of the special war tax therein.................. <ref>7</ref></p>
<p>Starr County.</p>
<p>County Court to regulate the pay of Sheriff in certain cases.............. <ref>9</ref></p>
</div4>
<div4 type="section">
<head type="main">T</head>
<p>Tarrant County. County Court to regulate the pay of Sheriff in certain cases............... <ref>9</ref></p>
<p>Terry, Col. B. F. an act releasing certain rights to his heirs............................ <ref>3</ref></p>
<p>Texas Iron Company. act of incorporation...................................... <ref>11</ref></p>
<p>Texas Lead and Copper Mine Company. act of incorporation............................... <ref>12</ref></p>
<p>Texas Paper Manufacturing Company. act of incorporation............................. <ref>9</ref></p>
<p>Titus County. County Court to regulate the pay of Sheriff in certain cases............ <ref>9</ref></p>
<p>Trinity County. County Court to regulate the pay of Sheriff in certain cases........... <ref>9</ref></p>
</div4>
<pb n="654" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="22" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div4 type="section">
<head type="main">U</head>
<p>Upshur County. County Court to regulate the pay of Sheriff in certain cases.......... <ref>9</ref></p>
</div4>
<div4 type="section">
<head type="main">V</head>
<p>Van Zandt County. County Court to regulate the pay of Sheriff in certain cases........... <ref>9</ref></p>
</div4>
<div4 type="section">
<head type="main">W</head>
<p>Walker County. County Court to collect the special war tax immediately.................. <ref>7</ref></p>
<p>Washington County Mutual Aid Association. act of incorporation........................................... <ref>14</ref></p>
<p>Wilson County. County Court to regulate the pay of Sheriff in certain cases.................. <ref>9</ref></p>
<p>Wood County. County Court to regulate the pay of Sheriff in certain cases.................. <ref>9</ref></p>
</div4>
</div3>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">THE STATE OF TEXAS, DEPARTMENT OF STATE.</head>
<p>I, R. J. Townes, Secretary of State of Texas, do certify that I have compared the foregoing Laws and Joint Resolutions of the Extra Session of the Ninth Legislature, with the originals now on file in the Department of State, and that they are true copies of such originals.</p>
<p>I further certify that the Extra Session of the Ninth Legislature of the State of Texas convened in accordance with the Proclamation of the Governor, at Austin on Monday the second day of February one thousand eight hundred and sixty<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />three, and adjourned on Saturday the seventh day of March, the same year.</p>
<p>Given under my hand and the seal of the Department of State, at <floatingText rend="left"><body><p>[SEAL.]</p></body></floatingText>the city of Austin this the first day of September one thousand eight hundred and sixty-three.</p>
<closer>
<signed>E. J. TOWNES.. Secretary of State.</signed>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="addendum">
<p>Note.&#8212;The certificate appended to the volume containing the General Laws of the Extra Session of the Ninth Legislature of the State of Texas, is hereby amended so as to read that the said Extra Session adjourned on Saturday the 7th of March 1863, instead of Friday the 6th of March as stated in said certificate.</p>
</div2>
</div1>
</body>
</text>