<text xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 UNTtite%20(1.3).xsd" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="TEI">
<body>
<pb n="835" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="1" />
<div1 type="article">
<head type="main">SPECIAL LAWS <lb/>OF <lb/>THE TENTH LEGISLATURE (SECOND EXTRA SESSION,) <lb/>OF <lb/>THE STATE OF TEXAS</head>
<byline>BY AUTHORITY</byline>
<byline>AUSTIN 1865</byline>
<pb n="836" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="2" />
<pb n="837" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="3" />
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">SPECIAL LAWS.</head>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER I.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to Incorporate the Osage Academy.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That S. D. McLeary, F. M. Burford, M. Nave, C. C. Jones, W. Good and S. R. Dehart, trustees of the Osage Academy, situated in the county of Colorado, be, and they are hereby created a body corporate, under the name and style of the Osage Academy, and by that name may sue and be sued, plead and be impleaded, enact such by laws, rules and regulations as may be necessary for their government, purchase, hold and enjoy property of all kinds not to exceed in value two hundred thousand dollars, or may receive the same by donation for the benefit of said Academy, to convert said property into money and dispose of the same and shall have a common seal and shall have the power to confer any and all literary honors upon all students considered worthy to receive the same.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That the rights and privileges herein granted shall extend to the trustees herein named and their successors, and they may elect from their own number, under such regulations as they may adopt and for such terms as they may see proper, a President, Secretary and Treasurer, or any other officer or agent necessary in the Board. They shall also have the power to construct such buildings as may be necessary for said Academy and to do all things neces<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sary to the proper conduct and management of said Academy not contrary to the law or inconsistent with this charter.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. This act shall take effect from its passage and remain in force for twenty-five years.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>October 29th, 1864</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER II.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act for the relief of Stephen W. Pipkin.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That Stephen W. Pipkin, of the county of Chambers, be and he is hereby authorized to sue for and collect the interest due him upon the notes and mortgages held by him against G. M. Hardin.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. All laws and parts of laws forbidding the same are hereby suspended, so far as relates to this act, and no farther.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>Nov. 3, 1864</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<pb n="838" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="4" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER III.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to change the name of Charles C. TenEyck to that of Charles Thomas Pelham.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Whereas, Charles Thomas Pelham, of Travis county, Texas, a member of Terry&#8217;s regiment, eighth Texas cavalry, a hero in more than one hundred battles, and while charging the Yankees near Dalton, Ga., he nobly fell at the head of the regiment, on the 9th day of May, 1864, a sacrifice to the cause of his country; and, Whereas, The said Charles Thomas Pelham leaves no issue, and in con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sideration of his many acts of cool and daring courage, and heroic conduct on the battle field to perpetuate his name, therefore</p>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the name of Charles C. TenEyck be, and the same is hereby changed to that of Charles Thomas Pelham.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>November 3d, 1864</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER IV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act for the relief of the heirs at law of Thomas Moore, deceased.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Commissioner of the General Land Office of the State of Texas be, and he is hereby authorized and required to issue a patent to the heirs at law of Thomas Moore, deceased, for six hundred and forty acres of land, as surveyed and re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />turned in his office from the Robinson Land District.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this act be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>November 7th, 1864</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER V.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to incorporate the Bastrop Cotton and Wool Manufacturing Company.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That A. J. Ward, P. R. Smith, S. S. Hunger, Sherman Reynolds, and Kennor Rector, and their associates and successors be, and they are hereby created a body corporate and politic, under the name and style of &#8220;The Bastrop Manufac<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />turing Company,&#8221; situated in the town of Bastrop, for the purpose of manu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />facturing cotton and woolen fabrics, and by that name may sue and be sued, plead and be impleaded, and do and perform all other acts incident to corpo<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />rations, for the furtherance of the above objects.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. The capital stock of said company shall not exceed the sum of two hundred thousand dollars, to be divided into shares of one hundred dollars each, said shares to be transferable by giving notice in writing to the Secretary of the company.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That the buildings, lots, engine, spinning, and all the factory machinery of Ward, Munger &#38; Co., in the town of Bastrop, now being put into operation by them, is hereby declared to be the property of the said Bastrop Manufacturing Company. Upon the said Ward, Munger &#38; Co. exe<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cuting to said Manufacturing Company the proper releases, and the proper officers of said Manufacturing Company, will issue to each of the above firm certificates of stock, for the amount they may respectively be entitled to.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. That as soon as practicable, after the passage of this act, the stock holders shall, on a day appointed for that purpose, and there being not less than two-thirds of the stock represented, elect a board of three directors, any two of whom shall constitute a quorum to do business, provided that no <pb n="839" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="5" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw> one shall be eligible to a Directorship in said company who does not own at least ten shares in the same. Said board shall be elected by ballot and each share represented in person, or by proxy, shall be entitled to one vote. They shall, from their number, elect one to be President of the company who, with a Secretary, to be elected by said board, shall constitute the permanent officers of the company.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. The board of directors elected under this charter shall hold their offices until the first Monday in January next after their election, and on that day in each year thereafter a new election shall be had by the stock holders of the company, but in ease of a failure to elect on that day, then the old board shall continue in office until a majority of the stockholders shall meet and elect their successors.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. The board of directors shall have the right to enact such by-laws and regulations as may be necessary for the transaction of their business.</p>
<p>Sec. 7. Said company may in their corporate name purchase and own slaves, wagons and teams, and such other personal property as may be useful for car<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />rying on said business.</p>
<p>Sec. 8. That all contracts, deeds, releases, certificates of stock, &#38;c., shall be signed by the President and countersigned by the Secretary of said company, and attested by the seal of the corporation.</p>
<p>Sec. 9. That this act take effect and be in force from its passage, and con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tinue in force twenty-five years.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>November 7th, 1864</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER VI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to provide for the exchange of so much of the old issue of the Treasury notes of the Confederate States, as is now or may be hereafter in the Treasury for the new issue as is authorized by the acts of Congress that now exist or may bereafter be passed.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Comptroller is authorized and required to exchange so much of the old issue of Treasury notes of the Confederate States now in, or which may bereafter come in the Treasury of the State for the new issue of the Treasury notes of the Con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />federate States, as is authorized by the acts of Congress that now exist or may bereafter be passed, in such ease made and provided. That the Governor of the State and the Comptroller are hereby authorized and empowered to do and perform all things necessary to carry into effect the provisions of this act.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. So much of any law as may be inconsistent with the provisions of this act is hereby repealed.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. This act take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>Nov. 12th, 1864</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER VII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to provide for the destruction of the Treasury Warrants, Coupons of the State Bonds, and Bonds of the State, that have been paid, or may bereafter be paid into the Treasury, and cancelled by the Treasurer and turned over to the Comptroller as vouchers.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Secretary of State and the Attorney General of the State shall act as Commissioners for the purpose of counting the Treasury warrants, coupons of the State bonds and bonds of the State that are now or may bereafter be paid into the <pb n="840" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="6" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw> treasury or be in the hands of the Comptroller for cancellation, and shall compare the same with the books of the Comptroller and Treasurer. If, upon examina<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion, they find such treasury warrants, coupons and bonds to correspond with the books of the Comptroller and Treasurer, said Commissioners are required to destroy the same by burning, and shall give the Comptroller a certificate for the amount of each class so destroyed, which certificate or certificates shall be a voucher or vouchers in the hands of the Comptroller for the warrants, coupons and bonds so destroyed. The Commissioners shall, from time to time, report to the Governor their action and the amounts of the liabilities of the State thus destroyed.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. The Comptroller shall keep a complete register of each warrant, coupon and bond cancelled and destroyed under the provisions of this act. This act to be in force from its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>Nov. 12th, 1864</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER VIII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to allow Assessors and Collectors and Chief Justices to purchase Station<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ery at the Comptroller&#8217;s Ofiice.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Assessors and Collectors of Taxes and Chief Justices be authorized and allowed to purchase stationery in such amounts as may be necessary to accomplish the ends of their offices, at the Comptroller&#8217;s department, when there shall be any on hand, at what it will cost the State to procure and transport the same to the capitol.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this act take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>Nov. 12th, 1864</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER IX.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act for the relief of the heirs of John B. H. Jones, deceased.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Administrator of the estate of John B. H. Jones, deceased, of Polk comity, Texas, be and is hereby authorized to exchange a negro boy, belonging to said estate, to-wit: Dick, aged about 15 years, for a negro girl or woman of equal value: Provided, That an account of said exchange shall be returned to the Probate Court in writing, and under oath, subject to the approval of the Chief Justice.</p>
<p>Sec. 2 The above named act shall take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>Nov. 12th, 1864</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER X.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to authorize the Comptroller to Audit and Settle the claims of L. P. Strong, for subsisting the Tonkaway Indians from the 16th day of December, 1863, to the 1st day of July, 1864.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Comptroller be, and be is hereby authorized and required to, audit and settle the claims of L. P. Strong, for subsisting the Tonkaway Indians from the 16th day of Dec. 1863, to the 1st day of July, 1864, provided the said claims shall be approved by the Governor.</p>
<pb n="841" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="7" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<p>Sec. 2. That so much as may be necessary of the unexpended, balance of the appropriation made by an Act entitled &#8220;An Act for the relief of the Tonkaway Indians, &#8220;approved December 16th, 1863, be and the same is hereby appropria<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ted for the payment of said claims; and that this Act take effect from its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>Nov. 14, 1864</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act supplemental to and amendatory of an Act entitled an Act to incorpo<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />rate the Guadalupe Manufacturing Company, approved May 28th, 1864.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the 2d section of the above recited act shall hereafter read as follows, to-wit: Sec. 2. That the said company are hereby created with the right to own, erect, maintain and carry on a factory for the purpose of manufacturing cotton and woolen rolls, and cloth of any and all kinds, and said company shall also have the privilege of running, in connection with said factory, a grist and flouring mill and saw mill, and any other machinery for the manufactory of any other articles, when it does not conflict with the successful operations of the manufacturing department.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this act take effect, and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>Nov. 14th, 1864</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to incorporate the Houston Paper Mill Manufacturing Company.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That Paul Bremond, Willard Richardson, E. H. Cushing, Abram Groesbeck and J. T. Brady and their associates and successors, are hereby created a body corporate and politic, by the name and style of the Houston Paper Mill Manufacturing Company, with power to sue and be sued, plead and be impleaded, to acquire, hold and convey personal property, and such real estate as may be necessary to carry out the purposes of the corporation, to have succession and a common seal, and to do such other things as are necessary to carry out the purposes of this act.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That said company be, and is hereby established with the right to erect, own and operate machinery and buildings, and locate the same in such portions of the State as said company may deem most advisable for the manu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />facture of paper.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That the capital stock of said company shall be divided into shares of one hundred dollars each, and the holders of said shares shall constitute, said company, and said capital stock shall not exceed one hundred thousand dollars.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. That the affairs of said company shall be conducted by a board of directors, not less than three nor more than five, composed of the stockholders. A majority of said board of directors shall constitute a quorum to do business, and shall continue in office until there be an election, the time for which may be fixed by said board.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. That the parties named in the first section of this act are hereby invested with the right to organize said company, and may enact <pb n="842" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="8" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw> such by-laws for their government as they may, from time to time, deem neces<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sary and proper, and shall have all such rights and privileges as are by law incident to, or necessary for corporations of this character.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. That this act take effect from and after its passage and continue in force for a period of twenty years.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>Nov. 14th, 1864</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XIII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act amendatory of an Act to revive and continue in force an Act entitled an Act to incorporate the Galveston and Houston Junction Railroad company, approved April the 8th, 1861, and to amend said Act, approved Feb. 25th, 1863.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That section 3d of said act, approved Feb. 25th, 1863, be, and is hereby so amended as to read as follows, to-wit: Said company shall complete said road and make said connection between the Galveston, Houston and Henderson and Texas Cen<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tral Railroads of the same gage of those roads within twelve months from the passage of this act.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That all laws and parts of laws conflicting with the provisions of this act, be, and the same is hereby repealed.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>Nov. 14th, 1861</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XIV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to amend the 5th section of an Act to incorporate New Braunfels Acad<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />emy, passed Feb. 5th, 1858.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the 5th section of an act to incorporate New Braunfels Academy, passed Feb. 5th, 1858, be so amended as to hereafter read as follows: Sec. 5th. That the cor<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />porate authorities of the city of New Braunfels shall have authority in their discretion to levy and collect a special tax upon all persons and property within the corporate limits of said city, and subject to taxation by the State for the support of the institution hereby incorporated, and the public schools of the city of New Braunfels, which tax shall not in any year exceed the rate of State tax for such year, and shall be levied and collected in like manner as other corporate taxes of said city are, and when collected, shall be paid over to the Treasurer of the county, and by him paid over, pro rata, to the different public schools of the city of New Braunfels, in proportion to the number of pupils taught therein.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. This act to take effect from its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>Nov. 14th, 1864</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to incorporate the Houston City Mills Manufacturing Company.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That T. W. House. C. S. Longcope, A. Sessums, P. Bremond, Wm. Brady, W. <pb n="843" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="9" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw> J. Hutchins, William R. Baker, A. J. Burke and William Anders and their associates and successors be and the same are hereby declared and constituted a body politic under the name and style of the Houston City Mills Manufactur<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing Company with capacity to own property, both real and personal, to make contracts, to have succession and a common seal, and to make by-laws for its government, and in its corporate name to sue and be sued, to grant and receive and generally to do and perform such acts and things necessary and proper for, and incident to, the fulfillment of its objects, or maintainance of its rights under this act, and consistent with the constitution and laws of the State of Texas.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That the said company be, and is hereby established with the right to own and erect buildings and machinery and operate the same in or near the city of Houston, for the manufacturing of cotton and woolen goods, and such other articles as said company may at any time choose to manufacture.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That the capital stock of said company shall be divided into shares of five hundred dollars each, and the holders of the shares shall constitute said company, and said capital stock shall not exceed five hundred thousand dollars.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. That the affairs and business of said company shall be conducted by a Board of Directors of not less than three nor more than five, who shall be elected by the stock holders, at their organization under this act, and annually thereafter, provided, that in ease of failure to elect at the stated time or times, that the Board of Directors incumbent shall continue in office until there be an election, the time for which may be fixed by said Board, of which a reasonable notice may be given.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. No person shall be eligible to the office of Director, unless he is the owner of five shares. The said Board shall elect a president from their own number, fill vacancies and appoint such officers as they may deem necessary, and require bond and security for the faithful performance of their duty, and to do generally, or cause to be done, all other acts and things which they shall deem proper in conducting the affairs of said company; a majority of the Board of Di<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />rectors shall constitute a quorum to do business.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. That the parties named in this act are hereby appointed commissioners and empowered to organize said company, and that this charter shall expire at the end of twenty-five years.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>Nov. 14th, 1864</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XVI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act supplementary to an Act entitled an Act to amend the 3d section of an Act to incorporate the Dallas Bridge Company, approved Dec. 11th, 1861.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Dallas Bridge Company, incorporated by act of the 9th of February, 1860, and the 3d section of which act was amended by act of Dec. 11th, 1861, shall have three years after the termination of the existing war between the United States and the Confederate States of America, in which to complete said bridge and causeway in said act mentioned.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this act take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Passed, <date>Nov. 12th, 1864</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<pb n="844" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="10" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XVII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to relieve James H. Benton and Samuel R. Shepherd, of Panola county, Samuel G. Haynes, of Bell County and Leonidas Moody Bragg, of Grimes County, Texas, from the disability of minority.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That James H. Benton and Samuel R. Shepherd, of Panola County, Texas, and Samuel G. Haynes, of Bell County, Texas, and Leonidas Moody Bragg, of Grimes county, Texas, be, and they are each relieved from the disability of minority, and em<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />powered to contract and do and perform all acts, as if they were of full age.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this act take effect and be in force from after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>Nov. 15th, 1864</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XVIII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to incorporate the Southern Minerva Institute.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That J. S. Holman, G. W. White, Joseph Harrell, L. D. Carrington, W. A. Morris, J. H. Lightfoot, and their associates and successors in office, are hereby constituted a Board of Trustees for the Female Institute, established at Austin, in Travis County, Texas, and which is by this act incorporated by the name and style of The Southern Minerva Institute, and by that name may sue and be sued, plead and be impleaded, enact by-laws, rules and regulations, purchase, hold and enjoy property of all kinds, not to exceed in value $200,000, or receive the same by donation, for the benefits of said Institute; may exchange or convert said prop<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />erty into money and dispose of the same; may have a common seal for the trans<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />action of business, and the Board of Trustees shall have the power to confer &#8220;degrees&#8221; and literary honors upon all students considered by the faculty worthy to receive the same.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That the rights and privileges herein granted shall extend to the trustees herein named, their associates and successors, and they may elect from their own number under such regulations as they may adopt, and for such terms as they may see proper, a President, Secretary and Treasurer, or any other officer or agent necessary in the Board. They shall also have the power to construct such buildings as may be necessary, and to do all things necessary to the proper conduct and management of said Institute, not contrary to the law or inconsistent with this charter.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage, and remain in force for twenty-five years.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>Nov. 15th, 1864</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XIX.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to incorporate the Holly Springs Manufacturing Company.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That Martin D. Rogers, Alfred Emmert, Charles D. McKnight, Peter M. Gun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />stream and Howard Keyes and their associates and successors, are hereby created a body corporate and politic, under the name and style of the Holly Springs Manufacturing Company, and by that name may sue and be <pb n="845" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="11" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw> sued, plead and be impleaded in any of the courts of this State. They shall, by their corporate name, be capable of contracting and being contracted with, and of acquiring, by purchase, donation, or otherwise, real and personal estate, and of selling and conveying the same, or any part thereof, as the said cor<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />poration may deem fit, provided, however, the said corporation shall not acquire, or hold, more real estate than is necessary for the purposes of said corporation in constructing and carrying on their corporate business.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Said company may manufacture cotton and woolen fabrics, cotton yarns, wool rolls, and other fabrics that may be useful to the country.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. The capital stock shall be five hundred thousand dollars to be divided into shares of one hundred dollars each.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. When one hundred thousand dollars shall be subscribed, the stock<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />holders may elect four Directors, who shall hold their office for two years, said Directors may proceed to elect one of their number President, who shall hold his office for and during two years.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. That when a suit shall be brought against the company, it shall be sufficient to execute process, on the President, either in person or by leaving a copy at the office of the company, with some white person attached to the com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pany over the age of eighteen years.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. Be it further enacted that this act shall take effect and be in force for and during twenty years from its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>Nov. 15th, 1864</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XX.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to authorize the Governor of the State to dispose of certain property not necessary for public use.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Governor be, and he is hereby authorized to dispose of all property not necessary for the public use belonging to the State which remained on hand after the transfer of the Frontier Regiment.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That said property shall be sold at auction for State Treasury War<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />rants at such time and places as the Governor may deem proper.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That in the event the contract between the State and Confederate au<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />thorities, by which a large amount of said property was conveyed to the Con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />federate government, should be cancelled, and the property returned to the State, such property shall be sold as above provided.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. That this act take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>Nov. 15th, 1864</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>Aa Act to incorporate the Austin Iron Company.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That W. S. Bead, James B. Allen, Wm. Griffiths, Wm. G. Beeves, and George Young, and their Associates and successors, be and the same are hereby created a body corporate, under the name and style of the Austin Iron Company, with capacity to own property, real, personal and mixed, in such quantities as may be necessary, for the legitimate purposes of this corpora<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion, to make contracts, have a common seal, establish by-laws, for its <pb n="846" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="12" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw> government, and in their corporate name to sue and be sued, to grant and re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ceive, and generally to do and perform such things and acts as may be essential and incident to the fulfillment of their objects, or in the maintenance of their rights under this act, and not inconsistent with the constitution of this State.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That said company is hereby created with the right to erect, own and maintain and carry on a manufactory of iron and steel of every description what<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ever, and all other articles of which iron or steel forms a part, at such place or places as said company may select in the counties of Bastrop, Llano, Travis or Burnet, in this State.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. The capital stock of said company shall be divided into shares of one hundred dollars each, and the holders of such shares shall constitute said company, and the capital stock of said company shall not exceed one million of dollars.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. The business of said company shall be conducted by a Board of Di<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />rectors of not less than three nor more than five, chosen by the stock holders out of their number at such time and place as the corporators herein mentioned, or a majority of them may prescribe, and annually thereafter, provided, that in case of failure to elect at the stated time the Board of Directors incumbent shall hold their office until there be an election, the time and place for which may be fixed by said Board, of which there shall be reasonable notice given of not less than twenty days.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. That no person shall be eligible as Director, unless he be a member of said Company. The Board shall elect from their own number a President, fill vacancies and appoint such officers as they may deem necessary, and exact se<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />curity for the faithful performance of their duties, and fix the time for the pay<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment of installments, to declare forfeitures of stock for non-payment, and to do and perform all things which they may deem necessary to a successful prosecution of the business of the company. A majority of said Board of Directors shall con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />stitute a quorum to do business.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. The members of said company shall be entitled to the benefits of any Bonus, Loan, or other benefits, that may be granted to companies or individuals, who engage in the manufacture of iron by any law heretofore or hereafter passed.</p>
<p>Sec. 7. That the parties named in the 1st Sec. of this act are hereby invested with the right to organize said company, and that this charter shall expire at the end of twenty-five years, and that this act shall take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>Nov. 15th, 1864</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to relieve Zepheniah McMillon of the disability of minority.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That Zepheniah McMillon, a minor, resident of the county of Anderson, State of Texas, be, and he is hereby relieved of the disability of minority, and declared of full and lawful age for all purposes of managing and controlling his own property, and subject to all the legal liabilities appertaining to the same.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>Nov. 15th, 1864</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<pb n="847" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="13" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXIII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act for the relief of Luke A. Falvell.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1, Be it enacted, by the Legislature i the State of Texas, That the Comptroller be, and he is hereby directed to audit th claim of Luke A. Falvell for the sum of five thousand and twenty-two dollars and twenty-one cents ($5,022,21) for services as sailing-master in the navy of the late Republic of Texas.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That the sum of five thousand and twenty-two dollars and twenty-one cents be, and the same is hereby appropriated for the payment of the same out of any money in the treasury not otherwise appropriated, said payment to be made in the new issue of Confederate Treasury Notes.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. This act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Passed, <date>Nov. 15th, 1864</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXIV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to authorize the County Court of Galveston County to borrow money to support the Indigent Persons of said County.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the County Court of Galveston County be, and the same is hereby authorized and em<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />powered, to borrow money for the purpose of supporting the indigent persons of said county, and to this end they may order the execution of the bonds of said county by the proper officers thereof, and sell the same to the amount of twenty thousand dollars; said bonds shall express the purpose for which they shall be executed, in order that the owners thereof may be entitled to the benefits of the provisions of this act, and it shall be the duty of the County Court of said county within the four years following the declaration of a treaty of peace between the Confederate States of America and the United States of America, to levy and col<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lect a special tax each year, sufficient to pay the interest falling due on the bonds, and one-fourth of the principal thereof, which, when collected, shall be paid by the Treasurer of said county to the owners of said bonds.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this act shall be of force from its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>November 15th, 1864</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
</div2>
<pb n="848" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="14" />
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">JOINT RESOLUTIONS.</head>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER I. JOINT RESOLUTION.</head>
<p>Whereas, Messrs. G. W. Johnson and Samuel Hayford have recently in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vented a machine for carding Cotton Rolls, and said machine has been tested and found to be a complete success, and, Whereas, It is confidently believed that said machine will prove to be of great utility to the country in supply<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing the place of, and in a great measure superceding the necessity for cotton cards, and thereby save an immense outlay of money to the State and the peo<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ple. And, Whereas, It is believed that said machine will prove a successful means of furnishing clothing for the soldiers in the army. Therefore,</p>
<p>Be it resolved by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Gen&#8217;l Com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />manding the Trans-Mississippi Department be, and he is hereby requested to, grant permanent details to said G. W. Johnson and Samuel Hayford of Austin County, Texas, for the purpose of manufacturing and putting into operation their said invention for carding Cotton Rolls, and that he be further requested to grant details to such other skilful mechanics in the different Counties of this State, as the respective County Courts may certify to be necessary for intro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ducing, constructing and putting into operation said machine. Resolved further, That the Governor of the State of Texas, transmit a copy of these Resolutions to the General Commanding the Trans-Mississippi Department.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>Nov. 3, 1864</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER II.</head>
<opener>
<salute>Joint Resolution on the Death of Gen. John Gregg.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Whereas, The Legislature of the State of Texas have heard with profound re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />gret the death of Gen. John Gregg, who fell leading his brigade against the country&#8217;s foe, therefore be it</p>
<p>Resolved, That in the death of Gen. Gregg the State mourns the loss of an<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />other of her bravest sons and best patriots, and will ever cherish with pride the memory of his noble deeds.</p>
<pb n="849" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="15" /><fw type="header" place="top">Joint Resolution.</fw>
<p>Resolved, further, That we deeply sympathize with the family of General John Gregg in their loss and bereavement, and hereby tender to them our hearty sym<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pathy, and with theirs mingle our sorrow and grief.</p>
<p>Resolved, That the Governor forward a copy of the foregoing to Mrs. General Gregg.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>November 8th, 1864</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER III.</head>
<opener>
<salute>Joint Resolution Concerning the Books of the Military Board.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Be it resolved by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Special Joint Committee on the Military Board be, and they are hereby authorized to employ a suitable person to balance the books of the Military Board containing the entries of the Board to April, 1864.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>Nov. 12th, 1864</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER IV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>Joint Resolutions Concerning the Distribution of Certain Medicines.</salute>
</opener>
<p>1. Be it Resolved by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the following medicines now in possession of the Military Board, to-wit: Four hundred ounces of quinine, two hundred and seventy-five pounds of opium, seventy-five ounces of morphine and forty-one and two-thirds gross of Wright&#8217;s pills, be distributed by the said Board to the county courts of the several counties of the State upon the basis, as nearly as may be, of the indigent lists, now required to be furnished by the county courts to the Comptroller of the State.</p>
<p>2. That, upon application of any Chief Justice of any county in this State, the said Military Board is hereby instructed to deliver to him, or to his authorized agent, the quota of medicines to which his county may be entitled, on his giving a proper receipt for the same.</p>
<p>3. That it shall be the duty of the said county courts to apply for the quota of medicines to which their respective counties may be entitled under the provisions of these resolutions, at the expense of said counties; and when received, they shall cause the same to be distributed gratuitously to such persons in their respective counties, as they may believe to have the greatest need for the same, and in the manner that they may judge best calculated to promote the object of these Reso<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lutions, giving the preference, as far as may be, to the indigent families of absent soldiers.</p>
<p>4. That in case any member of this Legislature may be willing to take charge of the quota of medicines to which the county or counties represented by him may be entitled under these resolutions, he shall be permitted to do so, upon giving his receipt for the same to the Military Board, which medicines, so received, shall be delivered free of charge and with as little delay as possible to the county court of the proper county.</p>
<p>5. In case the county court of any county shall fail or neglect to apply for the quota of medicines to which such county may be entitled, under the provisions of these resolutions, for the space of three months after the adjournment of the present session of the Legislature, the Military Board is hereby directed to cause the medicines to which such county or counties may be entitled, to be sold at public auction to the highest bidder for cash, <pb n="850" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="16" /><fw type="header" place="top">Joint Resolution.</fw> after giving ten days notice of the time and place of such sale in a public news<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />paper, printed in the city of Austin, and the proceeds of such sale shall be de<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />posited by the said Military Board, in the State Treasury, to the credit of the county or counties entitled to the same.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>Nov. 12th, 1864</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER V.</head>
<opener>
<salute>Joint Resolution in Relation to Cotton and Wool Cards.</salute>
</opener>
<p>1. Be it resolved by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the wool cards now in the hands of the Military Board be, and the same are hereby donated to the several counties of this State, and distributed among them, on the basis of the indigent lists required by existing law to be made by the County Courts to the Comptroller.</p>
<p>2. That the County Courts of the several counties receiving cards under this resolution shall transport the same from the City of Austin to their several county seats, at their own expense, and distribute them first, without charge, to indigent dependents of soldiers who will use them, and, secondly, if any remain, to be sold by the courts in such manner as they deem best, and the proceeds thereof applied to the support of indigent families and dependents of Texas soldiers.</p>
<p>3. The Governor, or the Military Board, shall cause notice to be given to the several Chief Justices of the number of cards due their counties under this reso<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lution, and if any county does not call for and receive the cards due it within ninety days from date of receiving notice as aforesaid, the Governor, or the Military Board shall cause the same to be sold in the City of Austin, in such way, and for such currency as such County Court may direct, and the proceeds of such sale paid to said County Court, on its order.</p>
<p>4. That this Joint Resolution take effect from its passage, and the members of the Legislature shall be authorized to receive and receipt for the cards due the counties they represent.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>November 15th, 1864</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER VI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>Joint Resolution.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Be it resolved by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That our Senators in Congress be instructed and our Representatives requested to use their exertions to procure the passage of a law, authorising soldiers and officers in our army or their families, to purchase supplies of provisions and the raw material for clothing, when<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ever there may be a surplus on hand, from Commissaries, Quartermasters and Collectors of Tax in Kind, at Schedule prices, in such quantities as may be abso<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lutely necessary for their support.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>Nov. 15th, 1864</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
</div2>
<pb n="851" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="17" />
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">INDEX TO SPECIAL LAWS.</head>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">A</head>
<p>Page.</p>
<p>Assessors and Collectors. To purchase Stationery from the Comptroller&#8217;s Office.............. <ref>6</ref></p>
<p>Austin Iron Company. Act of Incorporation .......................................... <ref>11</ref></p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">B</head>
<p>Bastrop Cotton and Wool Manufacturing Company. Act of Incorporation ............................... <ref>4</ref></p>
<p>Benton, James H. Relieved from disability of minority ................... <ref>10</ref></p>
<p>Bragg, Leonidas Moody. Believed from disability of minority ............. <ref>10</ref></p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">C</head>
<p>Confederate Treasury Notes. To Provide for Exchange of, Old Issue of, in the Treasury, for the New, <ref>5</ref></p>
<p>Coupons of State Bonds. To Provide for destruction of ........................................... <ref>5</ref></p>
<p>Chief Justices of Counties. To purchase Stationery from the Comptroller&#8217;s Office ........... <ref>6</ref></p>
<p>Cotton and Wool Cards. Joint Resolution concerning .......................... <ref>16</ref></p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">D</head>
<p>Dallas Bridge Company. Act of Incorporation, amended ...................... <ref>9</ref></p>
</div3>
<pb n="852" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="18" /><fw type="header" place="top">Index.</fw>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">F</head>
<p>Falvell, Luke A. For the Relief of .......................................... <ref>13</ref></p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">G</head>
<p>Galveston County. Authorized to borrow money to support indigent persons of ................ <ref>13</ref></p>
<p>Galveston and Houston Junction Railroad Company. Act of Incorporation of, revived, and to amend said Act ........... <ref>8</ref></p>
<p>Governor. To dispose of certain property not necessary for public use ............. <ref>II</ref></p>
<p>Gregg, Gen. John. Joint Resolution on the death of ..................... <ref>14</ref></p>
<p>Guadalupe Manufacturing Company. Act of Incorporation amended ................... <ref>7</ref></p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">H</head>
<p>Heirs of&#8212;Thomas Moore, for relief of .......................... <ref>4</ref></p>
<p>John B. H. Jones, for relief of .................. <ref>6</ref></p>
<p>Houston Paper Mill Manufacturing Company, Act of Incorporation of ........................... <ref>7</ref></p>
<p>Houston City Mills Manufacturing Company. Act of Incorporation of ................................. <ref>8</ref></p>
<p>Haynes, Samuel G. Relieved of the disability of minority ............................. <ref>10</ref></p>
<p>Holly Springs Manufacturing Company. Act of Incorporation of .................................. <ref>10</ref></p>
<p>Hayford, Samuel. Joint Resolution requesting detail of ............................. <ref>14</ref></p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">I</head>
<p>Incorporations. Austin Iron Company ............................... <ref>11</ref></p>
<p>Bastrop Cotton and Wool Manufacturing Company .......... <ref>4</ref></p>
<p>Dallas Bridge Company, charter amended .................... <ref>9</ref></p>
<p>Guadalupe Manufacturing Company, charter amended .............. <ref>7</ref></p>
<p>Holly Springs Manufacturing Company .................. <ref>10</ref></p>
<p>Houston Paper Mill Manufacturing Company ................ <ref>7</ref></p>
<p>Houston City Mills Manufacturing Company ................ <ref>8</ref></p>
<p>New Braunfels Academy, charter amended ................. <ref>8</ref></p>
<p>Osase Academy ................................................. <ref>3</ref></p>
<p>Southern Minerva Institute ................................. <ref>10</ref></p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">J</head>
<p>Jones, John B. H., Deceased. For the relief of heirs of ............................. <ref>6</ref></p>
<p>Johnson, G. W. Joint Resolution requesting detail of ........... <ref>14</ref></p>
</div3>
<pb n="853" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="19" /><fw type="header" place="top">Index.</fw>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">M</head>
<p>Moore, Thomas, Deceased. For relief of heirs of ......................................... <ref>4</ref></p>
<p>McMillon, Zepheniah. Relieved, from the disability of minority ............................. <ref>12</ref></p>
<p>Military Board. Joint Resolution concerning books of ................................. <ref>15</ref></p>
<p>Medicines. Joint Resolution concerning the distribution of certain belonging to the State ............................................. <ref>15</ref></p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">N</head>
<p>New Braunfels Academy. Charter amended ............................ <ref>8</ref></p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">O</head>
<p>Osage Academy. Act of Incorporation of .......................... <ref>3</ref></p>
<p>Officers, Commissary of Subsistence, C. S. A. Joint Resolution, requesting our Senators and Representatives in Con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />gress to try to have passed a law authorizing families of Texas sol<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />diers, &#38;c., to purchase supplies from Commissaries ............... <ref>16</ref></p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">P</head>
<p>Pipkin, Stephen W. For the relief of ...................................... <ref>3</ref></p>
<p>Pelham, Charles Thomas. To change the name of Charles C. TenEyck to .................... <ref>4</ref></p>
<p>Public Property. Certain unnecessary for public use to be disposed of ............... <ref>11</ref></p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">S</head>
<p>Shepherd, Samuel R. Relieved from the disability of minority ................ <ref>10</ref></p>
<p>Strong, L. P. Comptroller to audit and settle claim of, for supporting Tonkaway Indians ..................................... <ref>6</ref></p>
<p>Southern Minerva Institute. Act of incorporation of ................... <ref>10</ref></p>
<p>Soldiers. Joint Resolution requesting our Senators and Representatives in Con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />gress to try and have passed a law to authorize Commissaries, C. S. A., to sell provisions to. &#38;c. ................................ <ref>16</ref></p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">T</head>
<p>TenEyck, Charles C. Name changed to Charles Thomas Pelham .................. <ref>4</ref></p>
<p>Treasury Warrants. To provide for destruction of ....................... <ref>5</ref></p>
</div3>
</div2>
<pb n="854" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="20" /><fw type="header" place="top">Index.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">DEPARTMENT OF STATE, Austin, Texas, January 19th, 1865.</head>
<p>I, R. J. Townes, Secretary of state for the State of Texas, do hereby certify, that I have compared the foregoing Laws and Joint Resolutions of the Second Called Session of the Tenth Legislature, with the originals now on file in the Department of State, and that they are true copies of such originals.</p>
<p>I further certify, that the said Second Called Session of the Tenth Legislature of the State of Texas, assembled on Monday, the 17th day of October, 1864, and adjourned on the 15th day of November, 1864.</p>
<p>In testimony whereof, have hereunto set my hand, and affixed the seal of the Department of State, the day and date above written.</p>
<closer>
<signed><floatingText rend="left"><body><p>[L. S.]</p></body></floatingText>R. J. TOWNES, Secretary of State.</signed>
</closer>
</div2>
</div1>
</body>
</text>