<text xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 UNTtite%20(1.3).xsd" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="TEI">
<body>
<pb n="523" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="1" />
<div1 type="article">
<head type="main">SPECIAL LAWS <lb/>OF <lb/>THE NINTH LEGISLATURE <lb/>OF <lb/>THE STATE OF TEXAS</head>
<byline>PUBLISHED BY AUTHORITY</byline>
<byline>AUSTIN 1863</byline>
<pb n="524" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="2" />
<pb n="525" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="3" />
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">SPECIAL LAWS.</head>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER I.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act granting leave of absence from the State for three months to Edward H. Vontress, Judge of the Seventeenth Judicial District of Texas.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That leave of absence from this State is hereby granted to Edward H. Vontress, Judge of the Seventeenth Judicial District, for the space of three months, from the twenty-fifth day of November eighteen hundred and sixty-one.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>November 20, 1861</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER II.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to enable J. H. Saunders, the guardian of John Saunders, Cora Saunders, and Claiborne Saunders, to remove the property of his Wards from the State of Texas.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted, by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That J. H. Saunders may remove the property of his wards, John Saunders, Cora Saunders and Olaiborn Saunders, from the county of Harrison in this State to the State of Arkan<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sas, one of the Confederate States of America, whenever said J. A. Saunders shall have produced to the Chief Justice of Harrison county, at some regular term of the County Court, a full and complete transcript of the records of a court of competent jurisdiction in the State of Arkansas, properly authenticated, showing that he has been appointed guardian of the estate of said John Saunders, Cora Saunders and Claiborn Saunders, and given bond and security, as may be required by the laws of the State of Arkansas, and is authorized by such court to receive said property.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this act shall be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>November 27, 1861</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
<pb n="526" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="4" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER III.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to validate the official acts of the persons actually exercising the powers and performing the duties of certain officers in Newton County, between the 23d of April and the 15th of August, 1861.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the of<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ficial acts of the persons actually exercising the powers, and performing the duties of the offices of Chief Justice, County Clerk, County Commissioners, District Clerk, Sheriff, Assessor and Collector, County Treasurer, County Surveyor, Notary Public, Coroner, Justice of the Peace, and Constables, done and performed within, and for Newton County, from and after the 23d of April, 1861, and before the 15th of Au<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />gust, 1861, were, shall be, and are hereby declared to be as legal and valid, to all intents and purposes, as if the persons doing and performing such official acts, had then rightfully held the said offices.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>December 5th, 1861</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER IV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act for the relief of Noah Cox.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Comp<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />troller be authorized to issue to Noah Cox, a duplicate of Treasury Warrant No. 17,332, and draft No. 918, on the Assessor and Collector of Star County, drawn on the twenty-fifth day of March 1861, for the sum of three hundred and sixty dollars, ($360) in favor of said Noah Cox, for his mileage and per diem, as a member of the State Convention: Provided, that said Cox shall file an affidavit of the loss of said Warrant, together with a bond for double the amount of said Warrant with said Comptroller, conditioned that he will indemnify the State, in case the first War<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />rant or draft is paid.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>December 9th, 1861</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER V.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to amend an act, entitled &#8220;An Act to incorporate the Jefferson Insurance Company.&#8221;</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the 7th section of an act, entitled &#8220;An Act to incorporate the Jefferson Insurance Com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pany,&#8221; approved January 7th, 1860, be amended so as to read &#34;Marion County,&#8221; in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />stead of &#8220;Cass County,&#8221; where it occurs in said section.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>December 9th, 1861</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER VI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to amend the second and third sections of an act, entitled &#8220;An Act to Incor<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />porate the Southern Cotton Press and Manufacturing Company,&#8221; approved Febru<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ary 11th, 1860.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the second section of the above entitled act is hereby amended, so that the same shall hereafter read as follows: &#8220;That said Company be, and is hereby estab<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" /><pb n="527" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="5" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw> lished, with the right to receive, store, warehouse, repair, compress, and rebate cot<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ton, and to manufacture cotton rope, and all other articles of which cotton forms a component part, and to carry on any other manufactures which said corporation may desire, and to do all other acts and things necessary, or incident to the proper conducting of, or carrying on the business as aforesaid.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That the third section of said above entitled act, is hereby amended, so that the same shall hereafter read as follows: The capital stock of said Company shall not, at any time, exceed one million of dollars, to be divided into shares of one hundred dollars each, and the holders of such shares shall constitute said Company, and each member shall be entitled to one vote, in person or by written proxy, for each and every share he or she may own upon the books of the Company, and under such rules and regulations as may be, from time to time, prescribed by the by-laws of said Company.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>December 9th, 1861</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER VII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to incorporate the Rio Grande Female Institute.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That Hiram Chamberlain, Joel Chase, W. C. Blair and J. N. Cochran, Trustees of the Rio Grande Female Institute, located in the city of Brownsville, in the county of Cameron, Texas, be and are hereby created a body corporate, under the name and style of &#8220;The Board of Trustees of the Rio Grande Female Institute,&#8221; and in that name shall have succession and be capable in law to sue and be sued, plead and be im<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pleaded; to enact by-laws, rules and regulations, to have, hold and enjoy all the property of whatever kind that may be granted by donation, bequest or otherwise, for the benefit of the Institution, provided said property shall, at no time, amount to more than one hundred thousand dollars in value; and it shall have a common seal for the transaction of its business.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That the &#8220;Rio Grande Female Institute&#8221; shall be under the care and con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />trol of the Presbytery of Western Texas, and the said Board of Trustees shall have power to fill all vacancies that may occur therein, subject to the inspection of the Presbytery above expressed, and that a less number than three of the said Board of Trustees shall not be a quorum to do business, nor shall the number of Trustees, at any time, consist of more than seven members, a majority of whom must be pres<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ent, in person or by proxy, to fill a vacancy.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That the Board of Trustees shall annually present to the Presbytery of Western Texas, a written report of the financial condition of said Institute, the by<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />laws and regulations adopted by the Trustees, the number of teachers and the num<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ber of pupils in attendance during the year.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. That the funds belonging, or in any wise appertaining to said Institute, shall not be diverted from the object for which the same were given, and all dona<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tions and bequests to said Institute shall be good and binding, although the cor<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />porate name thereof may not have been properly stated by the person or parties making such bequest or donation.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. That the Board of Trustees may elect, from their own number, under such rules and regulations as they may adopt, and for such terms and times as they may see proper, a President, Secretary and Treasurer, or any other officer or agent necessary in the Board. They shall also have the power to construct, enlarge, alter or remove all necessary buildings for the <pb n="528" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="6" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw> purposes of said Institute, and to do all things necessary and proper for the conduct and management of the Institute, not contrary to law or inconsistent with this charter.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. That this act shall take effect and be in force from and after its passage, and continue in force thirty years.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>December 9, 1861</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER VIII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to amend the 14th Section of an Act entitled &#8220;An Act to incorporate the Houston, Trinity and Tyler Railroad Company.&#8221;</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the 14th section of an act entitled &#8220;An Act to incorporate the Houston, Trinity and Tyler Railroad Company,&#8221; approved January 7, 1860, be and the same is hereby amended so as to read as follows:</p>
<p>That said Company shall commence the construction of said road within twelve months from and after the declaration of a treaty of peace between the Government of the Confederate States and the Government of the United States, and shall have completely graded, and ready for the iron, at least twenty-five miles of said road within two years from the declaration of said treaty of peace, and twenty-five miles additional shall be completed in good running order for every two years thereafter.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>December 10, 1861</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER IX.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to prevent the sale of vinous, spirituous or other intoxicating liquor within one mile of the center of the town of Alto, in Cherokee county, in the State of Texas.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That if any per<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />son shall sell, or offer for sale, or be in any wise concerned in selling&#8212;whether with or without license&#8212;any spirituous, vinous or other intoxicating liquor, within one mile of the center of the town of Alto, in Cherokee county, in the State of Texas, except for medical or sacramental purposes, he, she or they shall be deemed guilty of a misdemeanor, and upon conviction thereof, before any Justice of the Peace, shall be fined the sum of fifty dollars for each and every such offense.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>December 11, 1861</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER X.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act for the relief of the heirs of Elijah Allcorn.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />missioner of the General Land Office be, and he is hereby authorized and empow<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ered to cancel the original title granted to James G. Wright, by the Commissioner of Austin&#8217;s Colony, as a colonist, situated on Cypress Bayou, for one league of land, and issue a certificate in lieu thereof, for one league of land, to the heirs of Elijah Allcorn, assignee of James G. Wright.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this act be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>December 11, 1861</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
<pb n="529" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="7" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to amend an act, supplemental to an act for the relief of Myrum Mudget, Daniel Kitchings, A. L. Spencer and E. G. Cantwell, approved February 8th,</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the above entitled act shall read as follows: Section 1. That the certificate provided for to be issued to A. L. Spencer and to E. G. Cantwell, in said act, shall be issued to E. G. Spencer and J. A. J. Cantwell, and the Commissioner of the General Land Office be required to issue the same to the parties mentioned in this act.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this act be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>December 11, 1861</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act for the relief of Samuel Everett.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />missioner of the General Land Office be, and is hereby authorized and required to issue, to Samuel Everett, a certificate for twelve hundred and eighty acres of land, which may be located, surveyed and patented, as other genuine land certificates.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>December 11th, 1861</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XIII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to amend an act, entitled &#8220;An Act authorizing C. C. DeWitt, of Gonzales County, to construct a Bridge across the Guadalupe River, near the town of Gon<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />zales, passed Sept, 1st, 1856.&#8221;</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the 2nd section of said act be so amended as to read as follows:</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That said DeWitt shall construct said bridge, in a durable and workman<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />like manner, within five years after the termination of the existing war, or after the declaration of peace between the United States of America and the Confederate States of America, and shall keep the same in good repair, for all passengers, for the term of thirty years from the completion of the same, and to be ready, at all times, to pass all persons, carriages, wagons teams, and stock, that may wish to cross on said bridge.</p>
<p>That the 3rd section of said act be so amended as to read as follows: (The said 3rd section, being the 2nd section, so marked upon said act 3rd, and being the clos<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing section of said act.)</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That no other public bridge or ferry shall be constructed across the Guad<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />alupe river within four miles of the bridge the said DeWitt may construct, until the expiration of this charter, provided, however, that should it become necessary, within said time, to construct a railroad bridge, across said river, that any Railroad Company may construct a bridge within said limits, for the passage of railroad cars.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>December 11th, 1861</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
<pb n="530" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="8" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XIV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to amend the 3rd Section of an act, entitled &#8220;An Act to incorporate the Dallas Bridge Company.&#8221;</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the 3rd section of an act, approved February 9th, 1860, entitled &#8220;An Act to incorporate the Dallas Bridge Company,&#8221; be and the same is hereby amended, so as to extend the time allowed said Company to build said bridge and causeway two years from and after the 9th day of February, 1862; and that this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>December 11th, 1861</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act for the relief of the Hon. A. W. O. Hicks, late Judge of the Fifth Judicial District, of the State of Texas.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted, by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Treas<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />urer of the State be, and he is hereby authorized to pay A. W. O. Hicks, late Judge of the Fifth Judicial district of the State of Texas, the sum of one thousand dollars, the balance of the salary due to said A. W. O. Hicks, for his services as late Judge of the district aforesaid, which sum is now withheld by the Comptroller.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>December 13th, 1861</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XVI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to amend, the 12th Section of an act, to &#8220;Incorporate the town of Mount Vernon, in Titus County, Texas; approved February 4th, 1853.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the 12th section of the above recited act, be so amended as hereafter to read as follows: &#8220;That the Board of Aldermen shall have power to regulate its own proceedings, and to pre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />scribe the duty of all the officers of the corporation; and shall have power to enact all ordinances necessary for the peace and welfare of said town, not contrary to law.</p>
<p>&#8220;That whenever the Board of Aldermen shall so direct, the Mayor of said town of Mount Vernon, shall have power and authority to execute deeds of conveyance to pass the title of town lots, in said town, belonging to said corporation, and may exe<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cute all necessary conveyances to perfect the titles to lots in said town, heretofore sold by said corporation, provided that no such conveyance shall interfere with vested rights.&#8221;</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this act shall take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>December 13th, 1861</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XVII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>Act to incorporate the Austin Hook and Ladder Fire Company, No. 1, of the City of Austin.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That, S. T. Smith, C. F. Millet. R. M. Elgin. Hugh A. Haralson, E. Bremond, and their associates, are hereby constituted a body politic and corporate, as a fire department, for the City of Austin under the name and style of &#8220;The Austin <pb n="531" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="9" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw> Hook and Ladder Fire Company, No. 1, of the City of Austin,&#34; with power to sue and be sued, plead and be impleaded; to have a common seal, with such device as they may adopt; to elect, in whatever manner they may choose, the officers to com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mand them; to establish by-laws for the government and regulation of their af<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fairs, not inconsistent with the Constitution and laws of this State, and the same to alter or amend at pleasure; and to hold real and personal property, and to dispose of the same; provided, however, such real estate and personal property, shall at no time exceed ten thousand dollars in value.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That the members of said Company shall never exceed sixty in number.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That the active members of said Company shall be exempt from jury ser<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vice.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. That neither the Company or its members shall be liable, in damages or otherwise, for property destroyed or injured by them while in the discharge of their duties as firemen.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. That any and all property of the Company shall be exempt from taxation for State and County purposes.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. That said Company shall have power, by their constitution and by-laws, to try all violators of their own ordinances, agreed upon by a majority of the mem<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />bers of said Company; to suspend, expel, or fine not exceeding ten dollars, those vio<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lating the constitution and laws of said Company.</p>
<p>Sec. 7. That this act of incorporation shall be and continue in force for and dur<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing the term of twenty years from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>December 14th, 1861</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XVIII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act for the relief of the heirs of Harvey Murphy.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />missioner of the General Land Office be and he is hereby required to issue to the heirs of Harvey Murphy, deceased, a certificate for 1280 acres of land, to be located upon any of the public domain not reserved from location, and to be surveyed and patented as in other cases, provided no certificate has heretofore issued.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>December 17, 1861</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XIX.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act for the relief of Peter Norton.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />missioner of the General Land Office be and he is hereby required to issue to Peter Norton a donation certificate for six hundred and forty acres of land for having par<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ticipated in the storming of Bexar, in the campaign of 1835, and a bounty warrant for three hundred and twenty acres of land for services in said campaign, also a bounty warrant to the said Peter Norton as the assignee of W. H. Frazier, in lieu of lost bounty scrip No. 977, for three hundred and twenty acres of land, dated Nov. 6, 1836, signed by Geo. W. Poe, which certificates may be located on any vacant land of the State of Texas, provided said Peter Norton has not received certificates for said service heretofore.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this act be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>December 17, 1861</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<pb n="532" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="10" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XX.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to repeal an act to authorize the County Court of the county of Nueces to levy a special tax, approved February 11, 1860.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That an act entitled &#8220;an act to authorize the County Court of Nueces county to levy a special tax,&#8221; approved February 11, 1860, be and the same is hereby repealed.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this act take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>December 17, 1861</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act for the relief of R. A. Henson.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That R. A. Henson be and is hereby restored to all the lights and privileges of an attorney and counsellor at law, and as such entitled to practice law in the different courts in this State.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>December 18, 1861</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to incorporate the Texas Powder Company.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted, by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That James R. Sweet, James Duff, Samuel A. Maverick, Alexander Young and Francis Gerand, and such other persons as may bereafter be associated with them, are hereby created a body corporate by the name of the Texas Powder Company, and by that name may sue and be sued, my plead and be impleaded; may transfer their right by suc<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cession or assignment; may have a common seal; and also by that name and style they and their successors may purchase, hold and convey real and personal estate, not to exceed one hundred thousand dollars.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That the said Company shall have the right to establish and erect, in Bexar county, or elsewhere in the State, buildings, machinery and improvements for the manufacture of gun powder and mining or blasting powder, or such other sim<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ilar compounds as the Company may at any time manufacture for sale, and the said Company shall moreover have the right to establish, anywhere within the limits of the State of Texas, apparatus and fixtures for the purpose of making, extracting or refining nitre, saltpetre and sulphur.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That the capital stock of said company shall be twenty thousand dol<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lars, to be divided into four hundred shares of fifty dollars each, and the said Com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pany shall have Authority to increase said capital to the amount of one hundred thousand dollars.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. That the affairs of the said Company shall be managed by a Board of five Directors, each of whom shall own at least ten shares of the capital stock of said Company; a majority of said directors shall constitute a quorum to do business, and shall have power to appoint a President from their num<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ber, and to fill all vacancies that may occur in the Board of Directors, from death, resignation or otherwise. After the first election of Directors by virtue of this act, all subsequent elections shall be held in the city of San Antonio on the first Tuesday in January of each year; in case of failure to elect <pb n="533" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="11" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw> said Directors at the time and place specified in this act, the corporation shall not be dissolved for that cause, but the President and Directors previously elected shall continue to perform their duties until their successors are elected.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. That the Directors shall be chosen by the stockholders of said Company, and that each stockholder shall have one vote for each share he may own, and may vote by proxy or in person.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. That the President and Directors of said Company shall have full au<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />thority to adopt all such rules, regulations and by-laws as they may consider neces<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sary to effect the object of this act of incorporation, not inconsistent with this act or the laws of this State, and may appoint and remove, at their pleasure, all agents or other employes necessary to transact the business of said corporation.</p>
<p>Sec. 7. That every person subscribing for any of the capital stock of the said Company shall pay such proportion thereof at the time of subscribing as may be directed by the terms of the subscription list, and after the election of the first Board of Directors, the balance shall be paid at such times and upon such terms as the said Directors may designate; provided, that in all cases where further payment may be required, notice thereof shall be given in some newspaper published in the city of San Antonio, or by written communication, if deemed sufficient by the Com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pany, at least thirty days before the time of said payment.</p>
<p>Sec. 8. That if any stockholder shall fail to pay the amount due on his subscrip<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion at the time required by said Directors it shall be lawful at any time after notice and advertisement has been made, in accordance with the preceding section of this Act, for the said Directors to sell the shares of said stockholder at public auction after ten days previous notice of said sale has been given by public adver<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tisement in a newspaper published in San Antonio, Texas, and the purchaser of said shares shall be subject to all the liabilities and entitled to all the benefits of the de<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />faulting stockholder.</p>
<p>Sec. 9. The Commissioner of the General Land Office is hereby authorized to issue to the said Texas Powder Company six land certificates for 640 acres each, which certificates said Company are authorized to locate upon any portion of the public domain which affords the necessary ingredients for gunpowder; provided, that the patents shall not issue under said locations until the powder manufactory of said Company shall be in successful operation; and, provided, said land and certificates shall be forfeited to the State if said manufactory be not in successful operation in six months after the passage of this act.</p>
<p>Sec. 10. That this act take effect from the date of its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>December 20, 1861</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXIII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act for the relief of the heirs of Isaac Pierson.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />missioner of the General Land Office be, and he is hereby authorized and required to issue to the heirs of Isaac Pierson, a patent to the three hundred and twenty acres of land located by virtue of the unconditional certificate, number twenty-four, for three hundred and twenty acres of land issued to the said Isaac Pierson by the Board of Land Commissioners of Grimes county, on the twelfth day of January, 1848, and situated in Grimes county, upon such heirs paying the patent fees.</p>
<pb n="534" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="12" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<p>Sec. 2. That this act take effect and be in farce from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>December 20, 1861</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXIV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to incorporate the Texas Manufacturing Company.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That a body corporate and politic be, and the same is hereby created and established, to consist of a Board of Directors, Stockholders, President of a company or association of in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dividuals, under the corporate name and style of the Texas Manufacturing Com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pany, with the right and privilege of manufacturing cotton and woolen goods, and any other fabrics for home use; to own real, and personal property, to sue and be sued, to plead and be impleaded, to contract and be contracted with, to take, buy, sell and convey real, personal and mixed property, and to do and perform all other acts and things necessary to the successful prosecution of the object of the asso<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ciation; and that John M. Brown, J. D. McAdoo, Gabriel Felder, L. W. Groce, Wm. L. Crump, Harris Hoit, N. Cavanaugh, Samuel Holliday, J. L. Farquhar, James P. Flewellen, Terrell J. Jackson, T. B. Traynham, R. H. Felder and R. T. Flewellen, are hereby appointed Commissioners to open books and receive subscriptions to the capital stock of said Company, and as soon as the sum of fifty thousand dollars in cotton, wool or money shall have been subscribed the Commissioners herein named shall meet and organize said Company; a majority of said Commissioners shall con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />stitute a quorum to do business, and shall hold their first meeting at the town of Washington, in Washington county, Texas, as soon as consistent after the passage of this act; of the time of the first meeting proper notice shall be given said Com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />missioners in writing or otherwise.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. The capital stock of said Company shall not exceed two hundred and fifty thousand dollars, which may be invested in any manner calculated to insure the successful prosecution of the business of the Company, who shall also have the right to locate their manufactory at any point or place in the State of Texas which they may deem most eligible, provided they can obtain, by purchase or otherwise, a good and sufficient title to the location they may desire.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. The parties named and appointed Commissioners by this got are hereby invested with the right and power of Directors, until Directors are chosen by the stockholders, when the power of said Commissioners shall cease.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. When fifty thousand dollars of the capital stock is subscribed on the books of the Company, the Commissioners shall proceed to organize said Company, by calling the stockholders together, and dividing the capital stock into shares of one hundred dollars each, each share entitling the owner thereof to one vote, by himself or by written proxy. Said shares shall be deemed personal property, and shall be transferable at any meeting of the stockholders by any conveyance in writing which may show that the stock has changed hands.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. The government of the affairs of said Company shall be vested in a Board of five Directors, a majority of whom shall constitute a quorum for the transaction of business. They shall elect one of their number President of the Company. The Commissioners shall give at least twenty days notice of election for Directors, who shall be chosen from among the stockholders, and hold their office for two years, and have the power to fill any vacancy that <pb n="535" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="13" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw> may occur in their Board until the next regular election. They may also appoint a Secretary, Treasurer, Superintendent and such other officers and agents as may be required, and prescribe and require bonds for the faithful performance of their duties. They shall have the right to pass and adopt all needful by-laws and regu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lations necessary for the proper conduct of their business, and keep or cause to be kept accurate records of all meetings of the Board of Directors and Company, which records shall always be open to the inspection of the stockholders, together with such other books as may be necessary to show, at all times, the amount of expenditures, receipts and disbursements of the Company.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. The Board of Directors shall be convened by the President, who shall preside at all meetings of the Board, and in his absence a President pro tem may be chosen by the Directors.</p>
<p>Sec. 7. Any agreement in writing, by which any person shall become a sub<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />scriber to the capital stock of said Company, may be enforced against him or her according to its terms, and if any subscriber shall fail to pay any installment called for, or amount due upon his or her share or shares so subscribed and called for by the Directors, within ninety days from the date of said instalment is required to be paid, the Dorectors may sell at auction and transfer to the purchaser, the share or shares of such delinquent, and if the proceeds of sale shall not be sufficient to pay the amount due on the said subscription, with interest and cost of selling Said share or shares, such delinquent shall be held responsible and liable for the re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mainder due the Company, and if the proceeds shall exceed the amount so due the Company, with interest and charges deducted, said delinquent shall be entitled to the surplus.</p>
<p>Sec. 8. The rights, powers, privileges and immunities hereby granted and con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ferred under this act of incorporation shall be and remain in force for thirty years from the passage of the same.</p>
<p>Sec. 9. Should any stockholder, at any time, be displeased with, or wish to withdraw from said Company, or dispose of his interest, or require a distribution of dividends, he or she shall not be permitted to institute legal proceedings against the Company to adjust his individual rights, or in way to impede the progress of said Company, unless sanctioned by a majority of the stockholders in the same, but is permited and required to dispose of his interest in the market, at such price as such stock may command at the time, and he or she so selling, shall thenceforth be exonerated from any loss said Company may afterward sustain, and debarred from any future profits said stock may realize; a majority of the stockholders being re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />quired at all times, to agree upon a dissolution of the Company, and a distribution or sale of the property and effects of said Company, before the same can be acted upon.</p>
<p>Sec. 10. This act shall take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>December 21, 1861</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act for the relief of the heirs of Sanford Holman, deceased, who was a soldier in the service of Texas, at the battle of San Jacinto.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Terns, That the Commissioner of the General Land Office be, and he is hereby authorized to issue to the heirs of Sanford Holman, deceased, a donation certificate for 640 acres of land, in consideration of the services of said Sanford Holman as a soldier in the service of Texas at the battle of San Jacinto.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. This act to take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>December 21, 1861</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
<pb n="536" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="14" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXVI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act for the relief of Garrett F. Lankford.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Commissioner of the General Land Office be, and he is hereby required to issue to Garrett F. Lankford an unconditional certificate for nine hundred and sixty acres of land, which certificate may be surveyed and located as provided for other genuine certificates, provided the same shall be received in full satisfaction of his claim against the State of Texas for corn furnished the late Republic of Texas.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this act shall take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>December 21, 1861</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXVII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to prohibit the sale of intoxicating liquors within four and a half miles of the Court House, in Fort Worth, Tarrant county, Texas.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That any person who shall be convicted of selling any intoxicating liquors, at any place within four and a half miles of the Court House in Fort Worth, Tarrant county, ex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cept for medicinal or sacramental purposes, shall be subject to a fine or not less than fifty nor more than two hundred dollars for each offence; and if any druggist or person shall be convicted of selling such liquors, under the pretence that they are to be used for medicinal or sacramental purposes, to individuals who will drink the same as a beverage, they, the vendors, shall be subject to the above penalties.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>December 23, 1861</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXVIII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to incorporate the Marcelina Bridge and Manufacturing Company.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That James R. Skiles, and his associates, be declared a body corporate and politic, to be known by the name and style of &#8220;The Marcelina Bridge and Manufacturing Com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pany,&#8221; and by that name may sue and be sued, plead and be impleaded, and have succession and a common seal, which they may change, alter or break, at pleasure.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That said Company is hereby invested with the power to erect and es<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tablish a Bridge across the San Antonio River, at or near the falls, known as the Cnquiste or Salto, in the county of Karnes, and to exact and receive the rates of toll hereinafter provided, for passing over said bridge; and, also, to establish and ereec in the same neighborhood, to be propelled by water or steam, a manufactory, for the purpose of manufacturing fabrics of any description, of cotton, wool, hemp or other materials; provided the fabrics so manufactured shall be of the descrip-<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" /> tion brought into the State of Texas from other States or countries; and further provided, that the rates of toll charged by said Company for crossing over said bridge shall mnt exceed 75 cents for every loaded wagon, 50 cents for every loaded cart, 25 cents for every pleasure carriage, or empty vehicle, 10 cents for every man and horse, 5 cents for every foot passenger, 5 cents for every horse or head of neat cattle and 3 cents for every hog, sheep, or goat.</p>
<pb n="537" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="15" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<p>Sec. 3. That the capital stock of said Company shall not exceed two hundred and fifty thousand dollars, to be held in shares of fifty dollars each; and that the said James R. Skiles, be and he is hereby appointed a Commissioner to receive sub<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />scriptions and organize said Company.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. That the stockholders of said Company shall annually elect a Board of Directors, to consist of not less than three, nor more than seven, and one of whom shall be chosen a President, for and during the term of one year; and the Dorectors so elected, shall have the management and control of the affairs of said Company, and in the election of Directors, every stockholder shall be entitled to a vote for each share of stock held by him.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. That the stockholders be and they are hereby authorized to enact such by-laws and rules for the government of their business, not inconsistent with the Constitution and laws of the State, nor with the charter, as to them may appear proper.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. That this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage, and continue in force for the period of thirty years.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>December 23d, 1861</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXIX.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act for the relief of the heirs of James McCown, deceased, assignee of George S. Jones.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Commissioner of the General Land Office, be and he is hereby authorized and re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />quired to issue to the heirs of James McGown, deceased, assignee of George S. Jones, an unconditional certificate for six hundred and forty acres of land, by virtue of Conditional No. 616, issued to said Jones, by the Board of Land Commissioners of Harrisburg County, on the 5th day of July, 1838; which may be located and patented in like manner, as other genuine Headright Certificates.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>December 24th, 1861</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXX.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to amend the Charter of the &#8220;Waco Classical School.&#8221;</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the act approved February 2d, 1860, incorporating the Trustees of the Waoo Classical School, be amended, so that the said corporation be hereafter known and desig<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />nated as, Waco University.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That in addition to the individuals now composing the Board of Trustees of said corporation, the following named persons are hereby constituted and de<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />clared to be members thereof, to-wit: Thomas P. Aycock, H. M. Watkins, Wm. Hogue, W. A. Milner, J. P. Cole, W. P. Rogers, Paul Mackershan, E. D. Towns, J. M. Perry, and C. R. Breedlove; and, the aforesaid persons, together with the present Board, as aforesaid, shall, by style and title of Waco University, have and hold personal and real estate, to any amount not exceeding fifty thousand dollars, ex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />clusive of gifts and bequests; and by said style and title shall succeed to, and enjoy all the rights, privileges, and immunities granted by the act to which this is an amendment.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That the said Board of Trustees are hereby authorized, upon the recommendation of the Faculty of said University, to confer upon any pupil of said University, or upon any other person, any of the degrees usually con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" /><pb n="538" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="16" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw> feared by similar institutions in any of the departments or branches of Literature, Arts, Science, Theology, Law or Medicine; and to grant Diplomas for the same; and in all other respects to exercise the functions of the most favored literary institu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tions in the State of Texas.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. That said Board of Trustees shall appoint the times of their annual and semi-annual meetings; and at such meetings only such rules and regulations of a permanent nature be made or amended, or any general policy of the University be adopted or altered. But the said Board may appoint, of their own number, an Executive Committee of four, of whom the President of the Board, shall be ex-officio chairman, whose duty it shall be, in the interim, to make all needful temporary regulations, and to supervise the financial and other interests of the University, subject, however, to the said Board, and under such rules as it may, from time to time, prescribe.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. The said Board of Trustees may appoint, from time to time, a Board of Visitors, or Curators, whose duty it shall be to visit the annual and semi-annual commencements of said University, examine the text and other books used, in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />quire concerning the course of study, exercise a general advisory care over the in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />terests of the University, subject, however, to such restrictions as may be imposed by the said Board of Trustees.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. That the third section of the act, to which this is an amendment, be and the same is hereby repealed; and that this act take effect and he in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>December 24th, 1861</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXXI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act amendatory of and supplemental to an act to incorpurate the city of Marshall, passed January 30th, 1856.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That in order to secure an active system of inspection over the conduct of slaves, as con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />templated by the charter of the city of Marshall, and a more perfect system of police for the protection of citizens and property, the City Council of said city are hereby authorized and empowered to cause every white male citizen, within the limits of said corporation to perform patrol duty under such regulations as may be adopted by said Council.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>December 24, 1861</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXXII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to amend the 1st and 5th sections of an act to incorporate the East Fork Bridge Company, approved 9th February, 1860.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the first section of the above entitled act shall hereafter read as follows:&#8212;That James Farris and William Wilson and such others as they may associate with them, and their successors, be, and they are hereby constituted and declared to be a body politic and corporate, under the name and style of the East Fork Bridge Company.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That the fifth section of said act shall be so amended as to read as fol<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lows:&#8212;That said bridge shall be completed within two years from and after the 1st day of January, 1862, otherwise this charter shall be null and void.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>December 27, 1861</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<pb n="539" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="17" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXXIII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act granting Solomon Wolfe the privilege of constructing a Toll Bridge across the Angelina river and sloughs on the Nacogdoches side of said river.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That Solomon Wolfe is hereby authorized and granted the privilege to construct a bridge across the Angelina river and the sloughs on the Nacogdoches side of said river, near the town of Linwood, in Cherokee county, where the present mail route from Nacogdoches, Crockett and Huntsville crosses said stream.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That the bridge contemplated to be built, shall be completed within one year from the first day of January, 1862, and that the privilege hereby granted, shall extend to the said Wolfe and his assigns for the term of twenty years from the date of the passage of this act.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That it shall be the duty of said Wolfe to construct a good, and substan<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tial bridge across the river at the place, and within the time prescribed in the first and second sections of this act, and good and substantial bridges over all sloughs that are in the river bottom on the Nacogdoches side of said river; and it shall also be the duty of said Wolfe to keep the road through the bottom in good order so as to facilitate travel.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. That whenever said bridges shall have been constructed, made and com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pleted, and shall have been examined and reported in good order and repair by the Commissioners appointed for that purpose in the manner prescribed by this act, the proprietor may erect a toll gate at some convenient place in the immediate vicinity of said bridges, and demand and receive at said gate, from all and any persons pass<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing over said bridges, toll according to the following rates: For all buggies and wagons drawn by one borse or mule, 30 cents; drawn by two horses or mules, 50 cents; drawn by two oxen, 50 cents; drawn by four horses, mules or oxen, 75 cents; and all over four, one dollar; for a man and horse, ten cents; for a footman, five cents; for each head of cattle, horses, or mules, four cents; sheep, hogs or goats two cents per head.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. That the County Court of Nacogdoches county shall appoint two com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />missioners, on the application of the proprietor of said toll bridge, citizens of said county, whose duty it shall be to examine and approve said bridges and road, au<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />thorized by this act to be constructed and made, and report the same whenever completed and in good order to said County Court, at a regular quarterly session thereof. Said Commissioners, appointed under the provisions of this act, shall hold their office for the term of two years and until successors shall have been ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pointed; and it shall be the duty of said County Court to appoint commissioners biennially to examine and report, at least twice in each and every year, the condi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion of said bridges and road herein authorized to he constructed and made by said Wolfe for which service the said commissioners shall each receive two dollars per day for the time they may be necessarily employed in the discharge of the duties hereby imposed, on them, to be paid by the proprietor for the time being of such privileged improvement.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. That it shall be the duty of the commissioners appointed under the pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />visions of this act, whenever said bridges and road shall be found out of order and unfit for travel, to direct said toll gate to be thrown open, and to so remain until said bridges and road shall be put in good order by the proprietor: and it shall not be lawful for the said proprietor to charge or receive toll during the time said bridges and road shall remain out of order as reported by said commissioners.</p>
<p>Sec. 7. That the owner or proprietor of said bridges shall be liable, by <pb n="540" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="18" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw> action, for damages to any person who may sustain injury to person or property by reason of negligence or failure to keep in repair said bridges and road, before any court having jurisdiction of the amount of damages claimed; provided that nothing contained in this act shall be so construed as to obstruct the free navigation of said stream; and further provided that nothing in this act shall interfere with vested rights heretofore granted.</p>
<p>Sec. 8. That this act shall take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>December 27, 1861</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXXIV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to incorporate the Pulaski Bridge Company.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That James Chatham, and those persons he may associate with him, be, and they are hereby constituted a body corporate and politic under the name and style of the Pulaski Bridge Company; that under such name and style they may sue and be sued, plead and be impleaded, and in such corporate capacity are hereby authorized to build and construct a bridge over and across the Sabine river, at a point known as Pulaski, in the county of Panola.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That the said James Chatham, and his associates, shall construct said bridge in a durable and substantial manner within five years from the time of the conclusion of peace between the Southern Confederacy and the United States of America: said bridge shall be ninety-five feet in length and thirteen feet in breadth, with forty feet space in the middle, which shall be filled with a slide to be drawn out for the purpose of allowing boats to pass and to prevent the obstruction of the navigation of said river; each end of said bridge for twenty-five feet to be placed on solid posts, and said bridge shall be kept in good repair for all passengers for the term of twenty years from the completion thereof, and be ready at all times to pass all persons, carriages, wagons and teams, and stock that may wish to cross said bridge; and no other public bridge shall be built or constructed within four miles of this bridge on said river.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That the County Court of Panola county shall appoint two commissioners on the application of said Company, whose duty it shall be to examine and approve said bridge and report the same, when completed and in good order, to said County Court, at a regular session thereof, and when the said commissioners shall have re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ported as aforesaid, the said company may demand and receive from every person crossing said bridge toll according to the following rates: For all carriages and wagons ten cents per wheel and five cents per head for the team attached thereto; for horse or mule and rider, ten cents; for loose horses and mules, five cents per head; cattle per head, two and a half cents; hogs, sheep and goats, one cent per head.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. That said James Chatham and his associates shall be responsible for any accident which may happen to any one so crossing, if it be clearly manifest that such accident was caused from any insufficiency pertaining to said bridge.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. That this act be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>December 27, 1861</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
<pb n="541" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="19" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXXV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to authorize the payment of audited scrip against the county of Cameron in satisfaction of the county license tax for the retail of spirituous, vinous or other intoxicating liquors in quantities of less than a quart.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the County Treasurer of the county of Cameron, be, and he is hereby authorized and required to receive, in payment of the tax specified in the caption hereof, any of the audited scrip or indebtedness of said county, whether audited by the District or County Court of said county, of whatever nature or description, in all cases where parties making such payment shall elect to make the same in such scrip or in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />debtedness, any law to the contrary notwithstanding.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>December 30, 1861</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXXVI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to authorize the Governor to appoint an Agent for the Alabama and Cooshattie Indians, and to make an appropriation for the same.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the office of Indian Agent of the Alabama and Cooshattie Indians is hereby created, and the salary of such officer shall in no case exceed the sum of four hundred dol<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lars per annum.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. The Governor shall appoint some suitable person to superintend, and take care of said Indians; whose duty shall be to visit them from time to time to learn their necessities, to encourage and promote their agricultural interests, and to pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tect them from the depredations of mischievous persons.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. The Governor may employ an agent at less than the sum hereinbefore mentioned, provided he is satisfied that the objects of this act as indicated in section 2d can be as well attained.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. The sum of eight hundred dollars is hereby appropriated to defray the ex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />penses of the said agent. This act shall take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>December 30, 1861</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXXVII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act supplemental to an act entiled &#8220;An Act to incorporate the West Fork Bridge Company,&#8221; passed February 11th, 1860.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted, by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the West Fork Bridge Company, incorporated by the act to which this is a sup<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />plement, shall have the right of way for the distance of one and a half miles above said bridge, and one and a half miles below the same; and that all and every per<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />son or persons are prohibited from making or opening any public road or crossing upon said stream, to wit: the west fork of Trinity river, within said limits.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>December 30, 1861</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
<pb n="542" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="20" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXXVIII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act for the relief of the Eastern Texas Railroad Company.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That when, the Eastern Texas Railroad Company shall complete the next section of five consecutive miles of their road, beyond the twenty-five miles now completed, or connect the same with the Texas and New Orleans Railroad, they shall be entitled to receive from this State, the sum of thirty thousand dollars as a loan, in the United States five per cent indemnity bonds, belonging to the special school fund, and the Board of School Commissioners of this State shall be, and they are hereby authorized and required to deliver the same to said Company upon the execution of their mortgage bond in favor of this State for that amount, as required by the act entitled &#8220;an act to provide for the investment of the special school fund in the bonds of railroad companies incorporated by this State,&#8221; approved August 13th, 1856; provided that nothing in this act shall be so construed as to deprive said company of the right to receive the remainder of the loan, over and above said thirty thousand dollars, to which they may be entitled under the act above recited in this section.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That the Commissioner of the General Land Office be, and he is author<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ized and required to issue to the said Railroad Company, in addition to the sixteen sections they may be entitled to under the general railroad law, certificates in quantities not less than six hundred and forty acres, for the amount of seven thou<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sand five hundred dollars. Said certificates may be located in the same manner as head-right certificates ore located, except that the locations shall be made in bodies of not less than six hundred and forty acres; provided said certificates shall be issued at the rate of fifty cents per acre.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. Said Company shall not be required to complete the first fifty miles of their road until one year after the termination of the war between the United States and the Confederate States of America.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. This act shall take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>December 30, 1861</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXXIX.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to change the names of certain children therein named, and to authorize certain persons therein named to adopt such children.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the infant female child now in the possession of J. P. Dent and his wife Prances W. Dent, whose parentage is unknown, shall be hereafter known and called by the name of &#8220;Nellie Dent,&#8221; and said J. P. Dent and Prances W. Dent are hereby author<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ized to adopt said child as their lawful heir; and said child shall have all the rights and privileges, and shall stand in law in the same position, in all respects, as though she were their natural heir; and said child, until she is twenty-one years of age or married, shall be under the control of said J. P. and Prances W. Dent, as though she were their natural offspring.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That the name of Alexander Wright be, and the same is hereby changed to Alexander Lea; and J. H. Lea is hereby authorized to adopt said Alexander, and after such adoption, shall have control of, and shall be under the obligation to edu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cate and support said Alexander as though he were the natural heir of said J. H. Lea.</p>
<pb n="543" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="21" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<p>Sec. 3. That this act shall be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>December 31, 1861</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XL.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act for the relief of Mrs. Martha Brenan.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Commissioner of the General Land Office be, and he is hereby required to issue Mrs. Martha Brenan, a certificate for one league and labor of land, which may be located, surveyed and patented, as any other first class certificate: Provided, that the said Mrs. Martha Brenan, has not heretofore received any land from the Repub<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lic, or State of Texas.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>December 31st, 1861</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XLI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act for the relief of the heirs of Abner Fox.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Commissioner of the General Land Office be, and he is hereby authorized to issue a certificate for six hundred and forty acres of land, to the heirs of Abner Box, de<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ceased, a colonist, in Peter&#8217;s colony, to be located, surveyed and patented, as other Peter&#8217;s colony certificates are: Provided, it shall appear that no certificate has ever been issued to said Abner Fox, or his heirs, by virtue of his emigration hither.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>December 31st, 1861</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER LXII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act supplemental to an act to authorize the County Courts of Nacogdoches, Navarro, Jackson, Colorado, and others, therein mentioned, to regulate the pay of Sheriffs therein, in certain cases, approved April 8th, 1861.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the County Courts of the Counties of Brown, El Paso, Hopkins, Houston, Tarrant. Williamson, Angelina, Lamar, Upshur, Hunt, Gonzales, Lavaca, De Witt and Panola, be and they are hereby authorized to allow the Sheriffs of their respective Counties, for summoning jurors, in the District Court, serving election notices, notices on overseers of roads, attending on the District Court, and doing all other business not provided for, such sum or sums of money, as such County Courts may deem sufficient for said services, not to exceed two hundred dollars per annum, to be paid out of the Treasury of the County, any law to the contrary, notwithstanding.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>January 1st, 1862</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XLIII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act for the relief of Francisco A. Ruiz and Antonio Ruiz de Herrera.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas,That the Commissioner of the General Land Office be, and he is hereby author<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ized and required to issue to Francisco A. Ruiz, two certificates for six hundred <pb n="544" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="22" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw> and forty acres of land, each, and to Antonio Ruiz de Herrera, two certificates for six hundred and forty acres of land, each; and to Francisco A. Ruiz and Antonio Ruiz de Herrera, jointly, one certificate for one hundred and ninety-four acres of land, which certificates may be located and patented, as other headright certificates.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>January 2nd, 1862</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XLIV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act attaching the Counties of Clay and Wichita to the County of Montague for Judicial Purposes.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Counties of Clay and Wichita are hereby attached to the County of Montague, for all judicial purposes, pertaining to, or coming within the jurisdiction of the District Court: Provided, that the jurisdiction hereby conferred upon the County of Montague, shall revert to the County of Clay so soon as it shall be ascertained that the said County of Clay, shall have within its limits, seventy-five resident voters.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. The clerk of the District Court of said Montague County, shall issue, and the Sheriff thereof, execute all process that may be necessary to enforce the juris<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />diction hereby conferred upon the County of Montague.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That this act be in force from the date of its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>January 3rd, 1862</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XLV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act for the relief of W. A. Grady.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Commissioner of the General Land Office, be and is hereby required to issue to W. A. Grady, a headright certificate for one-third of a league of land, to which he is entitled by virtue of immigration to this country in 1835.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>January 2nd, 1862</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XLVI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to amend an act to authorize the County Court of Collin County to levy a special tax for the erection of a Court House therein, passed January 7th, 1860.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the first section of an act, passed January 7th, 1860, authorizing the County Court of Collin County, to levy a tax to build a court house therein, shall be, and the same is hereby amended, so as to read as follows: &#8220;That the County Court of Collin County be, and it is hereby authorized to levy a special tax, for the years of 1862 and 1863, in addition to the county tax now authorized by law, upon the taxable property of said county, not to exceed, in any one year, the sum of six and one-fourth cents upon each hundred dollars of valuation, which tax shall be levied, collected and returned, the same as other county taxes, and when collected, shall be applied to the building of a Court house in said county, and to no other pur<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pose, and this act shall take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>January 3, 1862</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
<pb n="545" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="23" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XLVII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to authorize and require the Commissioner of the General Land Office to issue patent for the land located by virtue of unconditional certificate No. 16, is<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sued to Josiah Bradshaw, by the Board of Land Commissioners for Angelina County, which has not been reported by the Clerk.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Commissioner of the General Land Office be, and he is hereby authorized and required to issue patent for the land located by virtue of unconditional certificate No. 16, issued to Josiah Bradshaw, by the Board of Land Commissioners, for Ange<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lina County, as though the same had been reported to the Commissioner of the General Land Office, by the Clerk of said Court, as now required by law.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>January 2, 1862</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XLVIII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to repeal an act supplemental and amendatory of the act creating the County of Kauffman, approved April 6th, 1861.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the act of April 6th, 1861, changing the boundaries of Kauffman and Henderson Counties, be and the same is hereby repealed.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That the boundary lines of said counties referred to in the first section of this act, shall be and remain as they were, prior to the passage of the supple<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mental act, of April 6th, 1861; and that this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>January 2nd, 1862</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XLIX.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act for the relief of William V. Hughes, assignee of Jonathan Bird.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the proper accounting Officers be, and they are hereby authorized to issue a second class certificate of Public Debt, to William V. Hughes, assignee of Jonathan Bird, for one hundred and fifty dollars, in lieu of lost draft, issued by the Secretary of the Treasury of the late Republic, on the 31st of January, 1845, to said Jonathan Bird, for a similar amount, under the provisions of an act, approved January 8th, 1845; and when said certificate is so issued, the Treasurer is hereby authorized to pay the same: Provided, that the said Hughes shall first file with the Comptroller, a bond with security in double the amount, that the original draft shall not become a charge against the State.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this act take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>January 4th, 1862</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER L.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act for the relief of the purchasers of University Lands.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of texas, That the purchasers of the University lands shall have until the first of January, 1864, or six months after the close of the present war, should it terminate <pb n="546" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="24" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw> before the date named, or until otherwise provided by law, to make payment of the installments and interest due the University fund for said lands: Provided, that this act shall not be construed to prevent such persons as may desire to do so, from paying the installments, or the interest, or the entire purchase money due from them, and provided, further, that the sureties of each purchaser assent, in writing, to such extension of time, or the principals renew their notes, with two or more sureties, to be approved by the Comptroller.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. This act shall take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>January 4th, 1862</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER LI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act authorizing the issue of duplicate Treasury Warrants No. 3487, in favor of A. M. Ainsworth, and No. 17320 in favor of P. A. Work.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Comptroller of Public Accomnts be, and he is hereby authorized to issue a warrant on the Treasury, duplicating a warrant issued to A. M. Ainsworth on the 23d of August, 1861, for ninety-one dollars and sixty-six cents, the same to be delivered to E. H. Moore. That he be also authorized to issue a warrant on the Treasury, dupli<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cating warrant No. 17320, to P. A. Work, on the 25th day of March, 1861, for one hundred and sixty dollars, the same to be delivered to Milton J. Bean; provided that the said E. H. Moore shall file with the Comptroller a good and sufficient bond to the State, with at least two solvent securities, binding the parties to pay to the State the amount of the warrant duplicated, with interest, in the event the original shall ever be presented for payment; in which event suit may be instituted in Travis county; and, provided further, that the said Milton J. Bean shall file with the Comptroller&#39; a like bond, with like securities and with like conditions as the one required by this act of the said E. H. Moore.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this act shall take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>January 4, 1862</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER LII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act for the relief of Lipscomb Norvell.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />missioner of the General Land Office be, and he is hereby authorized and required to issue to Lipscomb Norvell, a headright certificate for one labor of land, it being the balance due him as a colonist of 1835, he having received a title under the laws of Coahuila and Texas for one league of land; provided it shall appear that said Lipscomb Nowell, his heirs or assigns have never received a certificate for said labor of land.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this act take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>January 6, 1862</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER LIII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act for the relief of John Thomas, assignee of D. Murphy.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Commissioner of the General Land Office be, and he is hereby authorized and required to issue to John Thomas, as assignee of D. Murphy, a certificate far six hundred and forty acres of land as a bounty for services in the army <pb n="547" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="25" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw> of the late Republic of Texas, from 7th of January to 9th August, 1836, in command of Col. Fannin, which said certificate may be located, surveyed and patented as other genuine bounty certificates; provided the original certificate issued by Geo. W. Poe and transferred by D. Murphy to said Thomas, be surrendered to the Com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />missioner of the General Land Office.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this act take effect and be in force from and after its ms sage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>January 6, 1862</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER LIV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act for the relief of Nelson Tarver.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Comptroller be, and he is hereby authorized to extend the time for Nelson Tarver&#8217;s settlement of taxes, for the county of Henderson, for three years, in equal annual instalments, from the date hereof, with interest thereon from the time of original settlement till its payment; provided the surities of said Nelson Tarver shall assent to the same by an endorsement upon his tax bond.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>January 6, 1862</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER LV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to reincorporate the town of San Felipe de Austin, and renew the charter granted to said town on the 18th of November, A. D. 1837.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the town of San Felipe de Austin is hereby re-incorporated, with the same rights, porwers and privileges that it had by the act of the Congress of the Republic of Texas, approved November 18th, 1837, and the charter granted at that time is hereby renewed.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>January 6, 1862</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER LVI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to make valid all acts and contracts of the corporate or supposed corporate officers of the town of San Felipe de Austin, since the 1st day of August, A. D., 1859.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That all acts done and all contracts made by the corporate or supposed corporate officers of the town of San Felipe de Austin, since the 1st day of August, A. D., 1859, are hereby made valid and binding; provided that, said acts and contracts were such as were authorized by the charter granted to said town on the 18th day of November, A. D., 1837.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>January 6, 1862</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER LVII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to incorporate the Dallas County Agricultural and Mechanical Association.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That Amon McCammos, President; A. C. Halleck and William Jenkins, Vice Presi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dents, and T. C. Hawpe, Jno. Jackson, Wm. H. Hord, James Bentley, A. <pb n="548" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="26" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw> Moss, Wm. C. McCamy, Geo. Wilson, Richard Bruton and P. Taylor, Directors, and their successors in office be, and they are hereby constituted a body politic and cor<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />porate, with perpetual succession, under the name and style of &#8220;Dallas County Agricultural and Mechanical Association,&#8221; and by that name may sue and be sued, plead and be impleaded, and be capable of acquiring and holding real and personal estate and of using, managing and disposing of the same under the same rules and regulations that govern individuals.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That said Association shall be composed of individual stockholders, who shall pay into the Treasury thereof the sum of twenty dollars each, and shall thereby become equally interested in all the estate, both real and personal, rents, profits, monies and effects of said Association, and equally liable for all damages against it.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That said Association shall manage and control all its affairs under such rules and regulations as they shall see fit to adopt, not inconsistent with the laws and Constitution of this State, and the Constitution of the Confederate States of America, and twenty-one members shall constitute a quorum to do business, until said Association shall change the same by its own constitution.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. That said Association shall, from time to time, make and amend such constitution, by-laws, rules and regulations for its action, its members and its fairs, as a majority of those present shall deem proper, or may submit the same to the regularly elected directors, together with the regulations and management of all fairs, improvements and other business, subject, however, at all times to the ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />proval or rejection of the Association.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. The officers of said Association shall be a President, two Vice Presidents, a Treasurer, a Corresponding and a Recording Secretary, nine Directors, who shall, be elected annually on the first Monday in December; shall immediately enter upon the discharge of their respective duties, and shall continue in office until their suc<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cessors are elected and qualified. The President and Vice Presidents shall be mem<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />bers of the Board of Directors, and hold the same office therein as in the Associa<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. That said Association may establish fair grounds and hold fairs therein, and may make such rules and general police regulations as will be sufficient to pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tect themselves, those who visit said fairs, and all property upon said said fair grounds, and within one half mile thereof, from molestation or injury, and the bet<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ter to accomplish said object, the Directors and Marshal, duly appointed at said fairs, shall each have the powers of a sheriff or constable within said limits, and all Justices of the Peace of said county, and the Mayor of the town of Dallas, shall have jurisdiction within said limits, of all cases arising under the rules and regula<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tions, and may fine and imprison for any violation of said rules and regulations, and for any disorderly or malicious conduct in contempt of said Association, or insulting to, or to the injury of any person or persons within said limits; provided that such imprisonment shall in no case exceed twenty-four hours, and said, fine one hundred dollars.</p>
<p>Sec. 7. That no person shall set up or carry on any establishment within one half mile of said fair grounds, for the retail or vending of any article of merchandise, or vinous or spirituous liquors, with the purpose of securing the benefits of a trade<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />with those who are drawn together by said fairs, unless he, she or they shall first obtain a license from said Association to set up or carry on said trade, and any per<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />son who shall violate this section of this act, shall forfeit and pay any sum not less than five dollars nor more than one hundred dollars for each day he shall so set up said trade, to be recovered before the authorities herein above specified.</p>
<p>Sec. 8. That all fines, forfeitures and penalties recovered, under the pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" /><pb n="549" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="27" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw> visions of this act, shall accrue to and be paid into the treasury of said Association.</p>
<p>Sec. 9. That this act shall take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>January 6th, 1862</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER LVIII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act for the relief of A. H. Cook.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Comptroller be, and he is hereby authorized and required to draw his warrant on the Treasurer of the State, in favor of A. H. Cook, for the sum of fifteen hundred and thirty 50-100 dollars, and the interest thereon, at the rate of eight per cent per annum, from the first day of January 1856; and that the Treasurer be required to pay the same out of any money in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>January 7th, 1862</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER LIX.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act supplementary to an act, incorporating the Southern Pacific Railroad Com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pany, approved 16th February, 1852, and to the several amendments and supple<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ments thereto, and for the relief of said Company.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the sec<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion of the Southern Pacific Railroad, now being graded by said Company, running from Jonesville in the County of Harrison, east to the boundary line between Texas and Louisiana, shall be deemed and taken as a part of the section of twenty-five consecutive miles, to be graded by said Company, in addition to the twenty-five miles already completed, in order to entitle said Company to the loan of six thousand dollars per mile, under the provisions of an act entitled, &#8220;An act to provide for the investment of the special school fund, in the bonds of Railroad Companies, incorpo<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />rated by the State,&#8221; passed 13th August, A. D. 1856, and that said section shall be deemed a part of the main trunk of said road, and the true eastern terminus thereof; the point where the same shall touch the boundary line between Louisiana and Texas, and without prejudice to the chartered rights, franchises, privileges and benefits of said Company, under the charter and the general laws of the State.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That in view of the fact said Company has nearly completed the grading of twenty-five consecutive miles, in addition to the first section of twenty-five miles already completed, and being worked, and is still progressing with the work on said road, and has a prospect of making a connected road from Marshall, in Harrison county, to Shreveport, in Louisiana, by an arrangement with the Vicksburg, Shreve<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />port and Texas Railroad Company, running through the State of Louisiana; the Governor, Comptroller and Attorney General, ex-officio School Commissioners, are instructed and directed to turn over to said Company the amount of indemnity bonds to which they are entitled, for the completion of twenty-five miles of said road, under the provisions of an act entitled &#8220;An act to provide for the investment of the special school fund, in the bonds of Railroad Companies, incorporated by the State,&#8221; passed 13th August, 1856; upon said Company executing its bonds to secure said loan, in confonnity with the 3rd section of said act.</p>
<pb n="550" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="28" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<p>Sec. 3. That said Company are authorized land empowered to purchase, own, con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />struct, equip, and work that portion of the Vicksburg, Shreveport and Texas Bail<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />road, extending from Shreveport, in Louisiana, to the eastern boundary line of Texas, upon such terms as they may obtain from the State of Louisiana, and may be agreed upon between them and the Vicksburg, Shreveport and Texas Railroad Company.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. That said Company are authorized and permitted, if it should desire so to do, to adopt the name of the Atlantic and Pacific Railroad Company.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. That this act shall be in force from and alter its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>January 8th, 1862</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER LX.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to consolidate in one act, and amend the several acts incorporating the city of Houston, in Harris county.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That all free white inhabitants of the city of Houston, shall be a body corporate, by the name of the Mayor, Aldermen and inhabitants of the city of Houston, and by that name they and their successors shall be known in law, and be capable of suing and being sued, and defending in all courts and all actions and matters whatsoever, and may have a common seal and may alter and change the same at their pleasure, and by the same name shall be capable of holding and conveying any estate, real or personal, for the use of said corporation: Provided, that such real estate be within the limits of said city.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That the bounds and limits of the said corporation shall include three miles square, to be run with the cardinal points of the compass, of which the Court house, in the city of Houston, shall be the centre.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That no person shall be ia qualified voter at any election for officers of said corporation, unless he possesses the qualifications of a citizen of this State, and has resided within the chartered limits of the corporation of said city six months, next preceding the election, and unless he be a householder or owner of real or per<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sonal estate, the last six months within the corporation limits of said city to the value of one hundred dollars, agreeably to the city tax roll, and has paid his taxes thereon, according to the city assessment for the preceding year.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. That no person shall be eligible as an officer of said city, who at the time of his election does not possess the qualifications of an elector, and has not resided in the said city twelve months next preceding, and has not held the last six months, within said city, real estate to the value of one thousand dollars, according to the city tax roll.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. That no person shall be eligible to the office of Mayor of said city, un<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />less he possesses the qualifications of an Alderman, and owns real estate to the value of two thousand dollars, in terms as required by the preceding section.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. That the city authorities are authorized to divide the city into a conven<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ient number of wards, not exceeding eight, and to fix and define the boundaries thereof.</p>
<p>Sec. 7. That the qualified voters of said corporation shall elect a Mayor, Recorder, Marshal, Sexton, and City Assessor and Collector, who shall hold their office for the term of one year, and until their successors shall be elected and qualified.</p>
<p>Sec. 8. That at the first annual election for city officers, after the passage act, there shall be elected two Aldermen from each ward; one of <pb n="551" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="29" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw> whom shall hold the office for the term of one year, and the other for the term of two years, and immediately after their being qualified, the Aldermen so elected from each ward, shall determine by lot who shall hold for the long term, and at every annual election thereafter, one Alderman shall be elected from each ward, who shall hold the office for the term of two years.</p>
<p>Sec. 9. That the Mayor and Aldermen shall constitute the City Council, over which the Mayor shall preside, when present, and in case of a tie in the vote of the Board he shall give the casting vote.</p>
<p>Sec. 10. That the City Council shall have power to regulate the manner and time of holding and conducting elections, not inconsistent with the laws and constitution of the State; and shall be the Judge of the elections of the officers of said corpora<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion.</p>
<p>Sec. 11. That the officers of said corporation before they enter upon the discharge of their duties, shall take and subscribe the oath of office required by the constitu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion of the State, which may be taken before any officer legally authorized to admin<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ister oaths.</p>
<p>Sec. 12. That the Mayor shall convene the Council whenever required to do so by three Aldermen of the said city, and no meeting shall proceed to the transaction of any business, unless it be composed of a majority of the whole number of Alder<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />men elected and qualified, and such a number, with or without the Mayor, shall be a quorum for the transaction of business.</p>
<p>Sec. 13. That in future the sittings, or assemblies, of the City Council of Houston shall be public, except where, at the request of two-thirds of the members present in said council, the said council shall deem it necessary to deliberate with closed doors.</p>
<p>Sec. 14. That in future the Mayor, Recorder, nor none of the Aldermen then in office, shall be allowed, either in his own name, or through the medium of other per<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sons, to become the lessee or bidder for any branch of the revenues of the city, nor for any work or undertaking whatsoever, which may be authorized or ordered by the corporation of said city.</p>
<p>Sec. 15. That in case of the inability of the Mayor of the city of Houston to per<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />form his duties, by reason of absence, refusal, or other cause, or in the event of a vacancy in said office, occasioned by death, resignation or otherwise, the Board of Aldermen of said city may be, and they are hereby, authorized and empowered to appoint from their own body a presiding officer, who shall be Mayor pro tem, and shall have, and may exercise, all the powers conferred by law on the Mayor, and shall perform all the duties thereof, until his return, the removal of such inbility, or a successor is elected and qualified; provided, that in case of a vacancy in said of<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fice, the City Council may order an election upon ten days notice, to fill such va<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cancy for the unexpired time.</p>
<p>Sec. 16. That whenever any order, resolution, by-law or ordinance may be passed by the Council, and is disagreed to by the Mayor, it shall be inoperative, unless the same shall be passed by a vote of a majority of the whole number of Aldermen, taken by yeas and nays, and recorded upon the journal of their proceedings.</p>
<p>Sec. 17. That in case of vacancy in the office of Aldermen, Recorder, Marshal, City Assessor and Collector, Sexton, or other subordinate office, the Mayor may or<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />der an election to fill the same, first giving ten days notice thereof, and the person so elected shall hold his office for the unexpired term.</p>
<p>Sec. 18. That the City Council shall elect a Secretary and Treasurer, and such other subordinate officers as may be necessary for preserving the peace and well or<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dering of the affairs of the said corporation, and shall prescribe their duties.</p>
<p>Sec. 19. That the City Council shall have power to remove any officer of the said corporation, for any neglect, misdemeanor, or malfeasance, in office. <pb n="552" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="30" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw> by a vote of three-fourths of the whole number of Aldermen elected and Qualified.</p>
<p>Sec. 20. That the City Council shall require such officers as they may see proper, to execute bonds for the faithful discharge of the duties and trusts incumbent upon them, in such amounts as it may deem necessary, with security, to be approved by the Council.</p>
<p>Sec. 21. That the Mayor and Recorder are hereby vested with all the powers and jurisdiction, civil and criminal, within the limits of said corporation, which may by law, be executed by Justices of the Peace, under the laws of this State, and in prosecutions, trials and proceeding, had before them under this act, and the by-laws and ordinances of said corporation, they shall be governed by the laws regulating the proceedings in Justices&#39; Courts, in force at the time, and shall be entitled to the same fees that Justices of the Peace are then allowed for similar service.</p>
<p>Sec. 22. That all process from the Mayor or Recorder may be directed to and exe<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cuted by the Sheriff, any Constable of the city, or the City Marshal, in the same manner that similar process from Justices of the Peace is executed.</p>
<p>Sec. 23. That it shall be the duty of the Mayor and Council to cause the Secre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tary and Treasurer of the corporation to publish, on the first Monday of March, in each year, an accurate, detailed and just statement of the receipts and expendi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tures, and condition of the treasury of said body politic, and publish the same in at least one of the gazettes printed in Houston; the said statement, before it is printed, shall be carried by the Treasurer aforesaid before some Judge or Justice of the Peace, before whom he shall testify on oath that the same is a faithful and cor<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />rect statement.</p>
<p>Sec. 24. That should the Secretary and Treasurer of said corporation refuse to account as directed by this Act, he shall pay a fine of two thousand dollars; said fine to be recovered on motion before the District Court by the District Attorney, or his assistant&#8212;ten days notice of which shall be given to the said Treasurer; and it is hereby made the duty of the District Attorney to inquire and see that the provisions of this Act are faithfully fulfilled, and proceed as the case may require.</p>
<p>Sec. 25. That the fines imposed by the regulations of the by-laws of the corpora<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion of Houston, shall not exceed the sum of one hundred dollars, and the recovery of the same shall be made before the Mayor or Recorder, in the name of the Mayor, Aldermen, and inhabitants of the city of Houston, for the benefit of said city.</p>
<p>Sec. 26. That the Mayor and City Council of Houston shall have power to ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />propriate so much of the revenues of the city, emanating from whatever source, to the improvement of the public market, roads, within or without the limits of the corporation, leading to the city, as they, in their wisdom, may, from time to time, deem expedient.</p>
<p>Sec. 27. That the Mayor and City Council of the city of Houston shall have full power and authority to make and pass such by-laws or ordinances as they shall deem necessary to maintain the cleanliness and salubrity of said city, to secure the safety and convenience of passing in the streets and squares, ways, levees, and other public roads, to fix the squaring, and to prevent any encroachment or other undertaking on the said public roads, to determine the completion and dimensions, the maintenance and repair of the said pavements in the said streets, at the cost of proprietors of houses, lands or neighboring lots, to fix the place and anchoring for all water crafts on the bayou, to establish an active system of inspection over the conduct of slaves, to establish a city guard, or patrols, to provide for lighting the streets, to deter<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mine in what part of the city wooden buildings shall not be allowed to be erected, to prevent gunpowder being stowed within the city and suburbs in such quan<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" /><pb n="553" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="31" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw> tity as to endanger the public safety, to determine on the means to be resorted to in order to extinguish conflagrations, and to prevent the same, to regulate the service of persons employed in working fire engines, to permit or forbid theatres, balls and other public amusements, to cause the playhouses and other places for shows or ex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />hibitions to be closed whenever the preservation of ordier, tranquility or public safety shall require it, also to close dram shops and drinking saloons whenever neces<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sary or expedient, to establish one or more market places, and to determine the mode of inspection for all comestibles sold publicly&#8212;either in said market or mar<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />kets, or in other places, to define and suppress nuisances, to regulate everything which relates to bakers, butchers, tavern keepers, or of grog shops, and other per<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sons keeping public houses, draymen, horse drivers, water carriers, and slaves em<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ployed as day laborers, to fix the compensation of said draymen, hack drivers, water carriers, common carriers, omnibus drivers, and baggage wagons, and to make other regulations which may contribute to the better administration of the affairs of said corporation, as well as for the maintenance of the police, tranquility and safety of said city: Provided, That no by-laws or regulations which have been made by said Mayor and City Council shall have any force and effect in what may be contrary to the provisions of the Constitution of the State of Texas. Provided, also, That said Mayor and City Council shall not have the power of fixing the price of any article sold in the market or other places, except wheat bread, the price of which may be regulated according to the market price of flour.</p>
<p>Sec. 28. That the Mayor and City Council of the said city shall have power to construct wharves on the banks of the Buffalo Bayou, within the limits of the cor<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />poration of said city, and such other improvements as may be necessary for the better navigation of said bayou, and for the convenience of landing vessels and their cargoes, and to lay contributions upon all such vessels and cargoes as may land at the said wharves, and to collect the same to defray the expenses thereof.</p>
<p>Sec. 29. That whenever any steamboat, or other craft, shall sink in the Buffalo Bayou, above the town of Harrisburg, so as to obstruct the navigation, it shall be the duty of the Mayor of the city of Houston, to appoint three good and discreet commissioners to inspect and examine the condition of such boat or craft sunk as aforesaid, who shal proceed immediately on their appointment, to make an exami<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />nation of such boat or craft so sunk, and report, in writing, their opinion, stating whether, in their opinion, the boat or craft sunk can be, or is likely to be, raised or removed within the space of ten days after their examination; and should they be of the opinion that such boat or craft is not likely to be raised or removed, so as to open the navigation, within the space of twenty days from the time of their ex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />amination, then and an that case, the Mayor land Aldermen of the city of Houston may order the removal of such boat or craft so sunk, in any manner they shall deem proper, without incurring any damage or penalty for the same.</p>
<p>Sec. 30. That said corporation of the city of Houston is hereby given full power and authority to take such steps to preserve and improve the navigation of the said Buffalo Bayou, above the town of Harrisburg, as they may think proper; and for that purpose they are authorized to levy and collect a tax on all steamboats and other craft running said Bayou, for the purpose of improving the navigation thereof: Provided, That the power in this section granted, shall not be construed to give said corporation any jurisdiction or con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />trol over said Buffalo Bayou, or the banks thereof, in any manner, without or beyond the corporate limits of said city, except for the purpose of pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tecting or improving the navigation of said bayou, and shall not give said cor<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />poration jurisdiction or control, to prevent, or interfere with the construction <pb n="554" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="32" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw> of any railroad or other bridge, by any company or person, across said bayou in such manner as not to interfere with the navigation of said bayou.</p>
<p>Sec. 31. That the City Council by a vote of a majority of the whole number of Aldermen, taken by yeas and nays, and entered upon their journal, shall have power to assess, license and tax, hawkers, pedlers, auctions, theatrical and other exhi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />bitions, shows and amusements, billiard tables, nine and ten pin alleys, public drays, wagons, omnibusses and carriages, grog shops, tippling houses, and dram shops, beer saloons, whether for the sale of domestic beers and liquors or otherwise, and such other trades or occupations not specially mentioned herein, as may be taxed by the laws of the State, and to suppress all gaming houses, and all disorderly houses, by whatever name or description known.</p>
<p>Sec. 32. That the City Council by a vote of a majority of the whole number of the Aldermen, taken by yeas and nays, and entered upon their journal, may assess and collect an annual direct tax upon all property, real and personal, situate and being within the limits of the corporation, not exceeding one-half of one per centum, ad valorem.</p>
<p>Sec. 33. That every person or persons on whom or whose vocation a license tax may have been assessed, shall, before engaging in such vocation, pay to the City Assessor and Collector the amount of such tax, taking his receipt therefor, which receipt shall entitle him, her, or them, to a corresponding license, to be issued by the Mayor. If any person or persons shall engage in any vocation within the limits of the city, on whom or which a license tax had been asssessed, by the City Coun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cil, without having first obtained a license therefor from the Mayor, such person or persons shall be liable to pay one-fourth of the amount of such annual license tax for each week, be, she or they, may be so engaged, and in the same proportion for each day, which may be recovered by action before the Recorder or any Justice of the Peace, or the District Court, according to the amount; one-fourth part of the recovery, for the use of the informer, and the balance to the city.</p>
<p>Sec. 34. That after the expiration of the time prescribed by law, for the payment of city taxes, the Assessor and Collector for the city, or such officer as the City Council may charge therewith, may proceed to seize upon any property, real or per<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sonal, the tax on which has not been paid, or that belongs to a delinquent tax<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />payer, and after advertising the same in some newspaper published in the city of Houston, or by posting at three public places, in said city, if there be no newspaper published as aforesaid, for twenty days, specifying the time and place of sale, may sell at the Court House door, of Harris county, to the highest bidder, for cash, so much of said property as will pay the taxes thereon or may be due from such delin<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />quent, as the case may be, together with costs of advertising and selling, unless the taxes and cost be paid before the day of sale. If the sales should not be completed on the day appointed, the Assessor and Collector may adjourn the sales from day to day, until they are all completed.</p>
<p>Sec. 35. That at the conclusion of the sales, and on compliance with the terms thereof, by a purchaser, the Assessor and Collector shall give to such purchaser a cer<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tificate of purchase, stating the amount of tax and costs paid, and describing the property sold, which shall entitle the purchaser to a deed for said property, at the expiration of twelve months, from the Mayor of the city; but such certificate may be redeemed within one year from the day of sale, by the owner of the property sold, or some person for him, by payment of double the amount of tax and costs paid by the holder; which payment may be made either to the City Treasurer, for the use of the holder of such certificate, or to the holder of such certificate.</p>
<pb n="555" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="33" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<p>Sec. 36. That if any certificate of purchase, given as before provided, be not re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />deemed within one year from the day of sale, then the holder may demand, and it shall be the duty of the Mayor of the city to give a deed to such holder, conveying all the right and interest of the person in whose name the property is sold, and of the owner, in case of unknown or non-resident owners, in and to the property speci<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fied in the certificate, on production and delivery of the certificate to him, such deed shall be signed by the Mayor, in his official capacity, and countersigned by the Sec<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />retary of the Council, under the city seal.</p>
<p>Sec. 37. That the city shall not be held responsible on any implied warranty, or for any damages under any deed or sale made for taxes; but the person injured by any neglect or malfeasance of any officer, shall have recourse against him for any damage sustained in consequence thereof.</p>
<p>Sec. 38. That any tax deed made as required by this act, shall be prima facie evidence that all the pre-requisites of the law have been complied with, and shall pass all the right of the person owning the property conveyed, unless it can be proven that the tax thereon had been paid before the sale, or the certificate of sale redeemed within the year aforesaid.</p>
<p>Sec. 39. That the Assessor and Collector shall, after his sales make returns to the Council of all property sold, and the names of the purchasers of each parcel of prop<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />erty, to whom certificates of purchase may be issued, which returns shall be pre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />served among the archives of the city.</p>
<p>Sec. 40. That the acts, so far as relate to the city of Houston, namely: &#8220;An act to incorporate the city of Houston, and other cities therein named, approved Janu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ary 28th, 1850; an act supplementary to an act, entitled an act, to incorporate the city of Houston, and other cities therein named, approved 28th January, 1839; ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />proved February 5th, 1840; an act to amend the several acts incorporating the city of Houston, approved November 17th, 1840; an act to amend an act to incorporate the city of Houston and other cities therein named, approved November 24th, 1841; an act to authorize the corporation of the city of Houston to remove obstructions in Buffalo Bayou, interfering with the navigation thereof, approved January 29th, 1842; an act supplementary to an act amending the several acts incorporating the city of Houston, approved February 3rd, 1844; an act to amend an act incorporat<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing the city of Houston, approved March 11th, 1848; and an act to provide for the election of all officers created by the charters, and Boards of Aldermen of the cities of Galveston and Houston, approved February 11th, 1852; be and the same are hereby repealed, and that all property actions, rights of actions, claims and de<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mands of every nature and kind, whatsoever, vested in said corporation, under and in virtue of the said laws, hereby repealed, shall vest in, remain and enure to the said corporation, under this act, as fully and completely in all respects, as if the said laws had not been repealed. And that all bylaws, resolutions and ordinances made and passed under, or in pursuance of the said laws hereby repealed, shall con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tinue and remain in full force, until repealed by the proper authorities of the said corporation. And this act shall take effect and be in force from and after the first day of February, A. D. 1862.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>January 8th, 1862</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<pb n="556" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="34" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER LXI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act for the relief of Levi English.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />missioner of the General Land Office be, and he is hereby instructed to issue to Levi English, of Atascosa county, a certificate for six hundred and forty acres of land, by virtue of his emigration to the Republic in 1837; provided a certificate in virtue of said emigration has never before been issued.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>January 8, 1862</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER LXII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act for the relief of Thomas F. Smith.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />missioner of the General Land Office be, and he is hereby authorized and required to issue to Thomas F. Smith an unconditional certificate, corresponding to condi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tional certificate No. 142, issued to the said Thomas F. Smith, for three hundred and twenty acres of land, by the Board of Land Commissioners of Lamar county, on the 29th day of December, 1841, to be located on any of the unappropriated do<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />main of the State.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this act take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>January 8, 1862</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER LXIII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act amendatory of an act supplementary to the second section of an act grant<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing a pension to Cynthia Ann Parker, approved April 8th, A. D. 1861.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted, by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the second section of the above recited act shall hereafter read as follows: &#8212;Sec. 2. That Silas M. Parker, of Van Zandt county, is hereby constituted an agent for Cynthia Ann Parker, formerly of Tarrant and now of Van Zandt county, and on his giving bond in the sum of four hundred dollars to the Chief Justice of Van Zandt county, con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ditioned for the faithful application of said pension to the support of said Cynthia Ann Parker, and for the support and education of her child, Topasannoh, and upon the production of the certificate of the Clerk of the County Court of Van Zandt county, to the Treasurer of the State of Texas, certifying that said agent has given bond as required by this act, the said Treasurer shall pay the said pension to the said agent or his order.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>January 8, 1862</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER LXIV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act for the relief of Charles H. Sims.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />missioner of the General Land Office be, and he is required to issue to Charles A. Sims a bounty land certificate for three hundred and twenty acres of land, for his services as an assistant quarter-master, from the 8th day of June to the 1st day of November, 1836, in the army of the Republic of <pb n="557" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="35" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw> Texas, which certificate may be located, surveyed and patented as other certificates, provided it shall appear that no certificate has ever issued to him for said services.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this act take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>January 9, 1862</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER LXV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act for the relief of Trueman B. Beck, William Custard, Abner Matthews and Abner H. Oook.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Comp<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />troller of Public Accounts is hereby required to credit the judgment rendered in the District Court of Travis county, on the 1st day of October, 1853, in favor of P. H. Bell, Governor of the State of Texas, against Trueman B. Beck, William Custard, Abner Matthews and Abner H. Cook, and the subsequent judgment of said Court thereon, reviving said judgment, with the sum of four hundred and ten dollars, paid by said Beck to the Sheriff of Travis county, on account of said judgment, prior to the first day of October, 1854, and interest from said date of payment, and said pay<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment shall be allowed as a credit to the defendants in said judgments, in the settle<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment thereof.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. This act shall take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>January 9, 1862</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER LXVI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to prohibit Stallions or Jacks from running at large in Dallas, Lamar and Bowie counties.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That it shall be unlawful for any citizen of Dallas county to allow any Stallion or Jack, over the age of two years, to run at large.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That any citizen of Dallas, Bowie and Lamar counties who may be an<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />noyed by any such animal shall have the right to take up, and in the presence of two or more respectable witnesses, castrate the same, provided that the person tak<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing up such animal, shall be required to give the owner thereof three days previous notice, if he is known to him.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That this act take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>January 9th, 1862</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER LXVII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act for the relief of the heirs of Lewis Powell, deceased.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />missioner of the General Land Office is authorized and required to issue to the heirs of Lewis Powell, deceased, for his having been killed at Goliad, as a married man under Col. Fannin, at the massacre of his men, an augmentation of two-thirds of a league and labor of land, provided they have not already received the same. The certificate to be issued under this act may be located, surveyed and patented as other like certificates for land.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>January 9, 1862</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<pb n="558" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="36" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER LXVIII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to validate certain certificates for land therein named.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the fol<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lowing named land certificates be, and they are hereby declared as legal and valid as though all the requisitions of the law had been fully complied with, to wit:</p>
<p>The unconditional headlight certificate No. 21 class 3, for 320 acres of land issued to the heirs of Pleasant M. Miller, by the Board of Land Commissioners of Milam county, on the 3d day of July, 1843.</p>
<p>The unconditional headright certificate No. 142, class 2, for 640 acres of land issued by the Board of Land Commissioners of Liberty county to Theophilus Wells on the 19th day of February, 1849.</p>
<p>The headright certificate for 320 acres, No. 91, issued by the District Court of Refugio county, on the 27th day of May, 1858, to the heirs of James Callan, and the headright certificate for 640 acres No. 92, issued by the District Court of Refugio county on the 25th day of May, 1859, to the heirs of Wm. R. Pay.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this act take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>January 9, 1862</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER LXIX.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act for the relief of Joseph P. Sneed assignee of Thomas Grubbs.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />missioner of the General Land Office be, and he is hereby required to issue to Joseph P Sneed, assignee of Thomas Grubbs, a headlight certificate for one-third of a league of land, which may be located and patented as other certificates, provided Thomas Grubbs has not heretofore received the same.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>January 9, 1862</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER LXX.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act authorizing and requiring the Commissioner of the General Land Office to issue to Archibald Hotchkiss, a certificate for one league of land, in right of, and as the assignee of the claim that Albert Emanuel had to a league of land as his Headlight.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />missioner of the General Land Office, be, and he is hereby authorized and required to issue to Archibald Hotchkiss, a certificate for one league of land, in right of, and as the assignee of the claim that Albert Emanuel had to a league of land as his Head<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />right.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this act take effect and be in force from,and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>January 9, 1862</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER LXXI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act for the relief of Robert H. Jackson.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />missioner of the General Land Office, be and he is hereby authorized and required to issue to Robert H. Jackson, a certificate for six hundred and <pb n="559" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="37" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw> forty acres of land, which may be located and patented as other genuine land cer<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tificates.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>January 9, 1862</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER LXXII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act for the relief of George W. Glasscock, assignee of Mandrid Wood.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />missioner of the General Land Office, be and he is hereby authorized and required to issue to George W. Glasscock, a certificate for three hundred and sixty-nine acres of land, as the assignee of Mandrid Wood, which certificate shall be located, sur<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />veyed and patented, as other first class certificates, Provided no such certificate has heretofore issued.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>January 9th, 1862</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER LXXIII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act for the relief of George W. Morris.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Terns, That the Comp<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />troller audit the claim of George W. Morris, for $364 81-100 for services rendered on the Santa Fe expedition.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That the sum of $364 81-100 be and the same is hereby appropriated for the payment of the same out of any money in the Treasury not otherwise appro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />priated and that this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>January 9th, 1862</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER LXXIV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act for the relief of James P. Plummer.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted, by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />missioner of the General Land Office, be and he is hereby authorized and required to issue a land certificate for twelve hundred and eighty acres of land, to James P. Plummer, of Limestone county, which may be located and patented as other genu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ine certificates, Provided the said Plummer has not received a grant of land here<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tofore.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this tact take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>January 9th, 1862</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER LXXV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to authorize and require the Superintendent of the Lunatic Asylum to re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ceive Margaret Needham, a lunatic, and to make provision for the same.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Super<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />intendent of the Lunatic Asylum, be and he is hereby authorized and required to receive, for treatment, Margaret Needham, a Lunatic from Travis county.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That the Chief Justice of Travis county, or the County Court thereof, is hereby required to make the same provisions for her support and <pb n="560" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="38" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw> maintainance, as is required by law, in other cases as though no patient had been sent from Travis county.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That this act be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>January 10th, 1862</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER LXXVI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act authorizing Stephen W. Beasley to demand, receive and take charge of the monies, warrants, or other dues, to which F. M. Marshall, J. R. Bonner, and Wm. J. McCain, were entitled to at their death, by virtue of service rendered under Capt. S. J. Richardson, in the army of Texas.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That Stephen W. Beasley, be and he is hereby authorized to demand, receive and take charge of the monies, warrants, or other dues, to which F. M. Marshall, J. R. Bon<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ner, and William J. McCain, members of Capt. S. J. Richardson&#8217;s Company, are entitled to receive from the State, which said Marshall, Bonner, and McCain, died in the service of the Confederate States.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. It shall be the duty of the said Beasley, to deliver the said monies warrants, or other dues so received, to the parents of the deceased.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That this act be in force and take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>January 11th, 1862</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER LXXVII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to authorize and require the County Court of Colorado county to furnish the County Surveyor of said county, with Books of Record, and to provide for transcribing the Records of the Surveyor&#8217;s Office, of said county.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the County Court of Colorado county, be and is hereby authorized and required to furnish the County Surveyor of said county, with well bound books or book, for the purpose of transcribing the Records of the Surveyor&#8217;s Office of said county.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That it shall be the duty of said Surveyor to transcribe the Records of the Surveyor&#8217;s Office of said county, in such book or books, in a plain legible hand, and when so transcribed, they shall be carefully compared with the original Record, by the County Court and the Surveyor. When found to be truly and correctly transcribed, the Chief Justice, Clerk, and at least two of the County Commissioners, shall certify, under then official oath of office, at the conclusion of the Record, with the impress of the county seal affixed on the same page, to the correctness of the same, reciting the number of pages contained in said book, from one to the highest number; after which said transcribed Records shall have all the force and effect in law and equity as the original Records.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That the said Surveyor making such transcript, shall be entitled to the same compensation for said services as are allowed to Clerks of the County Court for similar services.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. That this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>January 10th, 1862</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<pb n="561" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="39" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER LXXVIII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to confirm Bounty Land Warrant, No. 1551, issued to Andrew Benner, for 240 acres.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That a certain certificate, No. 1551, issued for military services, to Andrew Benner, for two hundred and forty acres of Bounty land, by James S. Gillett, Adjutant General of the State of Texas, on the 21st day of March, A. D. 1854, be and the same is hereby legalized, approved, and confirmed; and that said certificate may be located, surveyed, and patented in the same manner, as it might, had it been duly presented to, registered and approved by the Commissioner of Claims, and all other requisites complied with in relation thereto.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>January 11, 1862</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER LXXIX.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act for the relief of the heirs of John White, deceased.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted, by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Comptroller be, and he is hereby authorized and required to draw his warrant on the Treasurer for one hundred and eighty dollars, in favor of the heirs of John White, deceased, for services performed by said White, as 1st Lieutenant in Cap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tain Joseph Daniel&#8217;s Company, from the 15th day of November, 1838, until the 15th February, 1839, in the army of the Republic of Texas, and that the Treasurer be required to pay the same out of the money appropriated for the payment of the second class Public Debt of Texas.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this act shall take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>January 11th, 1862</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER LXXX.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act for the relief of W. L. Chalmers.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Comptroller be and he is hereby required to audit and allow the claim of W. L. Chalmers, now on file in his office, for services rendered the State of Texas, as Regi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mental Quartermaster, on the staff of Col. M. T. Johnson, according to the provis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ions of the Act of 14th February, A. D., 1860, and said Comptroller is furthermore required to audit and allow the claim of W. L. Chalmers, for sixty days service, for adjusting the accounts of the mounted Regiment of Col. M. T. Johnson, after said Regiment had been mustered out of the service of the State, in accordance with the account now on file in the office of the Comptroller, for three hundred dollars, and to draw his warrant on the Treasurer for the amount audited under the pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />visions of this Act, in favor of W. L. Chalmers; and that the sum of thirteen hun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dred and ninety-one dollars and forty-four cents, is hereby appropriated out of any money in the Treasury, not otherwise appropriated, to pay the same.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>January 11th, 1862</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<pb n="562" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="40" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER LXXXI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act for the relief of Sampson &#38; Henricks and S. M. Swenson.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Commissioner of the General Land Office be, and he is hereby required to issue to Sampson &#38; Henricks, a certificate for twelve hundred and eighty acres of land, and to S. M. Swenson, a certificate for nine hundred and sixty acres, which may be located and surveyed upon any public domain subject to location. Said land cer<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tificates to be taken by the said Sampson &#38; Henricks, and S. M. Swenson, in full payment of their claims as assignees of William R. S. Rondeau, as Clerk of the State Department.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That this act take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>January 11th, 1862</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER LXXXII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to extend the provisions of An Act to provide for the incorporation of towns and cities, to the town of Sumpter, in Trinity comity.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted, by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the provisions of an act entitled an act to provide for the incorporation of towns and cities, be and the same are hereby extended to the town of Sumpter, in Trinity county.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this act take effect and be an force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>January 11th, 1862</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER LXXXIII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to authorize and require the Comptroller to audit and settle the accounts of Quartermasters appointed for the several camps of instruction, organized by order of the Governor; and to authorize said Quartermasters to pay over any money in their hands to the Chief Justices of the Counties contributing supplies to said camps, in proportion to their respective contributions.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Comptroller be and he is hereby authorized and required to audit and settle the accounts of the Quartermasters appointed for the several camps of instruction, or<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ganized under order of the Governor; and any money which may be in the hands of such Quartermasters, received in the way of contributions, or may arise from the sale of property or supplies contributed, shall be paid over to the Chief Justices of the counties from which contributions were received, respectively in proportion to the amount of contributions from the county, which money shall be applied to the benefit of the soldiers who may have gone from the county.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That upon the filing in the office of the Comptroller, the receipts of the Chief Justices for the full amount found in their hands, upon the settlement provided for in the preceding section, the Comptroller shall be au<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />thorized to cancel the bonds of said Quartermasters on file in his office.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. Be it further enacted, That this act shall take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>January 11th, 1862</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<pb n="563" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="41" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER LXXXIV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to incorporate the Aransas Salt Works Company.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That Pryor Lea, as Commissioner, is authorized to organize a Joint Stock Company for the purposes of making salt and preparing it for market, to be called the Aransas Salt Works Company, to have capital stock, in shares of one hundred dollars each, to any amount not exceeding one hundred thousand dollars; to have the ordinary rights of a corporation when so organized, and to continue for thirty years from the date of this act; Provided, the Company shall have made one hundred thousand bushels of salt, at the place to be named below, before the expiration of two years from the close of the present war between the Confederate States of America and the United States of America.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. The Company, for the purposes aforesaid, may use such premises as it may acquire the right to use, by contract with the Aransas Road Company, embraced within the rights of the latter Company, in and adjoining Aransas bay; and, after such acquisition, may continue to so use it, during the term aforesaid, without dependence on any future action of the Aransas Road Company.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. This act shall be in force from its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>January 11th, 1862</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER LXXXV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act for the relief of the heirs of George W. Wilson.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Commissioner of the General Land Office, be and he is hereby required to issue to the heirs of George W. Wilson, deceased, a certificate for one league and labor of land, it being the quantity to which the said George W. Wilson was entitled by virtue of his emigration into the late Republic, in 1835; Provided, said George W. Wilson, his heirs or assigns, have not already received the benefits of said certificate or land.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this act take effect land be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>January 11th, 1862</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER LXXXVI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act for the relief of the heirs of Charles Clark.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Commissioner of Claims, be and he is hereby authorized and required to issue a donation certificate for 640 acres, and a bounty certificate for 320 acres of land, to the heirs of Charles Clark; and that this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>January 11th, 1862</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER LXXXVII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>All Act for the relief of Robert R. Scott.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Terns, That the Commissioner of the General Land Office, be and he is hereby authorized and required to issue to Robert R. Scott, a bounty warrant for two hundred and forty acres of land, for services rendered in the army of the Republic of Texas; Provided, said certificate has not heretofore been issued.</p>
<pb n="564" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="42" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<p>Sec. 2. That this act be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>January 11th, 1862</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER LXXXVIII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to authorize James W. Flanigan and his associates to construct a Bridge across the Sabine River.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That James W. Flanigan and other persons whom he may choose to associate with him, be and they are hereby authorized to construct a bridge across the Sabine river, at any point he or they may select, in the counties of Rusk or Harrison, between a ferry on said river known as Walling&#8217;s ferry, and another known as Ramsdale&#8217;s ferry, where he or they may be the owner of the land on either side of said river; provided the owner or owners of the land on the opposite side of the river, from the land so owned by said Flanigan and his associates, consent to the building of said bridge, or provided said bridge be constructed on some public road crossing said river, and should said Flanigan and his associates construct said bridge at some place on said river other than where said river is crossed by a public road, where he or they may own the land on both sides of the river, or where they can get the con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sent of the owner or owners of the bank of said river, not owned by said Flanigan and his associates, they may then have the right of way to open a road from the same to the town of Marshall, in Harrison county; and also to the town of Hender<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />son, in the County of Rusk; and also through the county of Harrison, in the direc<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion of Shreveport, in the State of Louisiana; Provided that said bridge shall be so constructed as not to obstruct or hinder the navigation of said river, and should any of the owners of the land over which said road is to be opened object to the open<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing of the same, then said Flanigan and his associates may apply to the County Court of the county where such land lies, and may obtain an order of said Court, or<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dering him and his associates, to open said road; and in ordering said road to be opened, such County Court shall be governed by the laws providing for the laying off and opening new public roads through the different counties of this State.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That the rates of toll to be charged and collected by said Flanigan and his associates shall be fixed by the County Court of Rusk county, and the license tax shall be levied by the same court, provided that the said Flanigan and his as<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sociates shall not be required to pay a license tax in any but one county on said bridge.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That said Flanigan and his associates shall in all respects be governed by the laws of this State regulating roads, bridges and ferries, when the same shall not conflict with the provisions of this act.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. That said Flanigan and his associates shall have the right to the use of a sufficient quantity of timber for the construction of all causeways and bridges that may be necessary on the road mentioned in this act, to be taken from the lands adjacent to said road, for which they shall pay a reasonable compensation to be determined by agreement between the parties, or in case they cannot agree, then either party may have the value of said timber assessed by applying to the County Court of the county in which the land from which said timber shall be taken lies, and on such application it shall be the duty of such court to appoint five qualified voters of the precinct in which such timber is situated, whose duty it shall be to assess the value of such timber, and return such assessment to the next term of said County Court, and said Flanigan and his associates shall be held liable to pay such person the value of said timber fixed by such appraisers, and the same <pb n="565" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="43" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw> may be recovered by suit before any court having jurisdiction of the same, and the assessment so made shall be sufficient evidence before said conrt to authorize the rendition of judgment for the amount so assessed.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. That said parties shall commence the building of said bridge within one year from the passage of this act, and have the same completed within five years, and in case of failure thereof they shall forfeit all privileges granted by this act.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. That this act take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>January 11, 1862</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER LXXXIX.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to provide for the payment of Captain Milton Webb&#8217;s company of Mounted Volunteers.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Comptroller be authorized and required to settle with the officers and privates of Captain Milton Webb&#8217;s company of Mounted Volunteers, in the service of the State, from the 10th day of April, 1861, to the 15th day of June, 1861, under an ordinance of the Convention, passed 18th of March, 1861, and by order of Gov. Ed. Clark, and to regard all accounts for pay, transportation and subsistence, as if the said company had been regularly in the service of the State during said period.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this act be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>January 11, 1862</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XC.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act for the relief of the Texas and New Orleans Railroad Company.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. B it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the failure of the Texas and New Orleans Railroad Company to make its annual report to the Comptroller, of its operations for the year ending on the first day of October, 1861, shall not operate as a forfeiture of its charter, or any of its lights under the same, or any act supplementary thereto, or any general law regulating railroad companies, provided said report shall be made within sixty days from the passage of this act.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That any penalty which may have been incurred by said Company by such failure be, and the same is hereby remitted, provided said Railroad Company complies with the provisions of this act, and that this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>January 11, 1862</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XCI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to repeal an act entitled &#8220;An Act to authorize and require all forced sales of real estate and negroes, and sales of real estate or negroes, made by executions and administrators, in the county of Nueces, be made at the front door of the La Retama House in the city of Corpus Christi,&#8221; approved April 16th, 1861.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the above entitled act be, and the same is hereby repealed, and that this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>January 11, 1862</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<pb n="566" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="44" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XCII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act for the relief of F. A. Sherman.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Commissioner of the General Land Office be, and he is hereby authorized and required to issue to F. A. Sherman a duplicate land warrant for 1280 acres of land in lieu of the original warrant for said quantity of land, provided it shall appear that said original warrant has not been returned to the General Land Office or a duplicate issued for the same.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this act take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>January 11, 1862</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XCIII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act authorizing Horace Cone to draw the mileage and per diem of the late Hon. John C. Walker.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That Horace Cone be, and he is hereby authorized to draw the mileage and per diem due from the State of Texas to the late Hon. Jno. C. Walker.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>January 11, 1862</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XCIV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act for the relief of John P. Gill.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Commissioner of the General Land Office be, and he is hereby authorized and required to issue to Jno. P. Gill a donation warrant for 640 acres of land, in con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sideration of his having entered Bexar between the 5th and 10th of December, 1835, and having participated in the reduction of the same; in lieu of donation warrant No.,&#8212;for the same service, which has been lost.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this act take effect from its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>January 11, 1862</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XCV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act for the relief of the heirs of James H. Denson.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Commissioner of the General Land Office be, and he is hereby authorized and required to issue to the heirs of James H. Denson a certificate for one third of a league of land which certificate may be located and patented as other-genuine cer<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tificates, provided the said Denson has not heretofore received a certificate for a third of a league headright, and that this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>January 11, 1862</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XCVI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act for the relief of Mrs. Ann E. Baxter and Mrs. Martha Tramel.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Commisioner of the General Land Office be, and he is hereby authorized <pb n="567" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="45" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw> and required to issue to Mrs. Ann E. Baxter, widow of Geo. G. Baxter, a certificate for one hundred and fifty-six acres of land, situated in the county of Smith, and de<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />scribed in survey and field notes, No. 1113, made by R. E. Curlee, county surveyor of Smith county, upon the application of said Geo. G. Baxter, under the provisions of &#8220;an act to authorize the sale of the public domain,&#8221; approved February 1st, 1860; provided that said Ann E. Baxter shall pay into the General Land Office fifty cents per acre for said 156 acres of land, with other fees, within the period required by the above recited act.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That Mrs. Martha Tramel be, and she is hereby entitled to the same amount of land in the county of Angelina, by complying with the provisions of the above entitled act.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That this act be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>January 11, 1862</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XCVII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to incorporate the Texas Lead Mine Company.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted, by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That Irby Morgan, John P. White, Jesse Arledge and Geo. W. White, and their asso<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ciates and successors, are hereby created and declared a body corporate and politic, by the name and style of the &#8220;Texas Lead Mine Company,&#8221; and by that name they their associates, and successors shall be capable of suing and being sued, plead and be impleaded, in all the courts of this State, and shall be capable in law of contract<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing and being contracted with, and acquiring by purchase, donation or otherwise, property, real, personal and mixed, holding and convoying the same as the said corporation may think proper.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That the State of Texas doth hereby relinquish to the said Corporation all the right, title and claim which the said State of Texas has in and to all minerals that may be found on any patented land which said Company may select and pur<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />chase for the manufacture of lead, provided the amount does not exceed twelve hundred and eighty acres, and provided further, that the manufacture of lead by said Company shall be commenced within twelve months from the passage of this act.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That the charter of said Company shall remain in force for twenty years, and that this act be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>January 11, 1862</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XCVIII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act for the relief of James L. Foster.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Commissioner of the General Land Office be, and he is hereby authorized to issue a duplicate unconditional land certificate of 640 acres to James L. Foster, by virtue of his conditional land certificate No. 236, for 640 acres now, on file in the General Land Office.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this act take effect from its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>January 11, 1862</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<pb n="568" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="46" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XCIX.</head>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">An Act for the relief of Jarman Carter.</head>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Commissioner of the General Land Office be, and he is hereby required to issue a patent to Jarman Carter for his pre-emption claim for 320 acres of land upon a return of the field notes, or a certified copy thereof from the books of the county surveyor of Fannin county, with due proof of his having complied with all the laws under which said pre-emption was taken, and the payment to the General Land Office of the sum of twenty dollars and the usual patent fees, and provided further, that upon examination said claim shall be found, to be free of conflict.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. This act shall not be construed to interfere with vested rights.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. This act be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>January 11, 1862</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER C.</head>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">An Act for the relief of Wm. B. Green.</head>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Commissioner of the General Land Office be, and he is hereby authorized and required to issue to Wm. B. Green, of Bastrop county, a certificate for thirty-three hundred and twenty-five acres of land, which certificate when issued shall be located, surveyed and patented as other first class certificates, provided that no such cer<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tificate has heretofore issued to the said Green.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this act take effect from its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>January 11, 1862</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER CI.</head>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">An Act to amend an act entitled &#8220;An Act to ascertain and adjudicate certain legal claims for land against the State, situated between the Nueces and Rio Grande rivers,&#8221; approved February 11th, 1860.</head>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the state of Texas, That the eleventh section of the above recited act shall read as follows, viz: this act shall continue in force until the 11th day of February. A. D., 1865, and no longer.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Tihis act shall be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>January 11, 1862</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER CII.</head>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">An Act to legalize the acts of Alexander Birdsong, Notary Public in and for Panola county.</head>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That all the official acts of Alexander Birdsong, as Notary Public in and for the county of Panola be, and the same are hereby legalized and made of full force and validity.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this act be in force and take effect from and after itsp assage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>January 11, 1862</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<pb n="569" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="47" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER CIII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act supplementary to an &#8220;An Act to consolidate in one act and to amend the several acts incorporating the city of Houston, in Harris county,&#8221; approved Janu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ary 8th, 1862.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the 21st section of the said act shall read as follows: That the Mayor and Recorder are hereby vested with all the powers and jurisdiction, civil and criminal, within the limits of said corporation which may by law be exercised by Justices of the Peace under the laws of this State, and in prosecutions, trials and proceedings had before them under this act, and the by-laws and ordinances of said corporation, they shall be governed by the laws regulating the proceedings in Justices Courts in force at the time, and shall be entitled to the same fees that Justices of the Peace are then allowed for similar service.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That the 23d section of the said act shall read as follows: That it shall be the duty of the Mayor and Council to cause the Secretary and Treasurer of the said corporation to publish on the first Monday of January in each year an ac<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />curate, detailed and just statement of the treasury, of the receipts and expenditures, and condition of the Terasury of said body politic, and publish the same in at least one of the gazettes printed in Houston; the said statement, before it is printed, shall be carried by the Treasurer aforesaid before some Judge or Justice of the Peace, before whom he shall testify on oath that the same is a faithful and correct statement.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That this act shall take effect and be in force from and after the first day of February, 1862.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>January 11, 1862</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER CIV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act for the relief of John Henderson.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Commissioner of the General Land Office be, and he is hereby required to issue to John Henderson, of San Patricio county, a headright certificate for twelve hundred and eighty (1280) acres of land, to be located upon any vacant public land in like manner as other land certificates, provided the said John Henderson has never received any land by virtue of his emigration to the Republic of Texas.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this act be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>January 14, 1862</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER CV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to authorize the Superintendent to receive Minerva J. Fannin into the Lunatic Asylum, and to contract with her guardian for her support and maintenance.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Superintendent of the Lunatic Asylum be, and he is hereby authorized and re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />quired to contract with Thos. F. McKinney, as guardian of Minerva J. Fannin, to receive and care for her in said Asylum, during the term of her natural life, pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vided that said McKinney shall provide and secure to said Asylum an annuity fully sufficient, in the judgment of the Superintendent, to support and maintain said Minerva in said Asylum during her life free from charge to the State.</p>
<pb n="570" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="48" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<p>Sec. 2. That said McKinney be authorized to transfer to said Asylum any part of the estate of said Minerva, descended to her from her parents, which may be necessary to secure such sum as is requisite to her support and maintenance in said Asylum.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>Janmary 14, 1862</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER CVI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act for the relief of Dillard Cooper.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Whereas, Dillard Cooper was one among the fortunate few who escaped death from the Mexicans at Fannin&#8217;s massacre at Goliad, in the revolution of 1836, and he was among the gallant defenders of Texas in her early revolutionary struggle, and whereas, he is now old, infirm, deceased and destitute of the means of subsistence, therefore,</p>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature oi the State of Texas, That said Dillard Cooper be allowed the sum of two hundred dollars annually to be paid in treasury warrants, one-half of said amount to be paid on the first day of February and the other half on the first day of August in each year, and that the Comptroller is hereby authorized to draw his draft for said amount on the Treasury, payable on the days above specified and each and every year during the natural life of said Cooper.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>January 13, 1862</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER CVII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to authorize John C. Crawford to use the water of the Leona river for purposes of irrigation.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That John C. Crawford be, and he is hereby authorized to take from the Leona river, in or near the vicinity of the Montezuma Mills, in the county of Uvalde, so much water as he may need for the purpose of irrigation, and the same to conduct by any neces<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sary ditch or ditches to such lands as he may wish to cultivate, and to make and construct such dam or dams in and across said river and such ditches, water-gates and other works as may be necessary for such purposes of irrigation.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. The said Crawford shall have a right of way and privilege of using the soil to make, construct and keep in order the said dams, ditches, water-gates and other works from and including the point where it may be necessary to take the water from said river to the point or points where the said ditch or ditches may terminate; provided that if it be necessary to construct such dams, ditches, water<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />gates and other works, or if any of them, upon or over the land of any other person or persons who may not have consented thereto, then the said Crawford shall pay to said person or persons for such right of way and privilege, such damages as may be awarded to him, her or them by the County Court of said county of Uvalde, within one year after the construction of such works upon his, her or their lands.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That this act take effect from its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>January 14, 1862</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<pb n="571" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="49" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER CVIII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act for the relief of Gregorie Simon.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the certificate No. 105, for three hundred and twenty acres of land, issued by the Commissioner of Castro&#8217;s Colony, on the 24th of August, A. D., 1854, to the heirs of Gregorio Simon be, and the same is hereby canceled, and upon the return of the said certificate to the proper office, the Commissioner of the General Land Office be, and he is hereby authorized and required to issue to the said Simon a certificate for three hundred and twenty acres of land, said certificate to be located surveyed and patented as other certificates of like character.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this act take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>January 13, 1862</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER CIX.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to authorize the County Court of Montague county to have the records of the District Court of said county transcribed.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the County Court of the county of Montague be, and they are hereby authorized to have all the records of the District Court of said county transcribed in well bound boohs, to be procured by them for that purpose; and be it further enacted that said records, when so transcribed, shall be of the same force and effect as if it had been made in said books originally.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. This act shall take effect from the date of its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>January 13, 1862</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER CX.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act for the relief of Philander Priestly.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Commissioner of the General Land Office be, and he is hereby required to issue to Philander Priestly an augmentation certificate for three hundred and sixty-nine acres of land, to be surveyed and patented on any unappropriated public domain, and that this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>January 13, 1862</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER CXI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to amend &#8220;An Act to incorporate the city of Austin,&#8221; approved February 9th, 1856.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature or the State of Texas, That the 7th section of said act be so amended as to read as follows, to wit: Section 7th. That the Mayor and City Council shall have power within the city by ordinance,</p>
<p>1st. To levy and collect taxes not exceeding one-twelfth of one per centum upon all property made taxable by law for State and county purposes.</p>
<p>2d. To borrow money on the credit of the city, provided the debt of the city from money so borrowed shall not exceed $5,000.</p>
<pb n="572" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="50" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<p>3d. To appropriate money and provide for the payment of the debt and expenses of the city.</p>
<p>4th. To make regulations to prevent the introduction of cantagious diseases into the city.</p>
<p>5th. To establish hospitals, and make regulations for the government thereof.</p>
<p>6th. To make regulations to secure the general health of the inhabitants and to prevent and remove nuisances.</p>
<p>7th. To provide the city with water and to erect hydrants, fire-plugs and pumps in the streets, within or beyond the limits of the city, for the convenience of the inhabitants of the city and environs.</p>
<p>8th. To open, alter, abolish, widen, extend, establish, grade, pave or otherwise improve, clean and keep in repair streets, lanes, avenues or alleys.</p>
<p>9th. To establish and keep in repair bridges, culverts and sewers, and regulate the use of the same; to establish, alter and change the channel of water courses and to wall them up and cover them over.</p>
<p>10th. To provide for the lighting of the streets and erecting lamps thereon.</p>
<p>11th. To establish, support and regulate night watch and patrols.</p>
<p>12th. To erect market houses, establish markets and market places, and to pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vide for the government and regulation thereof.</p>
<p>13th. To provide for the erection of all needful buildings for the use of the city.</p>
<p>14th. To provide for the enclosing, improving and regulating of all public grounds belonging to the city.</p>
<p>15th. To license, tax and regulate auctions, grocers, merchants, retailers and tav<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />erns, and to license, tax, regulate and suppress, by ordinances, hawkers, peddlers, brokers, pawn-brokers, money-changers and bakeries.</p>
<p>16th. To license, tax and regulate hackney carriages, omnibusses, wagons, carts and drays, and fix the rates to be charged for carriage of persons and of wagonage, cartage and drayage of property.</p>
<p>17th. To license and regulate porters and fix the rate of porterage.</p>
<p>18th. To license, tax and regulate and suppress theatrical and other exhibitions, shows and amusements.</p>
<p>19th. To license, tax, regulate billiard tables, tippling houses, and dram shops, and to suppress gaming and gambling houses and other disorderly houses, and to suppress bawdy houses.</p>
<p>20th. To provide for the prevention and extinguishment of fires, and organize and establish fire companies; also to regulate, restrain and prohibit the erection of wooden buildings in any part of the city; to regulate and prevent the carrying on of manufactories dangerous in causing or producing fires; to appoint fire wardens and property guards, with power to remove and keep away from the vicinity of any fire all idle or suspicious persons lurking near the same, and to compel any person or persons present to aid in extinguishing such fire, or in the preservation of prop<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />erty exposed to the danger of the same, and in preventing goods from being pur<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />loined thereat, and with such other powers and duties as may be prescribed by ordi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />nance to compel the owners of houses and other buildings to have scutttles upon the roof of any such houses and buildings, and stairs and ladders leading to the same.</p>
<p>21st. To regulate and order the cleaning of chimnies and to fix the fees thereof.</p>
<p>22d. To regulate the storage of gunpowder, tar, pitch, rosin, hemp, cotton and all other combustible materials, and the use of lights and candles in all stables, shops and other places; to remove and prevent the construction of any fire-place, hearth, chimney, stoves, ovens, boilers, kettles or apparatus used <pb n="573" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="51" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw> in any houses, building, manufactory or business which may be dangerous in causing or promoting fires; to direct the safe construction of deposits for ashes, and severally to enter into, or appoint one or more officers at reasonable times, to enter into and examine all dwelling buses, lots, yards, enclosures, buildings of every description, in order to discover if any of them are in a dangerous state, and to cause such as may be dangerous to be put in safe and secure condition.</p>
<p>23d. To regulate and prescribe the manner and order the building of partition and of parapet walls and of partition fences.</p>
<p>24th. To establish standard weights and measures, and to regulate the weights and measures to be used in the city in all cases not otherwise provided by law.</p>
<p>25th. To provide for the inspection and measuring of lumber and other building material.</p>
<p>26th. To provide for the inspection and weighing of hay, the measuring of char<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />coal, firewood and all other fuel to be used in the city.</p>
<p>27th. To regulate the inspection of butter, lard and other provisions; to regulate the vending of meat, poultry and vegetables, to restrain and punish the forestalling of poultry, butter, eggs and fruit, and to suppress hucksters.</p>
<p>28th. To regulate the weight, quality and price of bread to be sold and used in the city.</p>
<p>29th. To regulate the size of brick made and sold in the city.</p>
<p>30th. To provide for the taking of an enumeration of the inhabitants of the city.</p>
<p>31st. To provide for the removal from office any person holding an office created by this act, or by ordinance, not otherwise provided for.</p>
<p>32d. To provide for the appointment of all officers, servants and agents of the corporation, not otherwise provided for.</p>
<p>33d. To fix the compensation of city officers not otherwise provided for, and regulate the fees of all jurors, witnesses and others for services rendered under this act or any ordinance.</p>
<p>34th. To regulate the police of the city, to impose fines, forfeitures and penalties for the breach of any ordinance, and provide for the recovery and appropriating such fines and forfeitures and the enforcement of such penalties, provided that no fine shall exceed $100, and imprisonment not exceeding fifteen days for any one offence.</p>
<p>35th. To erect a work-house and house of correction, and provide for the regula<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion and government thereof.</p>
<p>36th. To regulate and license all ferries within the limits of the city.</p>
<p>37th. To levy and collect a poll tax not exceeding fifty cents upon every free white male person over 21 years of age, who shall have resided six months within the city.</p>
<p>38th. To remove all obstructions from the sidewalks and to provide for the con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />struction and repair of all sidewalks and curbstones, and for the cleaning of the same, and the gutters, at the expense of the owner of the ground fronting thereon.</p>
<p>39th. To prevent and restrain any riot, rout, noise disturbance or disorderly assemblage in any street, house or place in the city.</p>
<p>40th. To prevent and remove all encroachments in and upon all streets, lanes, avenues and alleys established by law or ordinance.</p>
<p>41st. To exercise complete and perfect control over the common and all the property belonging to the city, real and personal, whether lying within or beyond the limits of the corporation created by this act, and the same to lease, sell, transfer and dispose of, either absolute by or with limitation, to any person or persons whatsoever, and generally to make such rules, regulations. <pb n="574" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="52" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw> by-laws and ordinancss for the purpose of maintaining the peace, good government and order of the city of Austin, and the trade, commerce and manufacture thereof as the City Council may deem expedient, not repugnant to the laws and constitu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion of this State, and also to enforce the observance therof by inflicting penalties upon any inhabitant thereof, or other person or persons for the violation of any ordinance not exceeding one hundred dollars for any offence, recoverable with costs in any action of debt, by and in the name of the city of Austin for the use of the city, before any court having cognizance of the same.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted that the 9th section of said act be so amended as to read as follows:</p>
<p>The chief executive officer of the city shall be the Mayor, who shall be elected annually by the qualified electors of the city, who shall hold the office for one year; whose salary shall be fixed by the Aldermen of the city, but which shall not in any event succeed the sum of two hundred and fifty dollars and fees of office.</p>
<p>No person shall be Mayor who, at the time of his election, is not possessed of the qualifications required from an Alderman, or who holds any lucrative office under authority of the Confederate States.</p>
<p>When two or more persons shall have an equal number of votes for the office of Mayor, the City Council shall order a new election. Whenever an election for Mayor shall be contested, the City Council shall determine the same by vote.</p>
<p>Whenever any vacancy shall happen in the office of Mayor, it shall be filled by election in such manner as shall be provided for by ordinance. The Mayor may be removed from office for any misdemeanor, by a majority of two-thirds of the City Council.</p>
<p>The Mayor shall have power to nominate, and by and through the consent of the Board of Aldermen, to appoint all city officers, not ordered by this act to be other<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />wise appointed: he shall take care that the laws of the State, and the ordinances of the city are duly enforced, respected and observed within the city; he may remit fines, forfeitures and penalties, accruing from or imposed for the violation of any ordinance of the city; he may fill all vacancies which may occur in any elective office other than that of Alderman until the same be filled by election, and in any other office until the end of the session of the Board of Aldermen, which shall not happen after the vacancy shall have accrued; he shall, from time to time, give to the City Council information relative to the state of the city, and shall recommend to their consideration such measures as he shall deem expedient for the advantage of the city.</p>
<p>The Mayor may call special sessions of the City Council by notice served on them. Whenever a special session of the City Council shall have been called by the Mayor, he shall state to them, when assembled, the cause for which they have been con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vened.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>January 13, 1862</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER CXII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act for the relief of Elias Cassels.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Comptroller issue to Elias Cassels, as assignee, a duplicate of a warrant on the Treasury, numbered forty-two, issued in favor of Jack Waterhouse, for forty-three dollars and eighty-three cents, on condition that said Cassels <pb n="575" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="53" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw> file a bond, with good security, in double the amount of said warrant with said Comptroller, conditioned that he will indemnify the State in case the first warrant shall be paid.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. This act shall be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>January 14, 1862</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER CXIII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>All Act for the relief of certain persons hereinafter named.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />missioner of the General Land Office be authorized and required to issue land cer<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tificates to the following named persons for the respective quantities of land herein<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />after named to wit: To John R. Cannon for 320 acres, headright; to the heirs of John W. Glenn, for 320 acres, headright; to P. W. Birmingham, for 320 acres, bounty; to Samuel Smith, for 320 acres, bounty; to J. B. Shade, for 320 acres, bounty; to the heirs of Joseph Shepherd, for 320 acres, bounty, and for 640 acres donation land; and a duplicate donation warrant for 640 acres of land to H. H. Edwards, in lieu of donation warrant No. 1192, for 640 acres, issued on the 8th day of January, 1842, by George W. Hockley, Secretary of War of the late Republic of Texas.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>January 13, 1862</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER CXIV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act for the relief of Levi T. Lawler.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Comptroller and Commissioner of Claims of the State of Texas be, and are hereby required to audit the amount of sixty-seven dollars, and fifty cents, the amount due Levi T. Lawler for services rendered by him in the army of the Republic of Texas in the year 1842, on the Somerville expedition.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. This act shall take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>January 13, 1862</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER CXV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to incorporate the Fort Bend Manufacturing Company.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That James S. Sullivan, William Saunders and C. W. Buckley, and their associates and succes<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sors be, and they are hereby created a body corporate and politic by the name of the &#8220;Fort Bend Manufacturing Company,&#8221; and by that name may sue and be sued, plead and be impleaded, contract and be contracted with, as a natural person in law, and may have a seal which may be altered, changed or broken at pleasure, and the stockholders of said Company may make all by-laws they may deem necessary for the government of the affairs thereof, not inconsistent with the Constitution and laws of this State.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Said Company shall have the power to erect and maintain, in the county of Fort Bend, all buildings, machinery, &#38;c., necessary for the manu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />facture of all fabrics made in whole or in part of wool, cotton, silk, hemp or <pb n="576" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="54" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw> fiax, and also articles made of wood, iron, steel, or other metal, or material intended for the use and consumption of the people of Texas or elsewhere.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. The capital stock of said Company shall not exceed two hundred thousand dollars, to be divided into shares of one hundred dollars each, land each share shall entitle the holder to one vote for Directors or on any other question submitted to the stockholders, and the management of the affairs of said Company shall be con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ducted by a President and Board of Directors of not less than three nor more than five, to be elected by the stockholders, whose term of office shall be one year, and each of whom shall be the owner of not less than ten shares of the stock of said Company.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>January 13, 1862</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
</div2>
<pb n="577" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="55" />
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">JOINT RESOLUTIONS.</head>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER I. JOINT RESOLUTION.</head>
<p>Whereas, Mrs. Price, the wife of Gen. Sterling Price, of Missouri, having sought safety in Texas, from the horrors of the war now raging in Missouri, therefore, Resolved by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the people of Texas, through their representatives, welcome Mrs. Price to their State and tender to her the hospitalities of the same as a token of respect to her and admiration for her gallant husband, for the brilliant victories he has achieved at the head of the army of Missouri, in the defence of the southern cause, and that the Governor be requested to furnish Mrs. Price with a copy of this resolution.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>November 27, 1861</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER II. JOINT RESOLUTION.</head>
<p>Whereas, Mrs. David Bouldin, wife of Capt. David Bouldin of Missouri, having fled the State of Missouri to our State, for safety from the abolition Hessians of the North, and whereas she being the lady who carried the news of the position and design of the Federal troops, when about to attack Gen. Price, and whereas we believe it was a patriotic desire and love for the prosperity of our cause that prompted the noble act, and whereas if it had not been for the timely interference of the said Mrs. Bouldin in our behalf the result of the battle at Springfield might have been disastrous, therefore,</p>
<p>Be it resolved by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That we, the representa<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tives of the people of Texas, hereby tender to Mrs. Bouldin our sincere thanks for the patriotic part she acted for the furtherance of our cause in Missouri, and wel<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />come her to the State of Texas, and tender her the hospitalities of the same.</p>
<p>Resolved 2d, That the Governor furnish Mrs. Bouldin with a copy of this pre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />amble and resolution.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>December 20, 1861</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
<pb n="578" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="56" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER III.</head>
<opener>
<salute>Joint Resolution concerning Col. John S. Ford and his late command on the Rio Grande.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it resolved by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That in the opinion of this body Col. John S. Lord has entitled himself to the thanks of the peo<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ple of Texas, for the skill, prudence and moderation with which he has executed the important, arduous and embarrasing duties that devolved upon him as late com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mander of the forces of the State of Texas on the Rio Grande frontier, at a most try<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing period in our history as a State, and furthermore that the officers and men of his late command in the State service, by their gallant and soldierly bearing and patience under the many trying circumstances surrounding them, have entitled them<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />selves to the thanks of the people of the State.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That as an evidence of our approval of the conduct of Col. John S. Ford as such commander, the Governor be requested to furnish him a copy of these resolu$$tions.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>January 6, 1862</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER IV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>Joint Resolution requiring the Comptroller to receive and audit the claims accruing for three months&#8217; service of Capt. Jno. W. Sansom&#8217;s company of &#8220;Kerr County Mounted Volunteers,&#8221; on the frontier.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Be it resolved by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Comptroller of Public Accounts be, and he is hereby instructed to receive and audit as a valid debt, the claims accruing for three months&#8217; frontier service of Captain Jno. W. Sansom&#8217;s company of &#8220;Kerr County Mounted Volunteers,&#8221; composed of thirty-six men, rank and file; said service Commencing August 31st, 1859, as per muster roll and papers filed in the Adjutant General&#8217;s office.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Passed <date>January 13, 1862</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER V.</head>
<opener>
<salute>Joint Resolution requiring the Comptroller to pay to Nat M. Burford the balance due him for his salary.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Comp<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />troller be, and he is hereby directed to audit and draw his warrant on the Treas<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />urer for the claim of Nat M. Burford, Judge of the 16th Judicial District, for the balance due him on his salary, notwithstanding the notice of his failing to hold his Courts.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>January 9, 1862</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER VI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>Joint Resolution commendatory of the conduct of Lieut Colonel John R. Baylor and the officers and men under him.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it resolved by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That Lieut. Col. John R. Baylor is entitled to the praise and commendation of this Legislature for his gallant and patriotic Bourse in assuming the responsibility and taking possession of the territory of Arizona, with all the forts, cannon <pb n="579" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="57" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw> and seven hundred armed Federalists, and that his officers and men are entitled to equal commendation for their gallantry in sustaining him.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That the Governor be requested to furnish Lieut. Col. Baylor with a oopy of this resolution.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>January 11, 1862</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER VII. JOINT RESOLUTION.</head>
<p>Whereas, The State of Louisiana having caused to be placed in order, and delivered to the State of Texas, the two guns known in the history of Texas as the &#8220;Twin Sisters,&#8221; as a token of friendship towards this State, and desiring to return our acknowledgment of such a gift, and to express our friendship and kind feelings towards our sister State:</p>
<p>Section 1. Be it resolved by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That we re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ceive the valuable and useful gift to Texas, and acknowledge our obligations to our sister State for the friendship and generosity so manifested by the donation of the guns that are so famous in the history of Texas.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further resolved, That we assure our sister State that it is our desire to cultivate and perpetuate the friendly relations that now exist between this State and the State of Louisiana, and should an occasion occur in which it will become necessary for Texas to use the &#8220;Twin Sisters,&#8221; in defence of the right of Louisiana, Texas, or any other State in the Confederacy, and to repel the invasion of a despot, the sons of Texas will be found ready to man them, and to remain by them until the invaders of our common country shall be driven from our soil.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. Be it further resolved, Thaat the Governor of the State of Texas be, and he is hereby requested to cause a copy of these resolutions to be transmitted to the Governor of the State of Louisiana.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>January 13, 1862</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
</div2>
<pb n="580" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="58" />
<pb n="581" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="59" />
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">INDEX TO SPECIAL LAWS.</head>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">A</head>
<p>Ainsworth, A. M. for relief of....................................... <ref>24</ref></p>
<p>Allcorn, Elisha. for relief of.......................................... <ref>6</ref></p>
<p>Angelina County Court to allow the Sheriff pay in certain cases......................... <ref>21</ref></p>
<p>Angelina River. S. Wolf authorized to bridge........................... <ref>17</ref></p>
<p>Aransas Salt Work Co. act of incorporation............................... <ref>41</ref></p>
<p>Austin, City of. act of incorporation amended................................... <ref>49</ref></p>
<p>Austin H. and L. Fire Company. act of incorporation.................................... <ref>8</ref></p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">B</head>
<p>Baylor, John R. Joint Resolution of thanks to him and his men...................... <ref>56</ref></p>
<p>Baxter, Mrs. Ann E. for the relief of.................................................... <ref>44</ref></p>
<p>Beasley, S. W. to take charge of certain monies, etc., belonging to deceased members of Captain Richardson&#8217;s Company................................ <ref>38</ref></p>
<p>Beck, Truman B. for the relief of................................................ <ref>35</ref></p>
<p>Benner, Andrew. land warrant formerly issued him confirmed......................... <ref>39</ref></p>
<p>Birdsong, Alexander. acts of as Notary Public legalized....................... <ref>46</ref></p>
<p>Birmingham, P. W. for the relief of...................................</p>
<p>Brennen, Mrs. Martha. for the relief of............................................<ref>21</ref></p>
<p>Brown, County Court. to allow the Sheriff extra pay in certain cases....................... <ref>21</ref></p>
<p>Bradshaw, J. for the relief of................................................... <ref>23</ref></p>
<p>Boulding, Mrs. David. Joint Resolution of thanks to....................................... <ref>55</ref></p>
<p>Bowie County. see &#8220;counties.&#8221;</p>
<p>Burford, Nat M. balance on salary to be paid..................................... <ref>56</ref></p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">C</head>
<p>Callan, James. for the relief of the heirs of....................... <ref>36</ref></p>
<pb n="582" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="60" /><fw type="header" place="top">Index.</fw>
<p>Cantwell, E. G. for the relief of.................................. <ref>7</ref></p>
<p>Garter, Jarman. for the relief of.................................. <ref>46</ref></p>
<p>Gassels, Elias. for the relief of................................. <ref>52</ref></p>
<p>Cannon, John K. for the relief of........................................ <ref>53</ref></p>
<p>Cameron County. authorizing the payment of certain audited county scrip........... <ref>19</ref></p>
<p>Chalmers, W. L. for the relief of........................................... <ref>39</ref></p>
<p>Cherokee County. see &#8220;counties.&#8221;</p>
<p>Clark, Charles. for the relief of the heirs of........................................... <ref>41</ref></p>
<p>Clay County. attached to Montague for judicial purposes........................ <ref>22</ref></p>
<p>Cone, Horace. to draw the mileage and per diem of the Hon. John C. Walker............... <ref>44</ref></p>
<p>Cooper, Dillard. for the relief of............................................. <ref>48</ref></p>
<p>Colorado County. see &#8220;counties.&#8221;</p>
<p>Collin County. see &#8220;counties.&#8221;</p>
<p>Cook, A. H. for the relief of............................................... <ref>27</ref>-<ref>35</ref></p>
<p>Comptroller. authorized to issue duplicate Treasury Warrants Nos. 3587 and 17,320. <ref>24</ref></p>
<p>to audit and settle the accounts of certain Quartermasters............... <ref>40</ref></p>
<p>to audit the claims of John W. Sansom&#39;s Company..................... <ref>56</ref></p>
<p>to pay N. M. Buford balance due him on salary..................... <ref>55</ref></p>
<p>Counties. Bowie and Lamar county, stallions prevented from running at large in. <ref>35</ref></p>
<p>Collin county, amending the act authorizing the County Court to levy a special tax to build a court house..................... <ref>22</ref></p>
<p>Cherokee county, sale of intoxicating liquors, prohibited within one mile of Alto............................................ <ref>6</ref></p>
<p>Clay county, attached to Montague for judicial purposes............ <ref>22</ref></p>
<p>Colorado, County Court to furnish Surveyor books to transcribe his records............................................... <ref>38</ref></p>
<p>Dallas county, stallions prohibited from running at large therein..... <ref>35</ref></p>
<p>Kaufman and Henderson counties, act changing their boundaries re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pealed................................................. <ref>23</ref></p>
<p>Montague county to have the records of the District Court transcribed <ref>49</ref></p>
<p>Nueces county, act authorizing the levying of a special tax repealed... <ref>10</ref></p>
<p>Nueces county, act requiring forced sales to be made before the Re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tama House repealed............................ <ref>43</ref></p>
<p>Newton county, legalizing the action of certain officers therein......... <ref>4</ref></p>
<p>Tarrant county, sale of intoxicating liquors prohibited within 4&#189; miles of the court house......................................... <ref>11</ref></p>
<p>Wichita county attached to Montague for judicial purposes........... <ref>22</ref></p>
<p>Cox, Noah. for the relief of....................................... <ref>4</ref></p>
<pb n="583" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="61" /><fw type="header" place="top">Index.</fw>
<p>Crawford, John C. authorized to use the waters of the Leona river for irrigation......... <ref>48</ref></p>
<p>Custard, William. for the relief of........................................... <ref>35</ref></p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">D</head>
<p>Dallas Bridge Company. act of incorporation amended...................................... <ref>8</ref></p>
<p>Dallas Agricultural and Mechanical Association. act of incorporation........................................ <ref>25</ref></p>
<p>Dallas County. see &#8220;counties.&#8221;</p>
<p>Dent, J. P. and F. W. authorized to adopt a child........................................ <ref>20</ref></p>
<p>Denson, James H. for the relief of the heirs of........................................... <ref>44</ref></p>
<p>DeWitt, C. C. authorized to construct bridge across the Guadaloupe river............. <ref>7</ref></p>
<p>DeWitt County Court. to allow the Sheriff extra pay in certain cases................... <ref>21</ref></p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">E</head>
<p>Eastern Texas R. E. Co. for the relief of....................................... <ref>20</ref></p>
<p>East Fork Bridge Company. act of incorporation....................................... <ref>16</ref></p>
<p>Edward, H. H. for the relief of......................................... <ref>53</ref></p>
<p>El Paso County Court. to allow the Sheriff extra pay in certain cases....................... <ref>21</ref></p>
<p>English, Levi. for the relief of........................................... <ref>34</ref></p>
<p>Everett, Sam. for the relief of............................................ <ref>7</ref></p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">F</head>
<p>Fannin, Minerva J. to be received in the Lunatic Asylum....................... <ref>47</ref></p>
<p>Flannigan, J. W. authorized to bridge the Sabine river....................... <ref>12</ref></p>
<p>Ford, Col. John S. Joint Resolution of thanks to him and his men....................... <ref>56</ref></p>
<p>Fort Bend Manufacturing Company. act of incorporation............................................. <ref>53</ref></p>
<p>Foster, James L. act for the relief of.................................................. <ref>15</ref></p>
<p>Fox, Abner. for the relief of the heirs of........................................ <ref>21</ref></p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">G</head>
<p>Gill, John P. for the relief of................................................. <ref>44</ref></p>
<p>Glenn, John W. for the relief of the heirs of.......................................... <ref>53</ref></p>
<p>Glasscock, George W., Assignee of Wood. for the relief of........................................ <ref>37</ref></p>
<p>Gonzales County Court. to allow the Sheriff extra pay in certain cases....................... <ref>21</ref></p>
<p>Grady, W. A. for the relief of.................................................. <ref>22</ref></p>
<pb n="584" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="62" /><fw type="header" place="top">Index.</fw>
<p>Green, Wm. B. for the relief of............................................ <ref>46</ref></p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">H</head>
<p>Henderson County. see &#8220;counties.&#8221;</p>
<p>Henderson, John. for the relief of................................................... <ref>47</ref></p>
<p>Henson, E. A. restored to all the rights and privileges of an attorney and counsellor at law.................................................. <ref>10</ref></p>
<p>Herrera, A. Ruiz de. for the relief of....................................................... <ref>21</ref></p>
<p>Heirs of&#8212;For the Relief of.</p>
<p>Allcorn, Elisha................................... <ref>6</ref></p>
<p>Callan, James................................... <ref>36</ref></p>
<p>Clark, Charles................................... <ref>41</ref></p>
<p>Denson, James H................................... <ref>44</ref></p>
<p>Fox, Abner................................... <ref>21</ref></p>
<p>Glenn, John W................................... <ref>53</ref></p>
<p>Holman, Sanford................................... <ref>13</ref></p>
<p>Lankford, Garrett H................................... <ref>14</ref></p>
<p>McCowan, James................................... <ref>15</ref></p>
<p>Miller, Pleasant M................................... <ref>36</ref></p>
<p>Murphy, Harvey................................... <ref>9</ref></p>
<p>Pay, Wm. R................................... <ref>36</ref></p>
<p>Pierson, Isaac................................... <ref>11</ref></p> 
<p>Powell, Lewis................................... <ref>35</ref></p>
<p>Scott, Robert R................................... <ref>41</ref></p>
<p>Sheperd, Joseph................................... <ref>53</ref></p>
<p>Wilson, George W................................... <ref>41</ref></p>
<p>White, John................................... <ref>39</ref></p>
<p>Hicks, A. W. O. for the relief of................................... <ref>8</ref></p>
<p>Holman, Sanford. for the relief of the heirs of.................................. <ref>13</ref></p>
<p>Hook and Ladder Company of Austin. act of incorporation.................................. <ref>8</ref></p>
<p>Hotchkiss, A. land certificate to be issued to..................................... <ref>36</ref></p>
<p>Houston, Trinity and Tyler R. R. Company. Time extended them....................................... <ref>6</ref></p>
<p>Hopkins County Court. to allow Sheriff extra pay in certain cases....................... <ref>21</ref></p>
<p>Houston County Court. to allow the Sheriff extra pay in certain cases....................... <ref>21</ref></p>
<p>Hunt County Court. to allow Sheriff extra pay in certain cases....................... <ref>21</ref></p>
<p>Hughes, W. V. for the relief of.......................................... <ref>23</ref></p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">I</head>
<p>Incorporations. Arkansas Salt Works, Company..................................... <ref>41</ref></p>
<p>Austin Hook &#38; Ladder Company.......................................... <ref>8</ref></p>
<p>Dallas Bridge Company.................................. <ref>8</ref></p>
<p>Dallas Co., Mechanical &#38; Agricultural Association....................... <ref>25</ref></p>
<p>Eastern Texas R. R. Co. relief of................................... <ref>20</ref></p>
<p>East Fork Bridge Company........................................... <ref>16</ref></p>
<p>Fort Bend Manufacturing Company.................................... <ref>53</ref></p>
<pb n="585" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="63" /><fw type="header" place="top">Index.</fw>
<p>Jefferson Insurance Company.............................................. <ref>4</ref></p>
<p>Marcelina Bridge &#38; Manufacturing Company................................ <ref>14</ref></p>
<p>Pulaski Bridge Company.............................................. <ref>18</ref></p>
<p>Rio Grande Female Institute.................................... <ref>5</ref></p>
<p>Southern Cotton Press Manufacturing Company..................................... <ref>4</ref></p>
<p>Southern Pacific R. R. Company, Laws amended.................................. <ref>27</ref></p>
<p>Texas Powder Company........................................ <ref>10</ref></p>
<p>Texas Manufacturing Company..................................... <ref>12</ref></p>
<p>Texas Lead Mine Company.............................................. <ref>45</ref></p>
<p>Texas &#38; N. O. R. R. Company, time extended....................... <ref>43</ref></p>
<p>Waco Classical School, changed to Waco University....................... <ref>15</ref></p>
<p>West Fork Bridge Co., right of way extended to....................... <ref>19</ref></p>
<p>Incorporated Towns. Austin City Charter amended....................... <ref>49</ref></p>
<p>Houston City Charter amended....................... <ref>28</ref></p>
<p>Marshall City Charter amended....................... <ref>16</ref></p>
<p>Mount Vernon Charter amended....................... <ref>8</ref></p>
<p>San Philipe incorporated....................... <ref>25</ref></p>
<p>Sumpter incorporated...................................... <ref>40</ref></p>
<p>Indians. Governor authorized to appoint an agent to the Alabama and Coshatta Indians....................................................... <ref>19</ref></p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">J</head>
<p>Jackson, Robert H. for the relief of...................................................... <ref>36</ref></p>
<p>Jefferson Insurance Company. act of incorporation amended................................ <ref>4</ref></p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">K</head>
<p>Kaufman County. see &#8220;counties.&#8221;</p>
<p>Kitchings, Daniel. for the relief of....................... <ref>7</ref></p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">L</head>
<p>Lamar County Court. to allow Sheriff extra pay in certain cases, (see counties)....................... <ref>21</ref></p>
<p>Lankford, G. F. for the relief of the heirs of.................................................... <ref>14</ref></p>
<p>LaVaca County Court. to allow Sheriff extra pay in certain cases.............................. <ref>21</ref></p>
<p>Lawler, Levi T. for the relief of....................................................... <ref>53</ref></p>
<p>Lands. time extended to purchasers of the University lands....................... <ref>23</ref></p>
<p>an act to adjudicate certain legal claims to land lying between the Nueces and Rio Grande rivers, amended....................... <ref>46</ref></p>
<p>Lea, J. H. authorized to adopt Alexander Wright....................................... <ref>20</ref></p>
<p>Louisiana. joint resolution of thanks to, for the &#8220;Twin Sisters&#8221;....................... <ref>57</ref></p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">M</head>
<p>Marcelina Bridge &#38; Manufacturing Company. incorporated................................................. <ref>14</ref></p>
<p>Miller. P. M. for the relief of the heirs of............................................... <ref>30</ref></p>
<p>Marshall City. act of incorporation amended......................................... <ref>16</ref></p>
<pb n="586" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="64" /><fw type="header" place="top">Index.</fw>
<p>Mathews Abner. for the relief of..........................................<ref>35</ref></p>
<p>MeCown, James. for the relief of the heirs of.............................. <ref>15</ref></p>
<p>Montague County Court. to have the records of the District Court transcribed....................... <ref>49</ref></p>
<p>Morris George W. for the relief of........................................................<ref>37</ref></p>
<p>Mount Vernon. act of incorporation amended..................................... <ref>8</ref></p>
<p>Mudget Myrum. for the relief of................................................. <ref>7</ref></p>
<p>Murphy, Harvey. for the relief of the heirs of.................................. <ref>9</ref></p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">N</head>
<p>Needham, Margaret. to be received into the Lunatic Asylum....................... <ref>37</ref></p>
<p>Norvill, Lipscomb. for the relief of.......................................... <ref>24</ref></p>
<p>Norton, Peter. for the relief of............................................ <ref>9</ref></p>
<p>Nueces County. act authorizing the levy of a special tax repealed....................... <ref>10</ref></p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">P</head>
<p>Panola County Court. to allow the Sheriff extra pay in certain cases....................... <ref>21</ref></p>
<p>Parker, Cynthia Ann. act granting her a pension amended................................. <ref>34</ref></p>
<p>Pay, W. R. for the relief of the heirs of.................................. <ref>36</ref></p>
<p>Pierson, Isaac. for the relief of the heirs of................................ <ref>11</ref></p>
<p>Plummer, J. P. for the relief of....................................... <ref>37</ref></p>
<p>Powder Company, Texas. act of incorporation................................... <ref>10</ref></p>
<p>Powell, Lewis. for the relief of the heirs of...........................</p>
<p>Price, Mrs. General. Joint Resolution tendering her the hospitalities of the State.............. <ref>55</ref></p>
<p>Priestly, P. for the relief of........................................... <ref>49</ref></p>
<p>Pulaski Bridge Company. act of incorporation.................................... <ref>18</ref></p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">Q</head>
<p>Quartermasters. requiring certain accounts of to be audited....................... <ref>40</ref></p>
<p>must pay over to the Chief Justice of each county contributing to camps of instruction moneys, &#38;c....................... <ref>40</ref></p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">R</head>
<p>Rio Grande Female Institute, act of incorporation............................................. <ref>5</ref></p>
<p>Ruiz, Francisco. for the relief of............................................... <ref>21</ref></p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">S</head>
<p>Sabine River. J. W. Flanigan, et al, authorized to bridge....................... <ref>42</ref></p>
<pb n="587" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="65" /><fw type="header" place="top">Index.</fw>
<p>Saunders, J. H. may move the effects of his wards from Texas to Arkansas....................... <ref>3</ref></p>
<p>San Philipe, Town of. act of incorporation............................................ <ref>25</ref></p>
<p>legalizing the acts of corporate officers.............................. <ref>25</ref></p>
<p>Sampson &#38; Henricks. for the relief of...................................... <ref>40</ref></p>
<p>Sansom, Capt. J. W. see &#8220;Comptroller.&#8221;</p>
<p>Shade, J. B. for the relief of.................................... <ref>53</ref></p>
<p>Sherman, F. A. for the relief of.................................... <ref>44</ref></p>
<p>Shepard, Joseph. for the relief of the heirs of.................................... <ref>53</ref></p>
<p>Sims, Charles H. for the relief of.................................... <ref>34</ref></p>
<p>Simeon, Gregory. for the relief of.................................... <ref>49</ref></p>
<p>Scott, R. R. for the relief of the heirs of.................................... <ref>41</ref></p>
<p>Smith, Samuel. for the relief of.................................... <ref>53</ref></p>
<p>Smith, Thomas F. for the relief of.................................... <ref>34</ref></p>
<p>Sneed, J. R. for the relief of.................................... <ref>36</ref></p>
<p>Southern Cotton Press Manufacturing Company. act of incorporation amended.................................... <ref>4</ref></p>
<p>Southern Pacific R. R. Company. act of incorporation amended.................................... <ref>27</ref></p>
<p>Sheriffs. of certain counties to be allowed extra pay.................................... <ref>21</ref></p>
<p>Spencer, A. L. for the relief of.................................... <ref>7</ref></p>
<p>Sumpter, Town of. act of incorporation.................................... <ref>40</ref></p>
<p>Swenson, S. M. for the relief of.................................... <ref>40</ref></p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">T</head>
<p>Tramel, Mrs. Martha. for the relief of.................................... <ref>44</ref></p>
<p>Tarrant County Court. to allow the Sheriff extra pay in certain cases.................................... <ref>21</ref></p>
<p>Tarrant County. see &#8220;counties.&#8221;</p>
<p>Tarver, Nelson. for the relief of.................................... <ref>25</ref></p>
<p>Texas Lead Mine Company. act of incorporation.................................... <ref>45</ref></p>
<p>Texas Manufacturing Company. act of incorporation.................................... <ref>12</ref></p>
<p>Texas and N. O. R. R. Company. for the relief of.................................... <ref>43</ref></p>
<p>Thomas, John. for the relief of.................................... <ref>24</ref></p>
<p>Twin Sisters. Joint Resolution of thanks to Louisiana for them.................................... <ref>57</ref></p>
<pb n="588" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="66" /><fw type="header" place="top">Index.</fw>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">U</head>
<p>University Lands. see &#8220;lands.&#8220;</p>
<p>Upshur County Court. to allow Sheriff extra pay in certain cases.................................... <ref>21</ref></p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">V</head>
<p>Vontress, E. H. leave of absence granted to him.................................... <ref>3</ref></p>
<p>Vinous, Spirituous and other Intoxicating Liquors.</p>
<p>sale of prohibited within one mile of Alto, Cherokee county................... <ref>6</ref></p>
<p>sale of prohibited within 4&#189; miles of the court house of Tarrant county <ref>14</ref></p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">W</head>
<p>Waco Classical School. charter amended and name changed to Waco University.................... <ref>15</ref></p>
<p>Walker, Hon. John C. mileage and per diem to be drawn by the Hon. Horace Cone.....<ref>44</ref></p>
<p>Webb, Capt. M. company of M. V. to be paid............................. <ref>43</ref></p>
<p>Wells, T. for the relief of.................................... <ref>36</ref></p>
<p>West Fork Bridge Company. right of way extended to them.................................... <ref>19</ref></p>
<p>White, John. for the relief of the heirs of.................................... <ref>39</ref></p>
<p>Wichita County. attached to Montague for judicial purposes.................................... <ref>22</ref></p>
<p>Wilson, G. W. for the relief of the heirs of.................................... <ref>41</ref></p>
<p>Williamson County Court. to allow the Sheriff extra pay in certain cases..................... <ref>21</ref></p>
<p>Wolfe, Solomon. privilege granted to of constructing a bridge across the Angelina river <ref>17</ref></p>
<p>Work, P. A. for the relief of.................................... <ref>24</ref></p>
<p>Wright, Alexander. authorizing his adoption by J. H. Lea and the changing of his name.. <ref>20</ref></p>
</div3>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">THE STATE OF TEXAS. DEPARTMENT OF STATE.</head>
<p>I, R. J. Townes, Secretary of State of the State of Texas, do certify that I have compared the foregoing Laws and Joint Resolutions of the Ninth Legislature, with the originals now on file in the Department of State, and that they are true copies of such originals.</p>
<p>I further certify that the Ninth Legislature of the State of Texas assembled on Monday the fourth day of November, A. D., 1861, and adjourned on the 14th day of January, A. D., 1862.</p>
<p>In testimony whereof, I have hereunto signed my name and caused <floatingText rend="left"><body><p>[SEAL.]</p></body></floatingText>the seal of the Department of State to be affixed, at Austin, this 1st day of September, A. D., 1863.</p>
<closer>
<signed>R. J. TOWNES, Secretary of State.</signed>
</closer>
</div2>
</div1>
</body>
</text>